<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shorts on </title>
    <link>jarbus.net/tags/shorts/</link>
    <description> (shorts)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:25:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="jarbus.net/tags/shorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Short: Aftermath</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/short-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/short-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeff stepped over a beer can, then over a water bottle and onto a mat, whose faded lettering vaguely resembled the phrase &amp;ldquo;Welcome!&amp;rdquo; He opened his front door and walked inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to his right, Jeff noticed his old hooded friend where he left him; on his living-room rocking chair. The cold metal scythe still in his lap, the skeleton hadn&amp;rsquo;t moved an inch from where he left him earlier that morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s cooking, big guy?&amp;rdquo; Jeff said as he walked to the kitchen to grab his last can of Budweiser. His boney companioned turned his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Oh, you know&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, Death emitted. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;still out of work.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I do not understand why you still haven&amp;rsquo;t given up yet.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could say the same about you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I exist for one purpose, Jeffrey. and as long as you are alive, I cannot rest.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, you seem pretty well rested to me, what with you never leaving my house and all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I used to have what you call a &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo;. It was very fulfilling, Jeffery. Took up all of my time. Do you want to know what it was?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffery took a sip of his beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I used to collect the souls of the dead, Jeffery. It was wonderful. I conversed with the rich, the poor, the young and the old, Jeffrey, as they contemplated life and where they were headed. I had, what you would call, a &amp;lsquo;nice thing going.&#39;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All good things gotta come to an end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Then you came along,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death continued, ignoring him, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;and ruined everything.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It be like that sometimes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;It does not &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo; like that sometimes, Jeffrey&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death glared, a purple glow forming in his eye sockets. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A single human does not wipe out humanity &amp;lsquo;every now and then&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fair.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;What is even more despicable,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death proceeded, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;is that you don&amp;rsquo;t even regret pushing the button.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t really think about it too much.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;YOU HAD A CHOICE,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death boomed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;BETWEEN SAVING HUMANKIND, AND SAVING YOURSELF&amp;ndash;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mhm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;AND WITHOUT A SECOND THOUGHT, DOOMED YOUR ENTIRE SPECIES&amp;ndash;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yup.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;IN EXCHANGE FOR A LIFE OF THEFT AND SLUMBER.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can&amp;rsquo;t steal from the dead,&amp;rdquo; Jeff rebutted, taking another sip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;THAT IS NOT THE POINT, JEFFREY&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death bellowed. He paused, taking a few seconds to decompose himself. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You fail to understand the magnitude of your actions.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, I understand perfectly well, you&amp;rsquo;ve made sure of that. I&amp;rsquo;d have to be deaf to spend a day with you and not hear your whining.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe you even have a soul worth collecting.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Listen, it was self defense, alright? It&amp;rsquo;s not like I wanted to kill everyone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Adolf Hitler, Joseph Stalin, Osama Bin Laden; every single corrupt soul in your history books would not have stooped to your level; self-defense does not justify genocide.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So humans can drive thousands of species to extinction for selfish gain, but only when it happens to them it&amp;rsquo;s unjustified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death moved as if to rebutt, but said nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you know how close we came to nuclear war? There was never a guarantee of tomorrow for anyone. For all we know, the human race might last an extra few decades thanks to me.&amp;rdquo; Jeff said, smirking. &amp;ldquo;Why does humanity deserves the benefit of the doubt?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Why do you?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily,&amp;rdquo; Jeff said, taking a seat on the opposite couch. &amp;ldquo;It just happened to be my choice. My parents were already dead&amp;ndash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t owe anybody anything. What moral rule says I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to lay down my life for those I don&amp;rsquo;t know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You are selfish, Jeffrey Johnson.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Death said, rising from his seat. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You put yourself in front of millions of good, innocent people who would lay down their lives in your situation.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is it selfish, or simply not being selfless? A starving man doesn&amp;rsquo;t owe another starving man his bread.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death leaned forward, skull to face with Jeff, searching for any sign of remorse. He came back empty. Death turned around drifted towards the exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;He owes the guilt of denying a meal,&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; he remarked as he left the room. The front door creaked open, then closed. Silence filled the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Should I instead spend humanity&amp;rsquo;s last years crying?&amp;rdquo; Jeff yelled to the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The door didn&amp;rsquo;t respond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
