<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on </title>
    <link>jarbus.net/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description> (philosophy)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:25:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="jarbus.net/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Uninformed Or Misinformed?</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it better to have no facts about a topic and thus no opinion, or have access to a few &amp;ldquo;out of context&amp;rdquo; facts and thus a misinformed opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t be well-informed on every topic; It&amp;rsquo;s just not possible. That&amp;rsquo;s why world leaders have advisers. Yet somehow, if you look at anyone&amp;rsquo;s Facebook account, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to try too hard to figure out their view on any political issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to realize how much nuance there is to the headlines we see. When I read an article that ruins the image of a company or individual, I always wonder: What information could the author be omitting? What view could the other side have? What outside information is the author conveniently using to make a point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to avoid getting emotional until these questions are answered. I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of having basic gut feelings on unfamiliar topics, but these feelings aren&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to start an argument. I talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m informed about, and listen (with a grain of salt) to others talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for lots of us. Instead of admitting we are uninformed, many of us form an opinion after we read the headline, and most likely don&amp;rsquo;t update it after skimming the article with said headline. We are even less likely to look for an opposing take, as that requires we scroll outside of whatever feed we are browsing through. Some people don&amp;rsquo;t even use the news to form opinions: They just accept the opinions of their friends or family as &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;. As someone who accepted the outcome of the 2020 presidential election without looking into the claims of fraud, I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of this too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then take this opinion that a) isn&amp;rsquo;t ours and b) took less than 10 seconds to form, and carry it into the foreseeable future, not even considering the idea that there might be more we don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with admitting that we don&amp;rsquo;t know enough to judge a topic or event? Do we really think we have enough context and facts to make sound judgements on all our beliefs? Do we really need to hold an opinion after every scandal? Why can&amp;rsquo;t we just say &amp;ldquo;This is a side of a story&amp;rdquo; and move on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/03/timnit-gebru-google-fired/&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s firing of Timnit Gebru&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a headline about Google firing a researcher that criticized the company on a mailing list. I didn&amp;rsquo;t need about any more drama in my life, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t read further, tucking this away in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google responded with something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;she was using an email list in such a way that was improper for her position&amp;rdquo;. I still didn&amp;rsquo;t need the drama, so I kept it in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still hold no strong positions on this specific topic and don&amp;rsquo;t plan on learning more about it. Like in most &amp;ldquo;scandals&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;he said, she said&amp;rdquo; going on, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time figuring out who is right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to hold an opinion on this event, I&amp;rsquo;d need the following details to start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code of conduct for Gebru&amp;rsquo;s position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other alternative methods Gebru could have used not in violation of the Code of Conduct if her actions violated it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The contents of the email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbose arguments from both sides refuting each other&amp;rsquo;s points if possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence of Gebru&amp;rsquo;s claims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who does not work at nor plans to work at Google, this just isn&amp;rsquo;t worth my time, so I don&amp;rsquo;t form an opinion. There are other things to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR (again): Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Rules</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/soft-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/soft-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not all rules are made equal. Some rules, like the speed limit, are broken by everyone and their mother, and are enforced (mostly) when people are breaking them to a dangerous point. Other rules, like &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t murder people&amp;rdquo;, are enforced far more. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-rules-different-tools&#34; &gt;Different Rules, Different Tools
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#different-rules-different-tools&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules are in place to assign blame to someone with bad judgement. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing morally wrong with jaywalking when there are no cars coming, but you are at fault if you walk into oncoming traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules are in place to discourage bad habits from forming, like the drinking age. This law is so commonly broken that it&amp;rsquo;s expected behavior at this point, and yet I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen someone get arrested for under-age drinking. Despite this, the law conveys the dangers of drinking, makes it harder for minors to acquire alcohol, and prevents students from openly sharing alcohol in schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules, like mandatory attendance, exist to get people to show up to an event or perform an activity. Even when attendance isn&amp;rsquo;t taken, many people will still show up to prevent unnecessary trouble. College orientation activities are a prime example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules exist simply because they haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated. Before 2020, some companies &amp;ndash; especially older ones &amp;ndash; didn&amp;rsquo;t allow employees to work from home. Working from home was seen as an unnecessary risk by upper management with no tangible benefit to any of the executives. Along comes the coronavirus, and suddenly the jobs people have been doing in an office for decades are suddenly doable from home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-for-rules&#34; &gt;Rules for Rules
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rules-for-rules&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rules should be justified. If a sign on a fish tank says, &lt;em&gt;PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS&lt;/em&gt;, do you think most people, especially children, are likely to obey? Does your answer change if the sign were to say &lt;em&gt;PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS, IT SCARES THE FISH&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too many rules, even if they are justified. The more rules in place, the less likely people will follow them. Just think about it: If Moses received 206 commandments, do you think his followers would view &lt;em&gt;Thou shalt not eat meat and dairy&lt;/em&gt; with the same level of respect as &lt;em&gt;Thou shalt not kill&lt;/em&gt;? More rules can imply that there are strict guidelines to be followed, but people will interpret them as: &lt;em&gt;Whoever came up with this must be fun at parties.&lt;/em&gt; Unnecessary rules draw attention away from the important ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up-rules&#34; &gt;Wrapping Up Rules
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#wrapping-up-rules&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no rule expert. Nevertheless, I recognize that creating and selectively enforcing rules is a valuable skill, for both policy-makers and policy-enforcers alike. If you want people to respect your rules, make sure they have a reason for being there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Thinking</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/critical-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/critical-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more I learn about the world, the less certain I become about it. There are so many conflicting views and information taken out of context that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to discern fact from truth. Below are some notes I keep to help navigate the sea of information that is modern society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Don&amp;rsquo;t get fooled by facts if they have no context, don&amp;rsquo;t discount an opinion because it&amp;rsquo;s biased, and hear out crazy ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-skeptical-fact--truth&#34; &gt;Be skeptical: Fact != Truth
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#be-skeptical-fact--truth&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are facts available for virtually anything you need. No matter what argument you try to make, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to find a statistic that can back up your claims thanks to the glory of Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3030983/The-ultra-competitive-exercise-fad-ruin-health-called-planking-suddenly-sweeping-gyms-Pilates-classes.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did you know that planking can ruin your health and result in months of pain?&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifehack.org/292578/7-things-that-will-happen-when-you-do-planking-exercise-every-day&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not true, planking works out multiple muscles in your body and can greatly improve your health if done daily&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not exactly scientific sources, but I think this demonstrates my point. Furthermore, the level of mixed information increases exponentially as the topic gets more political.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facts should never be enough to prove a point, and I tend to suspect people who rely too heavily on them. Facts should instead be used to tell a narrative; facts are not the truth, but they can light the way towards it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ewarren/status/1090252713156403200&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The top 0.1% &amp;hellip; own about the same wealth as the bottom 90% of America.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While deemed &amp;ldquo;Mostly True&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2019/jan/31/elizabeth-warren/warren-top-01-own-about-much-bottom-90/&#34;&gt;Politifact.com&lt;/a&gt;, this statement in isolation is less than useless: it&amp;rsquo;s misleading. On it&amp;rsquo;s own, this fact paints a picture of a grim society, where the bottom 90% are left to struggle for survival, with all resources being held for a greedy few. If you are in the bottom 90%, this prompts you to believe that life is unfair, and that this should be changed. That&amp;rsquo;s why this statistic is so popular, it seems outrageous and gives Americans a sense of justified anger at the rich, an anger which many ex-presidential candidates used to garner support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break this idea down a bit. The greedy elite factoid on its own implies nothing about quality of life, standard of living, financial responsibility, or determination to work. Society could be a paradise where everyone has access to more than they could ever need, and the top 0.1% just has an absurd amount of money. Or society could be a system of addiction, where the bottom 90% are constantly spending money on things they don&amp;rsquo;t need and the top 0.1% simply aren&amp;rsquo;t addicted and save/invest wisely. The truth is, these numbers don&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything about the truth, and aren&amp;rsquo;t being used to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a narrative discussing the implications of this statistic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wealth_inequality_in_the_United_States#Effect_on_democracy&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2014 study by researchers at Princeton and Northwestern concludes that government policies reflect the desires of the wealthy, and that the vast majority of American citizens have &amp;ldquo;minuscule, near-zero, statistically non-significant impact upon public policy … when a majority of citizens disagrees with economic elites and/or with organized interests, they generally lose.&amp;rdquo; When Fed chair Janet Yellen was questioned by Bernie Sanders about the study at a congressional hearing in May 2014, she responded &amp;ldquo;There’s no question that we’ve had a trend toward growing inequality&amp;rdquo; and that this trend &amp;ldquo;can shape [and] determine the ability of different groups to participate equally in a democracy and have grave effects on social stability over time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people know about inequality, but not what it means for them. The wealth statistic means nothing in a vaccuum, only in context does it hold any value. If facts are used to invoke emotion instead of prove a point, be skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased&#34; &gt;Worth Listening to those who are biased?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A girl in a class of mine had a laptop sticker that read &amp;ldquo;Why be racist, sexist, or transphobic when you can just be quiet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t stand this type of thinking. It&amp;rsquo;s elitist, tells people with controversial views to not let their voice be heard, and contributes to the echo chamber of modern society. Furthermore, it accomplishes nothing except a pat on the back for people with her mindset. No racist is actually going to read that and go &amp;ldquo;Oh, guess I just won&amp;rsquo;t speak my mind then.&amp;rdquo; In fact, they might be driven further into racism in spite. Nobody likes being talked down to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of insight to be gained on both sides from listening to people with views you don&amp;rsquo;t like. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think white supremacists are evil and don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to speak; its harder to realize they have a reason for their beliefs. If you want to make the world a better place, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from silence, but from understanding. When fighting racism, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it make sense to understand where racists are coming from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss tax law, you should hear out the rich guy that wants lower taxes just as much as the working class American who wants the same. If you want to discuss diversity, don&amp;rsquo;t limit the white participants to those with an &amp;ldquo;anti-white&amp;rdquo; mindset. These perspectives are essential to promoting an open dialogue, and leaving out those with biased opinions leads to toxic echo chambers and a mentality of &amp;ldquo;us versus them&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hear-out-the-crazy&#34; &gt;Hear out the crazy
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#hear-out-the-crazy&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I experimented with fasting, a few people I knew were opposed. The concept of not eating for days on end? Ridiculous! Your body needs food, your metabolism will slow to a halt if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These arguments didn&amp;rsquo;t come from any sort of reading on the subject, but human intuition. The concept of not eating for a few days went against everything they knew; to them it was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fasting isn&amp;rsquo;t actually bad for you if done right, and can have &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fasting#Health_effects&#34;&gt;numerous health benefits&lt;/a&gt;. A simple Google search into the subject could have cleared up these misconceptions. But that would imply that this ridiculous idea could have some merit worth looking for. It&amp;rsquo;s like looking up &amp;ldquo;Did the Holocaust happen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to most domains however, there is usually some fascinating logic behind crazy ideas. Bitcoin comes to mind; a currency without a government to back it seems completely absurd on the surface. The gut reaction is to call Bitcoin a fraud, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/01/09/jamie-dimon-says-he-regrets-calling-bitcoin-a-fraud.html&#34;&gt;but when the best in the business take some time to think about it, they might have second thoughts&lt;/a&gt;. The Bitcoin community is full of brilliant people that built the foundation of blockchain technology. It&amp;rsquo;s worth hearing them out, even if their ideas seem a bit crazy at first glance. They must have their reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the news cycle continues to speed up, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to determine fact from fiction, who&amp;rsquo;s crazy and who&amp;rsquo;s biased, what&amp;rsquo;s conspiracy and what&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to listen to everyone, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t only listen to those with a similar mindset. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get the full story for every topic of discussion, but don&amp;rsquo;t fall for out-of-context information. Question everything, but keep an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some thoughts on Happiness:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from wealth. Otherwise, therapists and anti-depressants would have to be much cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If happiness came from consumption of goods and services, it would therefore follow that once those goods and services are reduced or cut off, one would no longer be as happy. If you can cut off happiness, it&amp;rsquo;s more akin to a drug than an emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2017/04/over-nearly-80-years-harvard-study-has-been-showing-how-to-live-a-healthy-and-happy-life/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Close relationships, more than money or fame, are what keep people happy throughout their lives.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; While financial security is ideal for easing pain and suffering, significant amounts of money can strain relationships and cast doubt on who your friends really are. If solid relationships are a path to happiness, the drama and expectations caused from wealth differences in the relationships might very well block that path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, happiness isn&amp;rsquo;t something you can obtain, but something you become. True happiness has to come from within to be strong and sustainable. Performing work you find meaningful, engaging in relationships of substance, and living a life of virtue are all ways to approach happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness can&amp;rsquo;t come from believing you are the smartest, most attractive, or funniest person in your social circles. If it does, you either aren&amp;rsquo;t around people you can learn from or are living in a world of illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If stressed about all those that are above you, happiness is possible if you enjoy the process of learning and take pride in trying your best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s possible to be a masterpiece and a work in progress at the same time.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain and happiness are not mutually exclusive, but rather two sides of the same coin. The greatest pains can come from the greatest happiness, such as the loss of a loved one. Some of the greatest happiness comes from the greatest pain, such as starting new relationships after others have ended. The most painful moments can sometimes fuel transitions into the best ones. Don&amp;rsquo;t let pain go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.health.harvard.edu/healthbeat/giving-thanks-can-make-you-happier&#34;&gt;One of the best ways to increase happiness is to show gratitude.&lt;/a&gt; When expressing thanks for what you have instead of longing for what you don&amp;rsquo;t, you learn to draw happiness from yourself instead of the high of getting something new. If you were to lose that for which you are thankful, the situation doesn&amp;rsquo;t change &amp;ndash; draw gratitude from what&amp;rsquo;s left.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness has a negative connotation these days. We see forgiving each other as weak — as not standing by one’s values, as giving up one’s pride. This view is incredibly counter-productive and, in my opinion, the cause of many problems in today’s society. Here is the actual definition of forgiveness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;forgive (verb)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to cease to feel resentment against (an offender)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: Merriam Webster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definition is all that forgiveness has to be — not pardoning or excusing someone for their actions, but instead letting go of anger towards them. Grudges may appear to make someone “tough” and “strong,” but all they do is keep someone’s mind tormented by the people they despise. It is very easy to hold a grudge—grudges make one feel powerful without requiring them to do anything. However, true power in one’s life stems from overcoming this negativity and taking control of one’s emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgiving-others&#34; &gt;Forgiving Others
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#forgiving-others&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forgiving others is much easier than it sounds and is one of the quickest and simplest ways to &lt;em&gt;improve your mental state&lt;/em&gt;. This will be more challenging for deep, long-term grudges, but you can displace surface-level anger as easily as saying, “[Person], I forgive you” aloud—even when alone. Forgiveness helps get negative people out of your head who don’t deserve to be there. It also helps you understand others instead of hating them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting go of blame/resentment helps focus on finding solutions, instead of blaming others for problems—this results in &lt;em&gt;better decision making&lt;/em&gt;. Your thought process goes from, “If only this person didn’t do that, everything would be so much better” to “This happened, what can I do about it?” It’s not possible to control the actions of others, but we can control our own responses. This attitude &lt;em&gt;sharpens social skills&lt;/em&gt;, as you learn to respond maturely instead of reacting passionately when upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgiving-yourself&#34; &gt;Forgiving Yourself
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#forgiving-yourself&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does forgiving yourself mean? In line with our definition from above, it means to cease self-resentment. Many toxic behaviors stem from insecurities and regrets people have. If people were content with themselves and their accomplishments, the world would be a kinder place. Self forgiveness can be a much more difficult task than forgiving others (since you can’t exactly put yourself behind you), but can reap the greatest benefits. &lt;em&gt;Self forgiveness helps guide one’s life towards inner peace and self-love and away from a dependency on external stimuli (such as degrading others) for happiness.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to help forgive yourself for shortcomings is to work on improving them. Hate how you look? Exercise! Hate being socially incompetent? Practice talking to people! The amount of effort you put into change doesn’t have to be significant, as long as it’s consistent. You should be able to say, “I don’t like this aspect of myself but that’s ok, because I’m taking steps to improve.” This will &lt;em&gt;increase self-esteem&lt;/em&gt; and thus &lt;em&gt;increase happiness&lt;/em&gt; in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to changing who you are is accepting your flaws. No one is perfect! This skill is difficult to master, but promotes loving who you are instead of trying to change into who you want to be. Self-acceptance doesn’t require you to change everything you despise about yourself, but also can lead to a life of mediocrity where you always settle for “good enough”. I find a bit of each mindset to be ideal—I try to improve the qualities I can control and accept the ones I can’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hold self-resentment for past actions, try talking to a professional counselor/therapist! They are skilled at helping patients work through complex and specific issues. They suggest solutions you might not have thought of and call you out when you need it, making your problems much easier to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap--final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Recap &amp;amp; Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#recap--final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness means letting go of resentment, not justifying an action or person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is easier to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not stronger to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness increases confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness improves communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness clears the mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness allows you to learn from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness in some aspects of life help you forgive in others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness makes the world kinder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I don’t like myself because I am inferior,” can turn into “I love myself because I’m trying to grow.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“If only this didn’t happen,” can turn into “This happened, how do we respond?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this writing isn’t citing scientific studies or telling anecdotes—it is presenting a set of ideas for the reader to consider. These beliefs do not cover the entire subject nor do they universally hold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance</title>
      <link>jarbus.net/blog/balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jarbus.net/blog/balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing sides is fun. Be it politics or pop culture, nothing validates an opinion better than classifying opposing opinions as wrong. Sometimes, as seen by Holocaust deniers or the anti-vaccine movement, it&amp;rsquo;s possible people can be completely and utterly wrong. However, in the general case, both sides have merits and both sides have pitfalls. When trying to gain a perspective of the bigger picture, it&amp;rsquo;s best to position oneself somewhere in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-versus-that&#34; &gt;This versus that
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#this-versus-that&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in a world with seven billion perspectives. Seven billion lifetimes of thought and contemplation. Of course, one cannot listen to every lifestory nor hear every person&amp;rsquo;s opinion. So we form into groups, with each important group representing something between the loudest minority or general majority of people with a particular set of opinions. This is a system able to properly distinguish emerging schools of thought while categorizing people into said schools, enabling people to efficiently organize, communicate, and compare ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not imply that everyone in a group has well formed opinions. Quite the opposite in fact &amp;ndash; these groups require people to give considerably less thought into their beliefs. Immersing oneself in a group for a few ideas can easily lead to naturally picking up other beliefs of the group, as many people will adapt for acceptance. This lower barrier to entry for taking sides is a core part of the conflict between groups, as society seems to reinforce beliefs by ridiculing opponents who don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand theirs &amp;ndash; consider the plethora of &amp;ldquo;Person X DESTROYS believer of Y&amp;rdquo; videos online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a large enough group however, there tend to be many people who have given careful time and consideration into why they believe what they believe. Thus, one cannot simply sweep a prominent idea under the rug because of a few bad apples. To do so is to throw away ideas which stood the test of time and the people behind them. If proposed a ridiculous sounding idea, merely dismissing it without consideration denies you of a potentially meaningful realization. Instead of &amp;ldquo;No, that&amp;rsquo;s wrong&amp;rdquo;, all parties benefit more from &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; The pursuit of knowledge would have ended a long time ago if we dismissed everything we didn&amp;rsquo;t believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;entertaining-thoughts&#34; &gt;Entertaining Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#entertaining-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An invaluable skill that many successful people have is the ability to play with an idea without accepting it. This is essential for multiple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By entertaining an idea, you can learn key takeaways from views that may appear ridiculous at first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can reinforce your beliefs by attempting (and failing) to convince yourself of an opposing view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, many people are absolutely rubbish at laying out a convincing argument. Requiring the persuasion of other people to change your mind will result in your mind rarely being changed. Sometimes, the best person to convince you of something is in fact, you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit an idea based on the people proposing it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit a person based on the group they belong to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing so inhibits learning for both parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone can&amp;rsquo;t convince you of something, try convincing yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a fully fleshed out idea of mine, nor is this idea exclusively mine. There are both counter arguments and room for expansion, however I think this is best left up to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
