<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jarbus.net on</title><link>/</link><description> (jarbus.net)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:42:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eloquence and Wit from Will Durant</title><link>/blog/story-of-civilization-1-quotes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:42:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/story-of-civilization-1-quotes/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just finished &lt;em>The Story of Civilization, Vol. 1&lt;/em> (1976) by Will Durant. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic read; Durant is eloquent, witty, and surprisingly relevant today. Below are some of my personal highlights of his writing, mixed with some quotes-of-quotes I found interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sections: &lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#communism">Communism&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#government">Government&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#women">Women&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#morals">Morals&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#language">Language&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#appearance">Appearance&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#sumeria">Sumeria&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#egypt">Egypt&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#babylon">Babylon&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#assyria">Assyria&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#judea">Judea&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#persia">Persia&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#india">India&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#China">China&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#Japan">Japan&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction" >Introduction
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#introduction">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;the provincialism of our traditional histories, which began with Greece and summed up Asia in a line, has become no merely academic error, but a possibly fatal failure of perspective and intelligence&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Civilization is an interlude between ice ages&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the decay of leadership through the infertility of the able&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The moment man begins to take thought of the morrow he passes out of the Garden of Eden into the vale of anxiety; the pale cast of worry settles down upon him, greed is sharpened, property begins, and the good cheer of the &amp;ldquo;thoughtless&amp;rdquo; native disappears.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Of what are you thinking?&amp;rdquo; Peary asked one of his Eskimo guides. &amp;ldquo;I do not have to think,&amp;rdquo; was the answer; &amp;ldquo;I have plenty of meat.&amp;rdquo; Not to think unless we have to—there is much to be said for this as the summation of wisdom&amp;quot;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If man began with speech, and civilization with agriculture, industry began with fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This primitive skill displayed itself proudly in the art of weaving. Here, too, the animal showed man the way. The web of the spider, the nest of the bird, the crossing and texture of fibres and leaves in the natural embroidery of the woods, set an example so obvious that in all probability weaving was one of the earliest arts of the human race&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Cattle were a convenient standard of value and medium of exchange among hunters and herders; they bore interest through breeding, and they were easy to carry, since they transported themselves&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="communism" >Communism
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#communism">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When Turner told a Samoan about the poor in London the &amp;ldquo;savage&amp;rdquo; asked in astonishment: &amp;ldquo;How is it? No food? No friends? No house to live in? Where did he grow? Are there no houses belonging to his friends?&amp;rdquo; The hungry Indian had but to ask to receive; no matter how small the supply was, food was given him if he needed it; &amp;ldquo;no one can want food while there is corn anywhere in the town.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;White travelers in Africa before the advent of civilization noted that a present of food or other valuables to a &amp;ldquo;black man&amp;rdquo; was at once distributed; so that when a suit of clothes was given to one of them the donor soon found the recipient wearing the hat, a friend the trousers, another friend the coat&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What is extremely surprising,&amp;rdquo; reports a missionary &amp;ldquo;is to see them treat one another with a gentleness and consideration which one does not find among common people in the most civilized nations&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Loskiel reported some Indian tribes of the northeast as &amp;ldquo;so lazy that they plant nothing themselves, but rely entirely upon the expectation that others will not refuse to share their produce with them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Darwin thought that the perfect equality among the Fuegians was fatal to any hope of their becoming civilized; or, as the Fuegians might have put it, civilization would have been fatal to their equality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Communism brought a certain security to all who survived the diseases and accidents due to the poverty and ignorance of primitive society; but it did not lift them out of that poverty&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It was a great moral improvement when men ceased to kill or eat their fellow men, and merely made them slaves&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="government" >Government
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#government">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Dyaks had no other government than that of each family by its head; in case of strife they chose their bravest warrior to lead them, and obeyed him strictly; but once the conflict was ended they literally sent him about his business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Time sanctifies everything; even the most arrant theft, in the hands of the robber’s grandchildren, becomes sacred and inviolable property&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Though men are naturally gullible they are also naturally obstinate, and power, like taxes, succeeds best when it is invisible and indirect&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The old Russian Government established courts of law in the Aleutian Islands, but in fifty years those courts found no employment. &amp;ldquo;Crime and offenses,&amp;rdquo; reports Brinton, &amp;ldquo;were so infrequent under the social system of the Iroquois that they can scarcely be said to have had a penal code.&amp;rdquo; Such are the ideal—perhaps the idealized—conditions for whose return the anarchist perennially pines.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is the routine that keeps men sane; for if there were no grooves along which thought and action might move with unconscious ease, the mind would be perpetually hesitant, and would soon take refuge in lunacy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;To violate law is to win the admiration of half the populace, who secretly envy anyone who can outwit this ancient enemy; to violate custom is to incur almost universal hostility&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The first stage in the evolution of law is personal revenge&amp;hellip; The second step toward law and civilization in the treatment of crime was the substitution of damages for revenge&amp;hellip; It is but a step from settling disputes and punishing offenses to making some effort to prevent them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Primitive punishments are cruel, because primitive society feels insecure; as social organization becomes more stable, punishments become less severe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="women" >Women
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#women">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;woman, apart from her biological disabilities, was almost the equal of man in stature, endurance, resourcefulness and courage; she was not yet an ornament, a thing of beauty or a sexual toy; she was a robust animal, able to perform arduous work for long hours, and, if necessary to fight to the death for her children or her clan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It was she who developed the home, slowly adding man to the list of her domesticated animals, and training him in those social dispositions and amenities which are the psychological basis and cement of civilization&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Since no society can exist without order and no order without regulation, we may take it as a rule of history that the power of custom varies inversely as the multiplicity of laws, much as the power of instinct varies inversely as the multiplicity of thoughts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The first task of those customs that constitute the moral code of a group is to regulate the relations of the sexes, for these are a perennial source of discord, violence, and possible degeneration.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There is no record of women objecting to marriage by purchase; on the contrary, they took keen pride in the sums paid for them, and scorned the woman who gave herself in marriage without a price; they believed that in a &amp;ldquo;love-match&amp;rdquo; the villainous male was getting too much for nothing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A Maori mother wailing loudly bitterly cursed the youth who had eloped with her daughter until he presented her with a blanket. &amp;ldquo;That was all I wanted,&amp;rdquo; she said; &amp;ldquo;I only wanted to get a blanket, and therefore made this noise&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Marriage was a profitable partnership, not a private debauch; it was a way whereby a man and a woman, working together might be more prosperous than if each worked alone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;as Anacharsis put it among the Greeks, if one were to bring together all customs considered sacred by some group, and were then to take away all customs considered immoral by some group, nothing would remain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The institutions, conventions, customs and laws that make up the complex structure of a society are the work of a hundred centuries and a billion minds; and one mind must not expect to comprehend them in one lifetime, much less in twenty years&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Greed, acquisitiveness, dishonesty, cruelty and violence were for so many generations useful to animals and men that not all our laws, our education, our morals and our religions can quite stamp them out; some of them, doubtless, have a certain survival value even today&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Yakuts have been known to eat forty pounds of meat in one day; and similar stories, only less heroic, are told of the Eskimos and the natives of Australia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;for to many a primitive mind no argument is settled until one of the disputants is dead&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In several tribes no woman would marry a man who had not killed some one, in fair fight or foul; hence the practice of headhunting, which survives in the Philippines today&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="morals" >Morals
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#morals">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;primitive hospitality, in many tribes, went to the extent of offering to the traveler the wife or daughter of the host. To decline such an offer was a serious offense, not only to the host but to the woman; these are among the perils faced by missionaries&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Almost all groups agree in holding other groups to be inferior to themselves&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Moral progress in history lies not so much in the improvement of the moral code as in the enlargement of the area within which it is applied&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;men are more easily ruled by imagination than by science&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The dwarfs of the Cameroon recognized only malevolent deities, and did nothing to placate them, on the ground that it was useless to try&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the Molucca Islands blossoming trees were treated as pregnant; no noise, fire, or other disturbance was permitted to mar their peace; else, like a frightened woman, they might drop their fruit before time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is the tendency of gods to begin as ogres and to end as loving fathers; the idol passes into an ideal as the growing security peacefulness and moral sense of the worshipers pacify and transform the features of their once ferocious deities. The slow progress of civilization is reflected in the tardy amiability of the gods.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;—a desired action was suggested to the deities by a partial or imitative performance of the action by men. To make rain fall some primitive magicians poured water out upon the ground, preferably from a tree. The Kaffirs, threatened by drought, asked a missionary to go into the fields with an opened umbrella&amp;hellip; In the Babar Archipelago the would-be mother fashioned a doll out of red cotton, pretended to suckle it, and repeated a magic formula; then she sent word through the village that she was pregnant, and her friends came to congratulate her; only a very obstinate reality could refuse to emulate this imagination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The favorite object of primitive tabu was woman.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the end terrestrial forces prevail; morals slowly adjust themselves to economic invention, and religion reluctantly adjusts itself to moral change. The moral function of religion is to conserve established values, rather than to create new ones&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="language" >Language
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#language">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Gesture seems primary, speech secondary, in the earlier transmission of thought; and when speech fails, gesture comes again to the fore.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Gesture was so prominent in some Indian languages that the Arapahos, like some modern peoples, could hardly converse in the dark&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nothing surprises the natural man so much as the ability of Europeans to communicate with one another over great distances, by making black scratches upon a piece of paper&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Perhaps science, like civilization in general, began with agriculture; geometry, as its name indicates, was the measurement of the soil&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Damara natives would not exchange two sheep for four sticks, but willingly exchanged, twice in succession, one sheep for two sticks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Perhaps we should employ another gender here, for probably the first doctors were women; not only because they were the natural nurses of the men, nor merely because they made midwifery rather than venality the oldest profession, but because their closer connection with the soil gave them a superior knowledge of plants, and enabled them to develop the art of medicine as distinct from the magic-mongering of the priests.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is astonishing how many cures primitive doctors effected despite their theories of disease&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="appearance" >Appearance
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#appearance">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Primitive man seldom thinks of selecting women because of what we should call their beauty; he thinks rather of their usefulness, and never dreams of rejecting a strong-armed bride because of her ugliness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There is,&amp;rdquo; says Georg, &amp;ldquo;no part of the body that has not been perfected, decorated, disfigured, painted, bleached, tattooed, reformed, stretched or squeezed, out of vanity or desire for ornament.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Clothing was apparently in its origins, a form of ornament, a sexual deterrent or charm rather than an article of use against cold or shame&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Cook had said of them, timelessly, they were &amp;ldquo;content to be naked, but ambitious to be fine.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Queen of the Wabunias on the Congo wore a brass collar weighing twenty pounds; she had to lie down every now and then to rest. Poor women who were so unfortunate as to have only light jewelry imitated carefully the steps of those who carried great burdens of bedizenment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The taut string of the bow became the origin of a hundred instruments from the primitive lyre to the Stradivarius violin and the modern pianoforte&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Bone tools—pins, anvils, polishers, etc.—were now added to those of stone; and art appeared in the form of crude engravings on the rocks, or simple figurines in high relief, mostly of nude women.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the ruins of a neolithic mine at Brandon, England, eight worn picks of deer horn were found, on whose dusty surfaces were the finger-prints of the workmen who had laid down those tools ten thousand years ago.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="sumeria" >Sumeria
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#sumeria">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;History so soon began its tragic alternance of art and war.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The form of these poems is unexpectedly first-personal, and the style does not please the sophisticated ear; but across the four thousand years that separate us from the Sumerian singer we feel the desolation of his city and his people&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The wars were waged frankly for commercial routes and goods, without catchwords as a sop for idealists&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;King Manish-tusu of Akkad announced frankly that he was invading Elam to get control of its silver mines, and to secure diorite stone to immortalize himself with statuary—the only instance known of a war fought for the sake of art&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The best element in this code was a plan for avoiding litigation: every case was first submitted to a public arbitrator whose duty it was to bring about an amicable settlement without recourse to law. It is a poor civilization from which we may not learn something to improve our own&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;As early as 2000 B.C. Sumerian historians began to reconstruct the past and record the present for the edification of the future; portions of their work have come down to us not in the original form but as quotations in later Babylonian chronicles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="egypt" >Egypt
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#egypt">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nearby, the Sphinx, half lion and half philosopher, grimly claws the sand, and glares unmoved at the transient visitor and the eternal plain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;to bring these vast stones six hundred miles, to raise some of them, weighing many tons, to a height of half a thousand feet, and to pay or even to feed, the hundred thousand slaves who toiled for twenty years on these Pyramids&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;With his knowledge of Greek, and the eleven letters made out from the obelisk, Champollion, after more than twenty years of labor deciphered the whole inscription, discovered the entire Egyptian alphabet, and opened the way to the recovery of a lost world. It was one of the peaks in the history of history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;All the world fears Time,&amp;rdquo; says an Arab proverb, &amp;ldquo;but Time fears the Pyramids.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;this alternation between centralized and decentralized power is one of the cyclical rhythms of history, as if men tired alternately of immoderate liberty and excessive order&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But Hatshepsut set this high-destined youngster aside, assumed full royal powers, and proved herself a king in everything but gender.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;they made everything from boats and carriages, chairs and beds, to handsome coffins that almost invited men to die.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If,&amp;rdquo; says Peschel, &amp;ldquo;we compare the technical inventory of the Egyptians with our own, it is evident that before the invention of the steam-engine we scarcely excelled them in anything.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A chalk tablet in the British Museum contains a chief workman’s record of forty-three workers, listing their absences and their causes—&amp;ldquo;ill,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;sacrificing to the god,&amp;rdquo; or just plain &amp;ldquo;lazy.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;[The] quantity of radishes, garlic and onions consumed by the workmen who built it; these things, too, had to have their immortality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A Greek tradition reports a great revolt in Egypt, in which the slaves captured a province, and held it so long that time, which sanctions everything, gave them legal ownership of it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Machinery was rare because muscle was cheap&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;One tomb inscription describes its occupant as &amp;ldquo;Overseer of the Cosmetic Box, Overseer of the Cosmetic Pencil, Sandal Bearer to the King, doing in the matter of the King’s sandals to the satisfaction of his Law&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;No people, ancient or modern,&amp;ldquo;said Max Müller, &amp;ldquo;has given women so high a legal status as did the inhabitants of the Nile Valley.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Hatshepsut and Cleopatra rose to be queens, and ruled and ruined like kings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;shame is a child of custom rather than of nature,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Copy-books survive from the days of the Empire with the corrections of the masters still adorning the margins; the abundance of errors would console the modern schoolboy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Khekheperre-Sonbu, a savant of the reign of Senusret II, about 2150B.C., complained that all things had long since been said, and nothing remained for literature except repetition.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The sign for 1,000,000 was a picture of a man striking his hands above his head, as if to express amazement that such a number should exist&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Egyptian geometry measured not only the area of squares, circles and cubes, but also the cubic content of cylinders and spheres; and it arrived at 3.16 as the value of π. We enjoy the honor of having advanced from 3.16 to 3.1416 in four thousand years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The wisdom of the Egyptians was a proverb with the Greeks, who felt themselves children beside this ancient race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In part such literature represents one of those interludes, like our own moral interregnum, in which thought has for a time overcome belief, and men no longer know how or why they should live. Such periods do not endure; hope soon wins the victory over thought; the intellect is put down to its customary menial place, and religion is born again, giving to men the imaginative stimulus apparently indispensable to life and work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is one of the tragedies of history that Ikhnaton, having achieved his elevating vision of universal unity, was not satisfied to let the noble quality of his new religion slowly win the hearts of men. He was unable to think of his truth in relative terms; the thought came to him that other forms of belief and worship were indecent and intolerable. Suddenly he gave orders that the names of all gods but Aton should be erased and chiseled from every public inscription in Egypt; he mutilated his father’s name from a hundred monuments to cut from it the word Amon; he declared all creeds but his own illegal, and commanded that all the old temples should be closed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;More and more the people starved in order that the gods might eat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="babylon" >Babylon
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#babylon">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Despite the secular quality of his laws Hammurabi was clever enough to gild his authority with the approval of the gods.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nearly all the bricks so far recovered from the site of Babylon bear the proud inscription: &amp;ldquo;I am Nebuchadrezzar, King of Babylon.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What modern city is so well governed that it would dare to offer such reimbursements to the victims of its negligence? Has the law progressed since Hammurabi, or only increased and multiplied?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We should remember, however, that the defeat of Chaos is only a myth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Even Alexander, who was not above dying of drinking, was shocked by the morals of Babylon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;we cannot judge a civilization from such fragments as the ocean of time has thrown up from the wreckage of Babylon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;These Babylonian libraries are lost; but one of the greatest of them, that of Borsippa, was copied and preserved in the library of Ashurbanipal, whose 30,000 tablets are the main source of our knowledge of Babylonian life&amp;hellip;the avowed purpose of Ashurbanipal’s library was to preserve the literature of Babylonia from oblivion&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But this almost secularized science found itself helpless before the demand of the people for supernatural diagnosis and magical cures. Sorcerers and necromancers were more popular than physicians, and enforced, by their influence with the populace, irrational methods of treatment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;For barbarism is always around civilization, amid it and beneath it, ready to engulf it by arms, or mass migration, or unchecked fertility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;he hunted nations as well as animals:&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;His son Sennacherib put down revolts in the distant provinces adjoining the Persian Gulf, attacked Jerusalem and Egypt without success, sacked eighty-nine cities and 820 villages, captured 7,200 horses, 11,000 asses, 80,000 oxen, 800,000 sheep, and 208,000 prisoners; the official historian, on his life, did not understate these figures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="assyria" >Assyria
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#assyria">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Probably it was in part by their reputation for mercy to prisoners of war that Alexander and Caesar undermined the morale of the enemy, and conquered the Mediterranean world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All in all, the Assyrian government was primarily an instrument of war. For war was often more profitable than peace; it cemented discipline, intensified patriotism, strengthened the royal power, and brought abundant spoils and slaves for the enrichment and service of the capital.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;As we read such pages we become reconciled to our own mediocrity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;but they had brought into Assyria, as captives, millions of destitute aliens who bred with the fertility of the hopeless, destroyed all national unity of character and blood, and became by their growing numbers a hostile and disintegrating force in the very midst of the conquerors&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Like all early voyagers, and some old languages, they made scant distinction between trade and treachery, commerce and robbery; they stole from the weak, cheated the stupid, and were honest with the rest&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="judea" >Judea
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#judea">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Next to the promulgation of the &amp;ldquo;Book of Law,&amp;rdquo; the building of the Temple was the most important event in the epic of the Jews. It not only gave Yahveh a home, but it gave Judea a spiritual center and capital, a vehicle of tradition, a memory to serve as a pillar of fire through centuries of wandering over the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He is talkative, and likes to make long speeches; but he is shy, and will not allow men to see anything of him but his hind parts. Never was there so thoroughly human a god.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He will have no pacifist nonsense; he knows that even a Promised Land can be won, and held, only by the sword;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;it will take centuries of military defeat, political subjugation, and moral development, to transform him into the gentle and loving Father of Hillel and Christ&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Since poverty is created by wealth, and never knows itself poor until riches stare it in the face, so it required the fabulous fortune of Solomon to mark the beginning of the class war in Israel&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is true that Amos dulls the edge of his idealism by putting into the mouth of his god a Mississippi of threats whose severity and accumulation make the reader sympathize for a moment with the drinkers of wine and the listeners to music.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Destroyed and rebuilt, destroyed and rebuilt, Jerusalem rises again, symbol of the vitality and pertinacity of an heroic race. The Jews, who are as old as history, may be as lasting as civilization&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;the scenes of our youth, like the past, are always beautiful if we do not have to live in them again&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="persia" >Persia
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#persia">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;So far as we can visualize him through the haze of legend, he was the most amiable of conquerors, and founded his empire upon generosity. His enemies knew that he was lenient, and they did not fight him with that desperate courage which men show when their only choice is to kill or die&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The first principle of his policy was that the various peoples of his empire should be left free in their religious worship and beliefs, for he fully understood the first principle of statesmanship—that religion is stronger than the state.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He publicly scoffed at the Egyptian religion, and plunged his dagger derisively into the bull revered by the Egyptians as the god Apis; he exhumed mummies and pried into royal tombs regardless of ancient curses; he profaned the temples and ordered their idols to be burned. He thought in this way to cure the Egyptians of superstition; but when he was stricken with illness—apparently epileptic convulsions—the Egyptians were certain that their gods had punished him, and that their theology was now confirmed beyond dispute.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He had hoped to govern in peace, but it is the fatality of empire to breed repeated war&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Persian councils never undertook serious discussions of policy when sober—though they took care to revise their decisions the next morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;For it was a proud boast of Persia that its laws never changed, and that a royal promise or decree was irrevocable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The generosity and kindliness enjoined by the Master did not apply, in practice,to infidels—i.e., foreigners; these were inferior species of men, whom Ahura-Mazda had deluded into loving their own countries only in order that they should not invade Persia.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Persians, says Herodotus, &amp;ldquo;esteem themselves to be far the most excellent of men in every respect&amp;hellip; [they] believe that other nations approach to excellence according to their geographical proximity to Persia, but that they are the worst who live farthest from them&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All in all [Zoroastrianism] was a splendid religion, less warlike and bloody, less idolatrous and superstitious, than the other religions of its time; and it did not deserve to die so soon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But humanity loves poetry more than logic, and without a myth the people perish.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is a testimony to the character of the Persians that whereas any one could hire Greeks to fight Greeks, it was rare indeed that a Persian could be hired to fight Persians.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;They resorted more frequently to spells than to drugs, on the ground that the spells, though they might not cure the illness, would not kill the patient—which was more than could be said for the drugs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When the two armies met at Issus Alexander had no more than 30,000 followers; but Darius, with all the stupidity that destiny could require, had chosen a field in which only a small part of his multitude couldfight at one time. When the slaughter was over the Macedonians had lost some 450, the Persians 110,000 men, most of these being slain in wild retreat;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="india" >India
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#india">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nothing should more deeply shame the modern student than the recency and inadequacy of his acquaintance with India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;our knowledge of the past is an occasional gap in our ignorance&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;They were too primitive to be hypocrites: they subjugated India without pretending to elevate it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;They wanted land, and pasture for their cattle; their word for war said nothing about national honor, but simply meant &amp;ldquo;a desire for more cows&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Marriage might be entered into by forcible abduction of the bride, by purchase of her or by mutual consent. Marriage by consent, however was considered slightly disreputable; women thought it more honorable to be bought and paid for, and a great compliment to be stolen&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;In the whole world,&amp;rdquo; said Schopenhauer &amp;ldquo;there is no study so beneficial and so elevating as that of the Upanishads. It has been the solace of my life—it will be the solace of my death.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Jains, having emptied the sky of God, soon peopled it again with the deified saints of Jain history and legend.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Buddha was convinced that pain so overbalanced pleasure in human life that it would be better never to have been born&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;One of his disciples concluded that Buddha would approve of suicide, but Buddha reproved him; suicide would be useless, since the soul, unpurified, would be reborn in other incarnations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There is nothing stranger in the history of religion than the sight of Buddha founding a worldwide religion, and yet refusing to be drawn into any discussion about eternity, immortality, or God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The simplicity of their laws and their contracts is proved by the fact that they seldom go to law.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The government made no pretense to democracy and was probably the most efficient that India has ever had&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the political sense Ashoka had failed; in another sense he had accomplished one of the greatest tasks in history. Within two hundred years after his death Buddhism had spread throughout India, and was entering upon the bloodless conquest of Asia. If to this day, from Kandy in Ceylonto Kamakura in Japan, the placid face of Gautama bids men be gentle to one another and love peace, it is partly because a dreamer, perhaps a saint, once held the throne of India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Mohammedan Conquest of India is probably the bloodiest story in history. It is a discouraging tale, for its evident moral is that civilization is a precarious thing, whose delicate complex of order and liberty, culture and peace may at any time be overthrown by barbarians invading from without or multiplying within.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Hindus had allowed their strength to be wasted in internal division and war; they had adopted religions like Buddhism and Jainism, which unnerved them for the tasks of life; they had failed to organize their forces for the protection of their frontiers and their capitals, their wealth and their freedom, from the hordes of Scythians, Huns, Afghans and Turks hovering about India’s boundaries and waiting for national weakness to let them in. For four hundred years (600-1000 A.D.) India invited conquest; and at last it came&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;he expressed his admiration for the architecture of the great shrine, judged that its duplication would cost one hundred million dinars and the labor of two hundred years, and then ordered it to be soaked with naphtha and burnt to the ground&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He was generous, expending vast sums in alms; he was affable to all, but especially to the lowly; &amp;ldquo;their little offerings,&amp;rdquo; says a Jesuit missionary &amp;ldquo;he used to accept with such a pleased look, handling them and putting them in his bosom, as he did not do with the most lavish gifts of the nobles.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Deeper than these interests was his penchant for speculation. This well-nigh omnipotent emperor secretly yearned to be a philosopher-much as philosophers long to be emperors, and cannot comprehend the stupidity of Providence in withholding from them their rightful thrones.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Jehangir was not so much a mediocrity as an able degenerate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Emperor himself,in his last years, began to realize that by the very narrowness of his piety he had destroyed the heritage of his fathers. His deathbed letters are pitiful documents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the seventh century the Arabs captured Persia and Egypt, and thereafter trade between Europe and Asia passed through Moslem hands; hence the Crusades, and Columbus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Death was the penalty for any of a great variety of crimes, such as housebreaking, damage to royal property or theft on a scale that would now make a man a very pillar of society&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Better thine own work is, though done with fault,&amp;rdquo; said the Bhagavad-Gita, &amp;ldquo;than doing others’ work, even excellently.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Passages of the Code advocate an enlightened gentleness to women: they are not to be struck &amp;ldquo;even with a flower&amp;rdquo;; they are not to be watched too strictly, for then their subtlety will find a way to mischief; and if they like fine raiment-it is wise to indulge them, for &amp;ldquo;if the wife be not elegantly attired, she will not exhilarate her husband,&amp;rdquo; where as when &amp;ldquo;a wife is gaily adorned, the whole house is embellished.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In so warm a climate clothing was a superfluity, and beggars and saints bridged the social scale in agreeing to do without it. One southern caste, like the Canadian Doukhobors, threatened to migrate if its members were compelled to wear clothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;I have had before me,&amp;rdquo; says a British judge in India,&amp;ldquo;hundreds of cases in which a man’s property liberty and life depended upon his telling a lie, and he has refused to tell it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The growth of Buddhism and monasticism in the first year of our era sapped the manhood of India, and conspired with political division to leave India open to easy conquest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Buddhism, like Christianity, won its greatest triumphs outside the land of its birth; and it won them without shedding a drop of blood&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;the cynical view of the matter is that the Brahmans believed that cows should never be slaughtered, that insects should never be injured, and that widows should be burned alive&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The secret of polytheism is the inability of the simple mind to think in impersonal terms; it can understand persons more readily than forces, wills more easily than laws&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Since the real problem of life is not suffering but undeserved suffering, the religion of India mitigates the human tragedy by giving meaning and value to grief and pain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Doubtless when India was wealthy, sceptics were numerous, for humanity doubts its gods most when it prospers, and worships them most when it is miserable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;They relied upon the conservatism of the poor to preserve the orthodox religion, and they were not disappointed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is India that gave us the ingenious method of expressing all numbers by ten symbols, each receiving a value of position as well as an absolute value; a profound and important idea which appears so simple to us now that we ignore its true merit. But its very simplicity the great ease which it has lent to all computations, puts our arithmetic in the first rank of useful inventions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the time of Yuan Chwang Hindu medical treatment began with a seven-day fast; in this interval the patient often recovered;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Vedas&amp;rdquo; he says, simply, &amp;ldquo;are an authority, since the author of them knew the established truth.&amp;rdquo; After which he proceeds without paying any attention to the Vedas.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Such enlightenment cannot be won at a stroke; the aspirant must move towards it step by step, and no stage of the process can be understood by anyone who has not passed through the stages before it;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;our Way of perceiving will forever be inextricably mingled with the thing perceived.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;As our energies tire in the daily struggle against impartial Nature and hostile Time, we look with more tolerance upon Oriental philosophies of surrender and peace.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Though she passes through the Ordeal of Fire to prove her innocence, he sends her away to a forest hermitage with that bitter trick of heredity whereby one generation repeats upon the next the sins and errors which it suffered from its elders in its youth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;a people that has lost the ability to govern itself, or to develop its natural resources, inevitably falls prey to nations suffering from strength and greed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;sometimes, on a sofa in an inner room, he would spend half a day silent with his memories and his dreams&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Shorn of religious belief, which is the very spirit of India, the Westernized Hindus returned to their country disillusioned and sad; a thousand gods had dropped dead from the skies&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;While still a boy Mohandas became an atheist, being displeased with the adulterous gallantries of certain Hindu gods; and to make clear his everlasting scorn for religion, he ate meat. The meat disagreed with him, and he returned to religion&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Judge expressed his profound regret that he had to send to jail one whom millions of his countrymen considered &amp;ldquo;a great patriot and a great leader&amp;rdquo;; he admitted that even those who differed from Gandhi looked upon him &amp;ldquo;as a man of high ideals and of noble and even saintly life.&amp;rdquo; He sentenced him to prison for six years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It was Gandhi’s task to unify India; and he accomplished it. Other tasks await other men.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="china" >China
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#china">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;China has been called &amp;ldquo;the paradise of historians.&amp;rdquo; For centuries and millenniums it has had official historiographers who recorded everything that happened, and much besides&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;legend, which loves personalities more than ideas, attributes to a few individuals the laborious advances of many generations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;and endeared himself to scholastic posterity by reducing the size of the whip with which Chinese children were educated&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In his reign, according to sacred legend, rice wine was discovered, and was presented to the Emperor; but Yü dashed it to the ground, predicting: &amp;ldquo;The day will come when this thing will cost some one a kingdom.&amp;rdquo; He banished the discoverer and prohibited the new beverage; whereupon the Chinese, for the instruction of posterity, made wine the national beverage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;For the rest we must rely on stories whose truth may not be proportioned to their charm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The historians, more virtuous than history, assure us that Wu Yi was struck dead with lightning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Annoyed by pamphlets in which Teng criticized his policies, the prime minister prohibited the posting of pamphlets inpublic places. Teng thereupon delivered his pamphlets in person. The minister forbade the delivery of pamphlets. Teng smuggled them to his readers by concealing them in other articles. The government ended the argument by cutting off his head&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The intellectual man is a danger to the state because he thinks in terms of regulations and laws; he wishes to construct a society like geometry, and does not realize that such regulation destroys the living freedom and vigor of the parts. The simpler man, who knows from his own experience the pleasure and efficacy of work conceived and carried out in liberty is less of a peril when he is in power for he does not have to be told that a law is a dangerous thing, and may injure more than it may help. Such a ruler regulates men as little as possible; if he guides the nation it is away from all artifice and complexity towards a normal and artless simplicity, in which life would follow the wisely thoughtless routine of nature,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the ancient days, says Lao, nature made men and life simple and peaceful, and all the world was happy. But then men attained knowledge, they complicated life with inventions, they lost all mental and moral innocence, they moved from the fields to the cities, and began to write books; hence all the misery of men, and the tears of the philosophers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Passivity has its victories more often than action&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;if the wise man knows more than other men he tries to conceal it; &amp;ldquo;he will temper his brightness, and bring himself into agreement with the obscurity (of others); he agrees with the simple rather than with the learned, and does not suffer from the novice’s instinct of contradiction&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;and indeed, from some points of view it is one of the most culpable oversights of nature that virtue and beauty so often come in separate packages&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Confucius taught the art of reasoning not through rules or syllogisms, but by the perpetual play of his keen mind upon the opinions of his pupils; when they went out from his school they knew nothing about logic, but they could think clearly and to the point&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Obscurity of thought and insincere inaccuracy of speech seemed to him national calamities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;men will not take seriously one who is not serious with them;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There was not much of the revolutionist in Confucius; perhaps he suspected that the inheritors of a revolution are made of the same flesh as the men whom it deposed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Therefore the prime instrument of government is good example: the ruler must be an eminence of model behavior, from which, by prestige imitation, right conduct will pour down upon his people&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the long run the philosophy of Confucius triumphed. We shall see later how the mighty Shih Huang-ti, with a Legalist for his prime minister, sought to end the influence of Confucius by ordering that all existing Confucian literature should be burned. But the power of the word proved stronger than that of the sword; the books which the &amp;ldquo;First Emperor&amp;rdquo; sought to destroy became holy and precious through his enmity, and men died as martyrs in the effort to preserve them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He was among the earliest of Chinese logicians, and the worst of Chinese reasoners&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It is true that the wicked sometimes leave a bad name behind them, but this is a matter that does not disturb their bones&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Again we suspect that time, who is a reactionary, has preserved for us the most respectable of Chinese thinkers, and has swallowed nearly all the rest in the limbo of forgotten souls&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We perceive how old are the political problems, attitudes and solutions of our enlightened age when we learn that Mencius was rejected by the princes for his radicalism, and was scorned for his conservatism by the socialists&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;return to Nature,&amp;rdquo; however, could not be so readily discouraged; it found voice in this age as in every other&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If by some negligence on his part, a true philosopher should find himself in charge of a state, his proper course would be to do nothing, and allow men in freedom to build their own organs of self-government.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yao and Shun, instead of being so honored by China and Confucius, should be charged with having destroyed the primitive happiness of mankind by introducing government&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Huns, barred for a time from Chinese soil, moved west into Europe and down into Italy; Rome fell because China built a wall&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He decreed that his dynastic successors should number themselves from him as &amp;ldquo;First Emperor,&amp;rdquo; down to the ten thousandth of their line; but the line ended with his son.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Disorder followed his death, as it has followed the passing of almost every dictator in history; only an immortal can wisely take all power into his hands&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;On his accession to power he surrounded himself not with the usual politicians, but with men trained in letters and philosophy; to these men his enemies attributed his failure, and his friends attributed his success.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Wang had conceived his policies in economic terms, and had forgotten the nature of man. He worked long hours, day and night, to devise schemes that would make the nation rich and happy; and he was heart broken to find that social disorder mounted during his reign.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What we do see is, above all, brevity. We are apt to think these poems too slight, and feel an unreal disappointment at missing the majesty and boredom of Milton and Homer. But the Chinese believe that all poetry must be brief; that a long poem is a contradiction in terms—since poetry, to them, is a moment’s ecstasy, and dies when dragged out in epic reams&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;The men of old,&amp;rdquo; say the Chinese, &amp;ldquo;reckoned it the highest excellence in poetry that the meaning should be beyond the words, and that the reader should have to think it out for himself.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Like Chinese manners and art, Chinese poetry is a matter of infinite grace concealed in a placid simplicity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Chinese pardonably consider their literature superior to any other than that of Greece; and perhaps the exception is due to Oriental courtesy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;and this office of court historian, carried down to our own generation, has raised up in China a mass of historical literature unequaled in length or dullness anywhere else on the earth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In a conflict between superstition and philosophy one may safely wager on the victory of superstition, for the world wisely prefers happiness to wisdom&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;As the result of Ch’ien Lung’s prohibition of woman players, female parts were acted by men, and so well that when women were in our time again admitted to the stage, they had to imitate their imitators in order to succeed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;and brought to many hearers that escape from the strife of wills and ideas which comes with the surrender to music well composed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The pursuit of wisdom and the passion for beauty are the two poles of the Chinese mind, and China might loosely be defined as philosophy and porcelain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Finally their greatest achievements were unconsciously hidden from Western travelers. For the Chinese do not flaunt their pictures on public or private walls; they roll them up and store them carefully away and unfold them for occasional enjoyment as we take down and read a book&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Hui Tsung, with an empire at his command, gave half his life to painting birds and flowers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;the world of beauty and the world of money never touch, even when beautiful things are sold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The educated classes displayed long nails as Western women wore French heels—to indicate their exemption from physical toil&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the third century Hua To wrote a volume on surgery and made operations popular by inventing a wine which produced a general anesthesia; it is one of the stupidities of history that the formula for mixing this drink has been lost&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Soap was a rare luxury, but lice and vermin were easily secured&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;For through this profound institution the nation, which was shut out from physical and spatial unity by great distances and the poverty of transport, achieved a powerful spiritual unity in time; the generations were bound together with the tough web of tradition, and the individual life received an ennobling share and significance in a drama of timeless majesty and scope.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But in the second century of our era these doctrines were improved upon by men who claimed to have received, in direct line from Lao-tze, an elixir that would confer immortality. This drink became so popular that several emperors are said to have died from pious indulgence in it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What the Chinese,&amp;rdquo; said Voltaire, &amp;ldquo;best know, cultivate the most, and have brought to the greatest perfection, is morality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;By building the house on a sound foundation,&amp;rdquo; Confucius had said, &amp;ldquo;the world is made secure&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Though economically subordinate the woman enjoyed the franchise of the tongue, and might scold her man into fright or flight in the best Occidental style&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The most impressive aspect of this civilization was its system of government. If the ideal state is a combination of democracy and aristocracy, the Chinese have had it for more than a thousand years; if the best government is that which governs least, then the Chinese have had the best. Never has a government governed so many people, or governed them so little, or so long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There was not a word in any of the tests about science, business or industry; the object was to reveal not knowledge but judgment and character. Those who survived the tests were at last eligible for the higher offices in the state&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Considerable portions of this indemnity were later remitted to China by the United States, Great Britain, Russia and Japan, usually with the stipulation that the remitted sums bespent in educating students from China in the universities of the remitting nation. It was a gesture of generosity, which proved more effective in the undoing of old China than almost any other single factor in this historic and tragic conflict of East and West.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The European world, which had proposed a moratorium on robbery after it had gathered in all available spoils joined America feebly in protests against this candid plunder, but prepared, as always, to accept victory as justification in the end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Once everything changed except the East; now there is nothing in the East that does not change. The most conservative nation in history has suddenly become, after Russia, the most radical, and is destroying with a will customs and institutions once held inviolate. It is not merely the end of a dynasty, as in 1644; it is the moulting of a civilization&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The queue is gone, and so are the graceful manners of the older time; the hatreds of revolution have coarsened the spirit, and radicals find it hard to be courteous to conservatives&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Revolution, like death and style, is the removal of rubbish, the surgery of the superfluous; it comes only when there are many things ready to die. China has died many times before; and many times she has been reborn.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="japan" >Japan
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#japan">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The feudal system triumphed in Japan for the same reason that it had triumphed in Europe: local sources of authority grew in power as a central and distant government failed to maintain security and order&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Kublai ordered from his ship-builders so vast a fleet that Chinese poets represented the hills as mourning for their denuded forests&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Japanese, in heroic retrospect, reckoned the vessels at 70,000, but less patriotic historians are content with 3,500 ships and 100,000 men&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The legal system of Japan was a vigorous supplement to private assassination and revenge&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In the Nara period the state nationalized the land, and rented it to the peasant for six years or at most, till death; but the government discovered that men did not care to improve or properly care for land that might in a short time be assigned to others; and the experiment ended in a restoration of private ownership, with state provision of funds in the spring to finance the planting and reaping of the crops&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When he heard that Hideyoshi was coming to see his famous collection of chrysanthemums, Rikyu destroyed all the blossoms in his garden but one, so that this might shine unrivaled before the terrible shogun&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Flowers are the religion of the Japanese; they worship them with sacrificial fervor and national accord. They watch for the blossoms appropriate to each season; and when, for a week or two in early April, the cherry-tree blooms, all Japan seems to leave its work to gaze at it, or even to make pilgrimages to places where the miracle is most abundant and complete&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Criminals en route to execution will sometimes ask for a flower&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The more serious devotee might cleanse his spirit by praying for a quarter of an hour under a waterfall in the depth of winter; or he might go on pilgrimages from shrine to shrine of his sect, meanwhile feasting his soul on the beauty of his native land&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The aim of learning is not merely to widen knowledge but to form character. Its object is to make us true men, rather than learned men.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The chief reason why the teachings of the sages are not more appreciated by the people is because scholars endeavor to show off their learning, rather than to make it their endeavor to live up to the teachings of the sages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Shogunate trembled at the notion that every man might judge for himself what was right and what was wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When he died they placed this enviable epitaph upon his tomb: He did not talk about the faults of others&amp;hellip;He cared for nothing but books. His life was uneventful&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Unlike Togai he enjoyed controversy and spoke his mind violently about philosophers living or dead. When an inquiring young man asked him, &amp;ldquo;What do you like besides reading?&amp;rdquo; he answered, &amp;ldquo;There is nothing better than eating burnt beans and criticizing the great men of Japan.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Jesuits, harassed with these linguistic barriers, reported that the language of the islands had been invented by the Devil to prevent the preaching of the Gospel to the Japanese.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Japanese, with whom gambling is a favorite passion, wagered so much money in haiku-composing contests that some enterprising souls made a business of conducting them, fleecing thousands of devotees daily, until at last the government was forced to raid these poetical resorts and prohibit this new mercenary art&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Murasaki writes with a naturalness and ease that soon turn her pages into the charming gossip of a cultured friend.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;He accepted poverty with good humor and, having no furniture, hung his bare walls with paintings of the furniture he might have had.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;On his deathbed Ikku enjoined his pupils to place upon his corpse, before the cremation then usual in Japan, certain packets which he solemnly entrusted to them. At his funeral, prayers having been said, the pyre was lighted, whereupon it turned out that the packets were full of firecrackers, which exploded merrily. Ikku had kept his youthful promise that his life would be full of surprises, even after his death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The death of a civilization seldom comes from without; internal decay must weaken the fibre of a society before external influences or attacks can change its essential structure, or bring it to an end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The eternal war of the generations—the revolt of over-eager youth against overcautious age—has been intensified by the growth of individualist industry, and the weakening of religious faith&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A Chinese boycott of Japanese goods ensued; but Japan proceeded on the historically correct assumption that boycotts are sooner or later frustrated by the tendency of trade to follow the line of lowest costs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion" >Conclusion
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#conclusion">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The institutions, customs, arts and morals of a people represent the natural selection of its countless trial-and-error experiments,the accumulated and unformulable wisdom of all its generations;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Europe and America are the spoiled child and grandchild of Asia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It would conceive man as a citizen rather than as a subject; it would give him political liberty civil rights, and an unparalleled measure of mental and moral freedom; it would create democracy and invent the individual.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Penultimate Wave of AI</title><link>/blog/the-penultimate-wave-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:46:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-penultimate-wave-of-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think &lt;a href="https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1">r1&lt;/a> will get us to artificial super intelligence, but whatever comes next probably will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are reaching a familiar bottleneck in AI. Previously, humans had to manually hardcode the patterns that AI could recognize. With deep learning, machines began to learn patterns on their own, without human assistance. With (relatively) expensive humans out of the loop, we threw machines at the world&amp;rsquo;s data until they began to talk, code, and paint. Many people believed this would be sufficient to reach artificial super intelligence&amp;ndash;but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We ran out of data. Luckily, our newborn bots could talk 24/7&amp;ndash;not just to hundreds of millions of people, but also to other programs. These programs would ask the bots questions, verify their answer, and then use the correct answers to further improve the models. Free, infinite data. If the world&amp;rsquo;s data wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, then infinite data must be&amp;ndash;but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are now watching the rise of reasoners&amp;ndash;models that &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; before giving an answer. Models which generate a series of words to raise the probability of eventually producing something we want. Surely, &lt;em>surely&lt;/em>, this is it. Once we train a model to reason, it will be able to reason about its own answers, and somehow, magically, self-improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This infinite self-improvement probably won&amp;rsquo;t happen. In the same way that a fixed amount of mass can&amp;rsquo;t produce infinite energy, I suspect a fixed amount of information can&amp;rsquo;t produce infinite intelligence, no matter how much we feed it back into itself. Fundamentally, a model needs information from the outside, whether that information is a response from an external system or a human filtering its prior output for quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We provide some external information using formal verification systems, which is why math and programming performace is the &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/learning-to-reason-with-llms/">prominent flex&lt;/a> from the latest models. But most domains, like biology, business, and rocket science, are not so lucky; the correct answer is rarely obvious, even for programming. How does one automatically verify an interface is easy to use?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer still comes down to humans. Much to the dismay of a few arrogant men in San Francisco, people are still a key ingredient. This time, we don&amp;rsquo;t merely tell machines what patterns to look for; rather, we filter synthetic data to &amp;ldquo;steer&amp;rdquo; the model towards answers we prefer, i.e, we tell them what patterns to look for, but cheaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, if the right mixture of curated data could yield superintelligence, it would have&amp;ndash;models are now &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12948v1">crushing benchmarks which PhDs struggle on&lt;/a>. This is ridiculous. We&amp;rsquo;re going to wring these models of performance until they&amp;rsquo;re dry, and even then they won&amp;rsquo;t be superintelligent. Aside from extending formal verification, the way forward still seems to be curating the reasoning data these models generate and feeding it back in. As chains of reasoning become longer and more complex, human-curated data will likely yield increasingly diminishing returns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll be approaching the limit of what these systems can do. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, they can do a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em>&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re basically magic&amp;ndash;but they can&amp;rsquo;t generally self-improve without humans or verifiers. And honestly, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what else comes next besides self-improving AI. We don&amp;rsquo;t know what that looks like&amp;ndash;maybe some &lt;a href="https://puffer.ai/">multiagent game-playing system&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;but whatever it is, it will be the last. For real, this time. Probably.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reducing Code Complexity using UI</title><link>/blog/reducing-code-complexity-using-ui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 07:01:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/reducing-code-complexity-using-ui/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m doing an internship right now, and thankfully, I read a few books on software design before starting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to design a database schema, data submission page, submission approval page, and dynamic dashboard for the project I was assigned to. This is one of those projects that AI can obviously do 90% of to work for if designed appropriately&amp;ndash;if the right abstractions are used, performance trade-offs are made, and the right tools are chosen. I wanted to make sure that, throughout the project, AI could always easily with any part of the codebase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For AI, code simplicity is a non-negotiable. Your code needs to be small, modular and clear, full stop. AI doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with complex code bases with many unfamiliar datastructures across multiple files yet, so one goal was limit the codebase for each webpage to a single file, and for that file to be as small as possible, which worked really well. Being able to copy+paste your entire codebase into ChatGPT is very powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We wanted to implement features such that the user would never end up in a slightly unintuitive state, specifically, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want users to normalize data by a series and view the data in log scale simultaneously. The issue is, given our tooling, it would take a decent chunk of code (relative to our codebase) to make it impossible to end up in such a state, and would require some logic to manage which action they took first. Did they normalize first, then try to view in log scale? Or did they try to view in log scale, and then normalize? What should take priority? What does the user expect?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of increasing the complexity and control flow to handle this, I instead tried to first make it clear to the user exactly what state they were in. We added a large, visible red X to the normalization dropdown to draw the user&amp;rsquo;s attention to the &amp;ldquo;Clear Normalization Series&amp;rdquo; option, which resets the chart to the absolute values, instead of relative. From the user perspective, this makes it clear when you are working with normalized data, so when you view in log scale, you know what you&amp;rsquo;re looking at, and can decide for yourself what view you want to see. If you want to see something unintuitive, no biggie, it&amp;rsquo;s obvious what you are looking at. The &amp;ldquo;Make the X big and Red&amp;rdquo; commit was a couple lines of CSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a &amp;ldquo;Graph Builder&amp;rdquo; feature, we initially planned to add a large number of buttons, dropdowns, and toggles to the UI elements so users can specify which types of data they want to view, and how they want to filter it. Adding the UI elements for each field would be a complexity nightmare, since we have a growing number of fields, many of which have missing data. However, we know our users are not our customers but rather internal employees, who have no other choice but to use our tool, and can afford a bit of a learning curve, since they will likely be using it for a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of adding potentially hundreds of lines of UI code/ callbacks, default options, and graceful handling of incompatible conditions, our solution is simply to allow users to specify a custom MongoDB query to fetch the data they want to visualize. This is the most powerful option, as it easily gives our users any view they desire, but it also requires that they know the database schema, which is annoying, even for me, the guy who made designed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make this feature user-friendly, we added a small &amp;ldquo;Show Query&amp;rdquo; button to all existing charts, so users can easily copy and maste queries used for existing graphs, gaining exposure to some of the fields and valies in the schema. This is a good start, but it&amp;rsquo;s still annoying to remember what additional fields are available, and what the current options are. This dashboard will have a tiny number of users and a modest amount of data, so what we can actually do, is run the working textarea query on each keystroke (if it&amp;rsquo;s valid) and, if no data is found, find out which values/fields don&amp;rsquo;t exist in the schema, and dynamically update a message below the text area with a list of existing entries which the user can type, all of which are easy to read. This too is a few extra lines of code, but allows the user to easily discover any field or value they want to use as they are typing the query. As a bonus, it allows users to save custom views in plain text as a MongoDB query, if they want to save or share them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By rethinking how we conveyed information to the user, we avoided increasing the complexity of our codebase in the first place. This approach doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to all scenarios, especially if your users are paying customers, but it&amp;rsquo;s great when it does.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eudaimonia in the Information Age</title><link>/blog/eudaimonia-in-the-information-age/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 16:48:51 -0800</pubDate><guid>/blog/eudaimonia-in-the-information-age/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eudaimonia">Wikipedia&lt;/a> translates the Greek philosophical concept of Eudaimonia as “Human Flourishing”, particularly on the spiritual level. It refers to genuine happiness and fulfillment over hedonism or GDP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The modern world feels meaningless at times. Instead of hunting or farming to put food on the table, many of us sit at a computer or stand behind a counter, far removed from the fruits of our labor—if our labor even bears fruit. Our screens bombard us with videos of people more beautiful and successful than we could ever hope to be while we stay inside, alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life is no longer a struggle for survival for many of us; it’s a struggle for meaning. We evolved to invoke happiness and fulfillment in completely different conditions than those in which we now reside. Like a camera trying to take pictures in the dark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve struggled immensely to find meaning and pride in the past, but I’ve found my light recently, and I wanted to write it down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve always held anger towards myself, to the point where I eventually collapsed. When I put myself back together over the following ten months, the anger didn’t disappear, but scattered, into hundreds of tiny thoughts, impulsive comments, and subconscious beliefs. To stop these ideas from coalescing back into a goliath of gloom, I began to read books on zen, to some success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up taking a four-month internship across the country. I was isolated, away from friends and family, and probably talking to ChatGPT more than real people. Strangely, despite this, I thrived. I started focusing more on myself: I began fasting, took better care of my appearance, found my sense of style, and watched videos on improving my communication skills. I started to fill in the gaps in my knowledge of history and world politics. I becme the person who I wanted to be. Both my confidence and competence skyrocketed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Life is full of many cognitive plagues, things that will always bother you somewhere deep down. Whether it’s your appearance, your intelligence, your family, your job, it just never sits quite right. I wasn’t living a bad life before, but I still had these persistent, negative feelings. The difference in how I feel now is night and day. I feel like I’m nearing my true potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All I had to do is, well, everything. For the many sources of negative thoughts, I had to actually &lt;em>try&lt;/em> to deal with it to some extent, and make progress. I’m not the most attractive guy in the world, but at least I feel comfortable with my hair quality now. I&amp;rsquo;m not the best speaker, but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to slow down and speak with clarity and confidence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nietzsche describes the concept of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%9Cbermensch">Übermensch&lt;/a>, which I interpret as “the ideal version of ourselves”. We can’t permanently reach this ideal, but we can strive for it, and, for brief periods, embody it. The Übermensch serves as a guide; I&amp;rsquo;d literally ask myself, &amp;lsquo;What would my Übermensch do?&amp;rsquo; and then do that, because the answer was always obvious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often focus our efforts on improving one aspect of our lives, like our career or health, which is important, but always leaves another aspect with which we are dissatisfied. I now feel like I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with every aspect of myself. I&amp;rsquo;m not perfect, not by a long shot, but there&amp;rsquo;s no longer parts of myself that I truly despise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t feel this way forever. I&amp;rsquo;ll break down again, and hopefully, get back up once more. But I wanted to log these thoughts while they are still fresh, so I (or someone else) can find strength.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Originality in the Age of AI</title><link>/blog/upwards-pressure-on-originality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 09:23:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>/blog/upwards-pressure-on-originality/</guid><description>&lt;p>It used to be good enough just to copy others. Now, with AI in the hands of billions, there&amp;rsquo;s little value in copying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, take programming. Five years ago, building apps, websites, or games required a non-trivial amount of skill, and getting your first project off the ground was an accomplishment. Now, AI can generate most starter projects in hours, if not minutes. I think this decimates the reward, both internal and external, of actually completing the first few projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, it&amp;rsquo;s less impressive, which, in my opinion, matters. We like the feeling of pride we get when we show our work to others, especially when just starting out. It&amp;rsquo;s sad to diminish the relative value of someone&amp;rsquo;s work when they are just starting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, it&amp;rsquo;s less satisfying for us. For those who just want to build useful tools, modern technology is great. But, for those who want to feel a sense of reward for creating something, it&amp;rsquo;s sad, I think. There&amp;rsquo;s still lots to build, but for most projects, especially starter projects, the internal payoff&amp;rsquo;s been greatly diminished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This might have long-term consequences, because to get to the point where you can build something truly original, you first have to build many things which are unoriginal. The end goal of making something new is still just as valuable, if not more so, but the journey to develop the skills and original voice seems more mundane than ever. I also suspect that the next generation, who learns from AI will be significantly less technically competent, as they may never need to understand the technology they are working with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this will place an upwards pressure on originality and novelty. Now that both the technical barrier to entry and the cost of producing unoriginal work is so low, society will start to value original ideas more than ever&amp;ndash;doubly so if we reduce the rewards of the journey towards becoming original and skilled. If the world becomes flooded with less original, less technical users of AI, the value of technical competence and originality will skyrocket.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple Announces iPad Pro Max</title><link>/blog/apple-announces-ipad-pro-max/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 11:22:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/apple-announces-ipad-pro-max/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>CUPERTINO, CALIFORNIA&lt;/strong> - Apple today announced the release of the groundbreaking iPad Pro Max, the world&amp;rsquo;s first tablet powered by the all-new quantum Q1 processor. Capable of 30 octillion floating point operations per second, the Q1 makes the iPad Pro Max the most powerful streaming device ever made, over 2x faster than the M4 iPad Pro. Available in both 11-inch and 13-inch sizes, Apple says that the iPad Pro Max is the perfect device for generating TV shows, movies, and games in real-time on the go using the power of AI, no network connection needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new iPad Pro Max&amp;ndash;the thinnest device Apple has ever created&amp;ndash;features a stunningly thin and light design, taking portability to a whole new level. The 11-inch model is just 3 nanometers thin&amp;ndash;thinner than a piece of paper&amp;ndash;and the 13-inch model is just 2 nanometers, thanks to TSMC&amp;rsquo;s cutting-edge 2-nanometer process, ensuring that you always have enough space in your bag for your Macbook to do real work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the iPad Pro Max&amp;rsquo;s stunning 16k display, today&amp;rsquo;s children can play Roblox in stunning detail, giving them the edge they need to dominate their less-affluent friends. With 100,000 nits of peak brightness, the iPad Pro Max can even be seen on the surface of the sun, enabling our astronauts to make the music they dreamed of in Garageband while still maintaining 10 minutes of battery life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beautiful Magic Keyboard Pro Max is the perfect companion for the iPad Pro Max. Featuring a new function row, larger trackpad, and hydraulic press, we can crush the dreams of our users and regulators like never before. The gorgeous aluminum palm rest and trackpad with haptic feedback makes the entire experience feel just like using a macbook, without the software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vesatility of the iPad Pro Max is enhanced by the new Apple Pencil Pro Max, which can now be used to write on any surface, including the air, thanks to Apple&amp;rsquo;s new AirInk technology, enabling anyone to change the world with a stroke. The Apple Pencil Pro Max starts at just $199,999.99, the Magic Keyboard Pro Max at $399,999.99, and the iPad Pro Max at just $999,999.99.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The iPad Pro Max is designed with the environment in mind. Featuring the thinnest, most irrepairable design in any product to date, the iPad Pro Max is guaranteed to take up less space in landfills than any other tablet on the market. Apple has also announced a new Core Technology Recycling Program, customers can return unsupported devices to Apple, in exchange for Apple charging a $0.50 Core Technology Recycling fee to the developer of each non-Apple app remaining on the device.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Reasonable Effectiveness of Using Old Phones as Servers</title><link>/blog/phone-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 14:42:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/phone-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>I installed &lt;a href="https://postmarketos.org">linux&lt;/a> on a OnePlus6T. Setup took less than an hour, technical issues included.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="why" >Why
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#why">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>$90 for 8GB RAM, 128GB storage, 2.8GHz 8-core CPU&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.postmarketos.org/wiki/OnePlus_6_(oneplus-enchilada)">Linux on the OnePlus 6T&lt;/a> is &lt;a href="blog/take-the-road-most-documented/">well documented&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Low power consumption&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Tiny&lt;/em> footprint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No additional cables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built-in battery backup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WiFi, bluetooth, speaker, screen, etc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Negligible environmental impact sans shipping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wanted to play with Linux on ARM&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t need a dedicated cable to power or connect it. Running on wifi, it only needs to be plugged into my phone&amp;rsquo;s charger. Whenever I need to charge my phone, I unplug the server and plug in my phone. It takes up so little space that I &lt;em>literally leave it on my night stand&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="unexpected-issues" >Unexpected Issues
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#unexpected-issues">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the Phosh image to boot, so I used the Plasma Mobile image instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The phone would suspend after a few minutes of inactivity. This caused a lot of issues over SSH and took a while to figure out, since servers usually don&amp;rsquo;t suspend.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="docker" >Docker
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#docker">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>After resolving the suspend issues, docker appears to work fine. Surprisingly, many images support ARM!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="tailscale" >Tailscale
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#tailscale">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I installed &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com">tailscale&lt;/a> to access the server remotely without exposing it to the internet. Tailscale is phenomenal, my grandma could set it up in less than five minutes if she needed to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="viability-as-a-regular-phone" >Viability as a regular phone
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#viability-as-a-regular-phone">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>The OnePlus 6T is so much faster than a &lt;a href="https://pine64.org/devices/pinephone/">PinePhone&lt;/a>, the Linux phone I used previously. But Linux still isn&amp;rsquo;t ready for daily-driving:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I need to manually connect to wifi for each reboot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The app ecosystem is still a work in progress, missing polished apps for navigation, cameras, streaming, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Traditional Linux apps like Firefox don&amp;rsquo;t scale properly&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Hopefully these issues are resolved in the future, but for now, the 6T is an excellent server.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="other-remarks" >Other Remarks
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#other-remarks">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with a few containers, but still haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on specific services to run yet. I&amp;rsquo;m considering:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://keila.io">Keila&lt;/a> for adding a newsletter to my blog&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org">Mastodon&lt;/a> to test running an activitypub server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://matrix.org">Matrix Synapse/Dendrite&lt;/a> and assorted &lt;a href="https://matrix.org/ecosystem/bridges/">bridges&lt;/a> for chat&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll post updates as things progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="related-projects" >Related Projects
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#related-projects">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12172">Scalable Smartphone Cluster for Deep Learning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.hpcwire.com/2015/01/27/new-purpose-old-smartphones-cluster-computing/">A new purpose for Old Smartphones: Cluster Computing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2023/04/27/using-an-old-smartphone-in-place-of-a-raspberry-pi/">Using an Old Smartphone in Place of a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Zen in the Art of Beat Saber</title><link>/blog/zen-in-the-art-of-beat-saber/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:21:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/zen-in-the-art-of-beat-saber/</guid><description>&lt;p>Contents: &lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#step-away-come-back-later">Step away, come back later&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#focus-but-not-too-much">Focus, but not too much&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#generalization-comes-after-specialization">Generalization comes after specialization&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to">Don&amp;rsquo;t bother if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#let-go">Let Go&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction" >Introduction
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#introduction">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I recently read &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_in_the_Art_of_Archery">Zen in the Art of Archery&lt;/a>, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a book about archery as much as it is a book about zen. The book describes author&amp;rsquo;s journey learning archery from a zen master. I highly recommend it, the book is a short read&amp;ndash;I finished it in a day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My core takeaway, which fails to properly describe book, is the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To master archery, the archer must first let go of their body and mind so they can be one with the art. This can only be achieved with an open mind through extensive practice.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I was mesmerized by the dedication, personal growth and the zen-like state the author achieved throughout his journey. I wanted to try something similar but have neither materials for archery or a zen master. I do, however, have a VR headset and a copy of &lt;a href="https://www.beatsaber.com/">Beat Saber&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/beatsaber/s/TSEdiDeJzk">which can apparently induce a feeling of zen&lt;/a>. I gave it a shot, silly as it seems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beat Saber a game where you need to slice blocks in a specific direction to the beat of a song. The harder the level, the more notes you have to hit per second. If you miss too many notes within a short time span, you fail the song. For reference, here is a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vXfw-fhmPc">video of gameplay on an easier difficulty&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N6Y7ZgxeTUs&amp;amp;">video of gameplay on harder difficulty&lt;/a>, and a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_songs_in_Beat_Saber">list&lt;/a> of the songs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My initial goal was to beat all ten songs in the first volume of the free soundtrack on the hardest difficulty, &lt;em>Expert+&lt;/em> (I also started this to get myself to exercise, but that&amp;rsquo;s less exciting). As someone who couldn&amp;rsquo;t beat a single medium difficulty song on &lt;em>Guitar Hero 3&lt;/em> as a child, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to beat anything on the hardest setting, let alone one that required physical activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you the hero&amp;rsquo;s journey: I beat all ten songs on &lt;em>Expert+&lt;/em> in a few weeks. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe my progress; I figured beating a single level would take me at least a month or two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to push myself and beat all the songs in all six original soundtracks on &lt;em>Expert+&lt;/em>. Again, I figured the levels would get harder, and I&amp;rsquo;d spend weeks mastering some of the harder songs. They did get significantly harder, but I chiped away at all but the six fastest songs over the course of another few weeks, one song at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still no zen-master, but I wanted to share some lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, which I think can apply to lots of aspects of life. Take these with a grain of salt, of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-away-come-back-later" >Step away, come back later
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#step-away-come-back-later">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The body naturally improves once you let it rest and process. I&amp;rsquo;d struggle with a song one night only to beat it on the first try the following morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="focus-but-not-too-much" >Focus, but not too much
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#focus-but-not-too-much">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Instead of restarting a failed song from the beginning, I relied on practice mode, which lets you start the song from any time. I drilled the sections I struggled with at lower speeds, ramping up the speed as I improved, eventually going back and beating the full song. Said in reverse, I wasted little time on the easy parts and made good use of my time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got tired of a song, I switched to one that I previously beat, but found that I rusted. Switching it up and reviewing things I previously mastered improved my general ability and allowed me to perform better when encountering a new song.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="generalization-comes-after-specialization" >Generalization comes after specialization
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#generalization-comes-after-specialization">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I spent most of my time drilling specific sequences of notes in certain songs, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t think would generalize well to other songs. While true to some extent, this practice helped me master patterns which would took similar forms elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the same principle applies to learning in general, at least for me. I learn better when I start from examples and experience. Only after a while do I obtain the subconscious instincts required to shift my attention from the specifics to the higher level abstractions. My growth as a programmer followed a similar path, and the same is true for chess grandmasters from what I hear.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to" >Don&amp;rsquo;t bother if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>During faster, less-intuitive sequences, I&amp;rsquo;d often fail because I attempted to hit every single note. I noticed that I&amp;rsquo;d usually go down-hill after making a few consecutive mistakes which threw me off. Instead of drilling these sequences to mastery, I realized I could flat-out ignore the few pain points that disrupted my flow without failing the track.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="let-go" >Let Go
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#let-go">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Eventually, the songs got so fast that my conscious mind couldn&amp;rsquo;t process rapid sequences in time. These parts weren&amp;rsquo;t counter-intuitive or confusing like prior sequences I drilled, they were simply &lt;em>too fast&lt;/em>. I felt drilling these sequences wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help, no matter the speed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The strategy that eventually worked was &amp;ldquo;not thinking&amp;rdquo;, true to zen philosophy. For most of the song, I&amp;rsquo;d consciously process the notes and patterns as they came, but for the fastest sequences, I would clear my mind, and operate purely on instinct for a few seconds. This was perhaps the most surpising part of this journey&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;d often be able to land a perfect or near-perfect combo once my mind no longer got in the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="final-thoughts" >Final Thoughts
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#final-thoughts">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I plan on beating the remaining songs, and will update this post if/when I do. I did not expect this experiment to go anywhere, but I learned a surprising amount about myself, my learning process, and breaking my limits. With the exception of brief moments, I don&amp;rsquo;t experience a zen-like state when playing, but I do notice that I need to &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing significantly less.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emergent Trade and Tolerated Theft Using Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning</title><link>/blog/emergent-trade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 12:14:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/emergent-trade/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been an author on a few papers before, but I recently published the first research project where I was responsible for most of the work and direction. It&amp;rsquo;s in the first 2024 issue of the journal &lt;em>Artificial Life&lt;/em>, which you can find &lt;a href="https://direct.mit.edu/artl/article-abstract/doi/10.1162/artl_a_00423/119154/Emergent-Resource-Exchange-and-Tolerated-Theft">here&lt;/a>. You can find a non-paywalled version &lt;a href="./trade-paper.pdf">here&lt;/a> Below, I tell the chronology of the project and summarize our findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./trade.gif" alt="Emergent Trade" loading="lazy">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We explore the conditions under which trade can emerge between four deep reinforcement learning agents that pick up and put down resources in a 2D foraging environment. Agents are rewarded for having both resources once, but the resources are distributed far apart from each other. To maximize reward, agents need to split up the work - agent 1 goes to resource A, agent 2 goes to resource B, etc, and then they meet to exchange resources, since meeting halfway can get them the most of each resource in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was working on this for a while in isolation, getting nowhere, and slowly going crazy. A few months later, Deepmind published a &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.06760">paper&lt;/a> that explored this exact behavior&amp;mdash;and found that agents could not discover how to exchange goods without programming a trading system into the game mechanics directly. I was getting similar results, but found that this trading behavior could emerge if I rewarded agents for being physically close to one another, which we&amp;rsquo;ll call a &amp;ldquo;community bonus&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I reached out to the authors (great people btw), and they hypothesized that the trading behavior was a result of agents trying to keep each other alive to get the community bonus. In my setup, agents could die if they ran out of resources, so they were also keeping each other alive for company. The authors suggested I add some sort of &amp;ldquo;market&amp;rdquo;, a place for agents to meet up and trade without getting directly rewarded for giving away resources for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They explored similar ideas in their work, and if they couldn&amp;rsquo;t get this behavior to emerge, what chance did I have? I needed to try something similar but sufficiently different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of adding a market where agents could come and go as they please, I added a campfire and a day-night cycle. I gave negative reward to agents for being out in the dark, which incentivizes them to gather around the campfire near others. Agents would only have enough time during the day to forage a single resource.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it turns out, agents really, &lt;em>really&lt;/em> don&amp;rsquo;t want to learn this behavior. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for agents to get cheated out of the resources they offer by others who offer nothing in return, so they gather as much as possible on their own. They even forage at night if the darkness penalty isn&amp;rsquo;t severe enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, after 4+ days of training time, agents start to realize that working together isn&amp;rsquo;t so bad and land on a trading protocol where agents stand back, drop an offer, then walk over to collect the resources dropped by others. Experiments show that agents keep their distance initially so they can reclaim their offer if their trading partner attempts to cheat them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one trial, agents converge on a local minimum, where agents 1&amp;amp;2 go to the same area to collect resource A, agent 3 goes to collect resource B, and agent 4 collects a bit of the other remaining resources. In this setting, we notice a behavior which we dub &amp;ldquo;Tolerated Theft&amp;rdquo;. When agent 1 collects significantly more of resource A than agent 2, agent 2 tries to steal the resources exchanged between agents 1 and 3. To defend against this, agent 1 will drop some resources away from agent 3, to get agent 2 off their backs while they trade. This is particularly interesting, because an agent manages to &amp;ldquo;steal&amp;rdquo; resources without us adding a combat or larceny system. Nature truly does find a way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend checking out the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.01862">arxiv pre-print&lt;/a> if you are interested in the details and figures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>List</title><link>/list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 13:17:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>/list/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://punk.ist">punk.ist&lt;/a> - A list of increasing importance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy">Unix&lt;/a> - The philosophy of modular programs&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hea-www.harvard.edu/~fine/Tech/vi.html">vi key bindings&lt;/a> - Comfortable computing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://alife.org/encyclopedia/introduction/artificial-life/">Artificial Life&lt;/a> - Life &lt;em>in silico&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://100r.co/site/home.html">100 Rabbits&lt;/a> - Low-tech maritime artist collective&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antifragility">Antifragility&lt;/a> - Strength from setbacks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6vwnon3sINoBBQf4xTSZbP938hdIpD5T">Lauryn Hill&amp;rsquo;s MTV Unplugged&lt;/a> - The unknown Queen of Hip-Hop&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yQs3HP9arts">George Watsky&amp;rsquo;s Live! From the Metro&lt;/a> - The concert which made me love live music&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://worrydream.com/">Bret Victor&lt;/a> - Redefining computing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://jvns.ca/">Julia Evans&lt;/a> - If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of her, you should&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://justine.lol/">Justine Tunney&lt;/a> - One hell of a programmer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://suckless.org/">suckless&lt;/a> - Simple, frugal, clear software&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/">LOW←TECH MAGAZINE&lt;/a> - Forgotten tech creating a sustainable future&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.clockworkpi.com/">Clockwork&lt;/a> - Beautiful handheld computing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://teenage.engineering/products">Teenage Engineering&lt;/a> - Stunning hardware design&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://tilde.town/">tilde.town&lt;/a> - Community on a linux server&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/">Arch Linux&lt;/a> - which I use, btw&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://unsongbook.com/">UNSONG&lt;/a> - United Nations Subcommittee On Names Of God&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_of_Zen">The Way of Zen&lt;/a> - Liberation on paper&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://secretofoursuccess.fas.harvard.edu/">Secrets of Our Success&lt;/a> - The beauty of cultural evolution&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_graffiti">Reverse Graffiti&lt;/a> - Art from removing scum&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Take the Road Most Documented</title><link>/blog/take-the-road-most-documented/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 02:52:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/take-the-road-most-documented/</guid><description>&lt;p>How great would it be if the solution to most errors you face were in the first place you looked? That&amp;rsquo;s what the &lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/">Arch Wiki&lt;/a> has been for me: a massive wealth of information and troubleshooting resources to help me navigate the various configuration and installation issues I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered. Some people claim Arch Linux is too difficult for new users, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s been the only distribution I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to get consistently working, and it&amp;rsquo;s all thanks to the detailed documentation and known workarounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used to run a Dell XPS 9560, and have tried and failed to install Ubuntu and Manjaro on multiple occassions. Sometimes, the automatic installers would fail, other times they would succeed but install a broken configuration, leaving me with networking configurations that would crash as much as it would connect&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. However, when installing Arch, I resolved each installation error with the help of the wiki, so that by the time I was in a graphical desktop environment, everything was running smoothly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got my next laptop, I looked on the arch wiki to make sure there would be as few issues as possible setting up Linux&amp;mdash;and I faced none when installing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love exciting, and popular, and &lt;em>new&lt;/em> software, but installing Arch showed me that &lt;em>popular&lt;/em> isn&amp;rsquo;t as important as &lt;em>understandable&lt;/em>. Software will always break; I don&amp;rsquo;t think there isn&amp;rsquo;t a single program I use daily whose configuration I haven&amp;rsquo;t broken at some point. But when I encounter an installation error, or a feature isn&amp;rsquo;t working, or I need to use a program for an unintended purpose, choosing programs with extensive documentation and active community resources has always saved me a headache.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use Hugo to generate this website. It&amp;rsquo;s so well documented (and there are bountiful answers on StackOverflow) that not only can I usually find the answer to the thing I want to do in the first few search results, but GPT-4 can often make a specific change I want too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With all else equal, take the road most documented.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>This was before 2020, I&amp;rsquo;m sure these issues are largely fixed by now&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>The Way of Zen</title><link>/blog/the-way-of-zen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 15:49:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/the-way-of-zen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Excerpts I found interesting from Alan Watt&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>The Way of Zen&lt;/em>, grouped by vibes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#definition">Definition&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#convention">Convention&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#feel">Feel&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#growing">Growing&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#spontaneity">Spontaneity&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#pointing">Pointing&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#ego">Ego&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#interference">Interference&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#present">Present&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#negation">Negation&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#liberation">Liberation&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#za-zen">Za-zen&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#widespread">Widespread&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#art">Art&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="definition" >Definition
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#definition">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zen Buddhism is a way and a view of life which does not belong to any of the formal categories of modern Western thought.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As will soon be obvious, a way of liberation can have no positive definition. It has to be suggested by saying what it is not, somewhat as a sculptor reveals an image by the act of removing pieces of stone from a block.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An obvious reason for the lack of materials would be that a principle of this kind, so easily open to misinterpretation, might have been kept as a “secret doctrine,” discussed openly only in later times.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zen points out that our precious “self” is just an idea, useful and legitimate enough if seen for what it is, but disastrous if identified with our real nature.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>According to the famous saying of Ch’ing-yüan: Before I had studied Zen for thirty years, I saw mountains as mountains, and waters as waters. When I arrived at a more intimate knowledge, I came to the point where I saw that mountains are not mountains, and waters are not waters. But now that I have got its very substance I am at rest. For it’s just that I see mountains once again as mountains, and waters once again as waters.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To remain caught up in ideas and words about Zen is, as the old masters say, to “stink of Zen.” For this reason the masters talk about Zen as little as possible, and throw its concrete reality straight at us.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Another master was having tea with two of his students when he suddenly tossed his fan to one of them, saying, “What’s this?” The student opened it and fanned himself. “Not bad,” was his comment. “Now you,” he went on, passing it to the other student, who at once closed the fan and scratched his neck with it. This done, he opened it again, placed a piece of cake on it, and offered it to the master. This was considered even better, for when there are no names the world is no longer “classified in limits and bounds.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="convention" >Convention
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#convention">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We have difficulty in communicating with each other unless we can identify ourselves in terms of roles–father, teacher, worker, artist, &amp;ldquo;regular guy,&amp;rdquo; gentleman, sportsman, and so forth.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>According to convention, I am not simply what I am doing now. I am also what I have done, and my conventionally edited version of my past is made to seem almost more the real &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; than what I am at this moment. For what I am seems so fleeting and intangible, but what I was is.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A philosophy restricted to the alternatives of conventional language has no way of conceiving an intelligence which does not work according to plan, according to a (one-at-atime) order of thought.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To serve their purpose, names and terms must of necessity be &amp;ldquo;fixed and definite like all other units of measurement. But their use is–up to a point–so satisfactory that man is always in danger of confusing his measures with the world so measured, of identifying money with wealth, fixed convention with fluid reality. But to the degree that he identifies himself and his life with these rigid and hollow frames of definition, he condemns himself to the perpetual frustration of one trying to catch water in a sieve.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Transitoriness is depressing only to the mind which insists upon trying to grasp.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We are so accustomed to this convention in speaking and thinking that we fail to recognize that it is simply a convention, and that it does not necessarily correspond to the actual experience of knowing. Thus when we say, “A light flashed,” it is somewhat easier to see through the grammatical convention and to realize that the flashing is the light.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The anxiety-laden problem of what will happen to me when I die is, after all, like asking what happens to my fist when I open my hand, or where my lap goes when I stand up.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The diffculty of making equations and comparisons between Eastern and Western ideas is that the two worlds do not start with the same assumptions and premises. They do not have the same basic categorizations of experience. When, therefore, the world has never been divided into mind and matter, but rather into mind and form, the word “mind” cannot mean quite the same thing in both instances. The word “man,” for example, does not have quite the same meaning when contrasted with “woman” as when contrasted with “animal.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="feel" >Feel
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#feel">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The general tendency of the Western mind is to feel that we do not really understand what we cannot represent, what we cannot communicate, by linear signs–by thinking. We are like the “wallflower” who cannot learn a dance unless someone draws him a diagram of the steps, who cannot &amp;ldquo;get it by the feel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We learn music, for example, by restricting the whole range of tone and rhythm to a notation of fixed tonal and rhythmic intervals-a notation which is incapable of representing Oriental music. But the Oriental musician has a rough notation which he uses only as a reminder of a melody. He learns music, not by reading notes, but by listening to the performance of a teacher, getting the “feel” of it, and copying him, and this enables him to acquire rhythmic and tonal sophistications matched only by those Western jazz artists who use the same approach.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>By far the greater part of our important decisions depend upon “hunch”- in other words, upon the “peripheral vision” of the mind. Thus the reliability of our decisions rests ultimately upon our ability to “feel” the situation, upon the degree to which this “peripheral vision” has been developed. Every exponent of the I Ching knows this. He knows that the book itself does not contain an exact science, but rather a useful tool which will work for him if he has a good “intuition,” or if, as he would say, he is “in the Tao.” Thus one does not consult the&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="growing" >Growing
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#growing">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Whereas God produces the worldby maklng (wei), the Tao produces it by “not makmg” (wu wei) which is approximately what we mean by &amp;ldquo;growing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If the universe were made, there would of course be someone who knows how it is made-who could explain how it was put together bit by bit as a technician can explain in one-at-a-time words how to assemble a machine.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But the genuine &amp;ldquo;Zen flavor&amp;rdquo; is when a man is almost miraculously natural without intending to be so. His Zen life is not to make himself but to grow that way.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the course of time it may grow, but one does not blame an egg for not being a chicken; still less does one criticize a pig for having a shorter neck than a giraffe.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But he watches as a gardener watches the growth of a tree, and wants his student to have the attitude of the tree–the attitude of purposeless growth in which there are no short cuts because every stage of the way is both beginning and end.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Rinzai School has always forbidden the publication of formally acceptable answers to the various koan because the whole point of the discipline is to discover them for oneself, by intuition. To know the answers without having so discovered them would be like studying the map without taking the journey.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Chinese proverb “What comes in through the gate is not family treasure” is understood in Zen to mean that what someone else tells you is not your own knowledge.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="spontaneity" >Spontaneity
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#spontaneity">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We saw that the I Ching had given the Chinese mind some experience in arriving at decisions spontaneously, decisions which are effective to the degree that one knows how to let one’s mind alone, trusting it to work by itself. This is wu-wei, since wu means “not” or “non-” and wei means “action,” “making,” “doing,” “striving,” “straining,” or “busyness.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;No amount of working with the muscles of the mouth and tongue will enable us to taste our food more acutely. The eyes and the tongue must be trusted to do the work by themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Become unaffected;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cherish sincerity;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Belittle the personal;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reduce desires.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ Lao Tzu&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The idea is not to reduce the human mind to a moronic vacuity, but to bring into play its innate and spontaneous intelligence by using it without forcing it. It is fundamental to both Taoist and Confucian thought that the natural man is to be trusted, and from their standpoint it appears that the Western mistrust of human nature–whether theological or technological–is a kind of schizophrenia.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When a man has learned to let his mind alone so that it functions in the integrated and spontaneous way that is natural to it, he begins to show the special kind of “virtue” or “power” called te. This is not virtue in the current sense of moral rectitude but in the older sense of effectiveness, as when one speaks of the healing virtues of a plant[&amp;hellip;] Te is the unthinkable ingenuity and creative power of man’s spontaneous and natural functioning–a power which is blocked when one tries to master it in terms of formal methods and techniques.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nirvana can only arise unintentionally, spontaneously, when the impossibility of selfgrasping has been thoroughly perceived.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The doctrine of the Dharmadhatu is, approximately, that the proper harmony of the universe is realized when each “thing-event” is allowed to be freely and spontaneously itself, without interference. Stated more subjectively, it is saying, “Let everything be free to be just as it is. Do not separate yourself from the world and try to order it around.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Six Precepts&amp;rdquo; of Tilopa: No thought, no reflection, no analysis, No cultivation, no intention; Let it settle itself.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>–that truly to know is not to know, that the awakened mind responds immediately, without calculation, and that there is no incompatibility between Buddhahood and the everyday life of the world.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He was the first to answer questions about Buddhism by hitting the questioner.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We feel that our actions are voluntary when they follow a decision, and involuntary when they happen without decision. But if decision itself were voluntary, every decision would have to be preceded by a decision to decide–an infinite regression which fortunately does not occur. Oddly enough, if we had to decide to decide, we would not be free to decide. We are free to decide because decision “happens.” We just decide without having the faintest understanding of how we do it. In fact, it is neither voluntary nor involuntary.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The master may begin a conversation with the student by asking a series of very ordinary questions about trivial matters, to which the student responds with perfect spontaneity. But suddenly he will say, “When the bath-water flows down the drain, does it turn clockwise or counter-clockwise?” As the student stops at the unexpectedness of the question, and perhaps tries to remember which way it goes, the master shouts, “Don’t think! Act! This way–” and whirls his hand in the air. Or, perhaps less helpfully, he may say, “So far you’ve answered my questions quite naturally and easily, but where’s your difficulty now?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The point of mo chih ch’u is not to eliminate reflective thought but to eliminate “blocking” in both action and thought, so that the response of the mind is always like a ball in a mountain stream-“one thought after another without hesitation.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yet this is why the Western mind is dismayed when ordered conceptions of the universe break down, and when the basic behavior of the physical world is found to be a “principle of uncertainty.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The same is true in learning to use the brush for writing or painting. The brush must draw by itself. This cannot happen if one does not practice constantly. But neither can it happen if one makes an effort. Similarly, in swordsmanship one must not first decide upon a certain thrust and then attempt to make it, since by that time it will be too late. Decision and action must be simultaneous.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To use the imagery of a Tibetan poem, every action, every event comes of itself from the Void “as from the surface of a clear lake there leaps suddenly a fish.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="pointing" >Pointing
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#pointing">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Thus from the standpoint of Zen the Buddha “never said a word,” despite the volumes of scriptures attributed to him. For his real message remained always unspoken, and was such that, when words attempted to express it, they made it seem as if it were nothing at all.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yet it is the essential tradition of Zen that what cannot be conveyed by speech can nevertheless be passed on by “direct pointing,” by some nonverbal means of communication without which the Buddhist experience could never have been handed down to future generations.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In its own (probably rather late) tradition, Zen maintains that the Buddha transmitted awakening to his chief disciple, Mahakasyapa, by holding up a flower and remaining silent.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The basic position of Zen is that it has nothing to say, nothing to teach. The truth of Buddhism is so self-evident, so obvious that it is, if anything, concealed by explaining it. Therefore the master does not “help” the student in any way, since helping would actually be hindering. On the contrary, he goes out of his way to put obstacles and barriers in the student’s path.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="ego" >Ego
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#ego">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is fundamental to every school of Buddhism that there is no ego, no enduring entity which is the constant subject of our changing experiences.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We can, for example, imagine the path of a bird through the sky as a distinct line which it has taken. But this line is as abstract as a line of latitude. In concrete reality, the bird left no line, and, similarly, the past from which our ego is abstracted has entirely disappeared. Thus any attempt to cling to the ego or to make it an effective source of action is doomed to frustration&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Here, too, lies the basis of the Buddhism of faith, of the Sukhavati or Pure Land school, in which it is held that all efforts to become a Buddha are merely the false pride of the ego.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There is often a deceptive resemblance between opposite extremes. Lunatics frequently resemble saints, and the unaffected modesty of the sage often lets him seem to be a very ordinary person.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is why the sage Fa-yung received no more offerings of flowers from the birds after he had had his interview with the Fourth Patriarch, for his holiness no longer “stood out like a sore thumb.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No one notices him because he does not notice himself.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So often one thinks of the saint as a man whose sincerity provokes the enmity of the world, but Ryokan holds the distinction of being the saint whom everyone loved–perhaps because he was natural, again as a child, rather than good.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="interference" >Interference
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#interference">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This, however, cannot quite be compressed into the sweeping assertion that “life is suffering.” The point is rather that life as we usually live it is suffering-or, more exactly, is bedeviled by the peculiar frustration which comes from attempting the impossible.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Man is involved in karma when he interferes with the world in such a way that he is compelled to go on interfering, when the solution of a problem creates still more problems to be solved, when the control of one thing creates the need to control several others. Karma is thus the fate of everyone who “tries to be God.” He lays a trap for the world in which he himself gets caught.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This nonduality of the mind, in which it is no longer divided against itself, is samadhi, and because of the disappearance of that fruitless threshing around of the mind to grasp itself, samadhi is a state of profound peace.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>However, not exterminating the passions does not mean letting them flourish untamed. It means letting go of them rather than fighting them, neither repressing passion nor indulging it. For the Taoist is never violent, since he achieves his ends by noninterference (wu-wei), which is a kind of psychological judo.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To concentrate on the mind and to contemplate it until it is still is a disease and not dhyana.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the principle that “the true mind is no-mind,” and that “our true nature is no (special) nature,” it is likewise stressed that the true practice of Zen is no practice, that is, the seeming paradox of being a Buddha without intending to be a Buddha.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There is no place in Buddhism for using effort. Just be ordinary and nothing special.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Whereas the koan advocates used this technique as a means for encouraging that overwhelming “feeling of doubt” which they felt to be essential as a prerequisite for satori, the Soto School argued that it lent itself too easily to that very seeking for satori which thrusts it away, or–what is worse–induces an artificial satori.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The temptation is all the stronger because it upsets the fondest illusion of the human mind, which is that in the course of time everything may be made better and better. For it is the general opinion that were this not possible the life of man would lack all meaning and incentive. The only alternative to a life of constant progress is felt to be a mere existence, static and dead, so joyless and inane that one might as well commit suicide. The very notion of this “only alternative” shows how firmly the mind is bound in a dualistic pattern, how hard it is to think in any other terms than good or bad, or a muddy mixture of the two.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To succeed is always to fail–in the sense that the more one succeeds in anything, the greater is the need to go on succeeding. To eat is to survive to be hungry.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Consequently the whole notion of getting something “out” of life, of seeking something “from” experience, becomes absurd.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In short, Zen begins at the point where there is nothing further to seek, nothing to be gained. Zen is most emphatically not to be regarded as a system of self-improvement, or a way of becoming a Buddha&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Furthermore, the effort to remain always “good” or “happy” is like trying to hold the thermostat to a constant 70 degrees by making the lower limit the same as the upper.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To the Taoist mentality, the aimless, empty life does not suggest anything depressing. On the contrary, it suggests the freedom of clouds and mountain streams, wandering nowhere, of flowers in impenetrable canyons, beautiful for no one to see, and of the ocean surf forever washing the sand, to no end.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yet the superficiality of this consciousness is seen in the fact that it cannot and does not regulate even the human organism. For if it had to control the heartbeat, the breath, the operation of the nerves, glands, muscles, and sense organs, it would be rushing wildly around the body taking care of one thing after another, with no time to do anything else. Happily, it is not in charge, and the organism is regulated by the timeless “original mind,” which deals with life in its totality and so can do ever so many “things” at once.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Clear sight has nothing to do with trying to see; it is just the realization that the eyes will take in every detail all by themselves, for so long as they are open one can hardly prevent the light from reaching them. In the same way, there is no di8culty in being fully aware of the eternal present as soon as it is seen that one cannot possibly be aware of anything else–that in concrete fact there is no past or future.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="present" >Present
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#present">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the one hand, it is one-pointed in the sense of being focused on the present, since to clear awareness there is neither past nor future, but just this one moment.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the same way Dogen pointed out that firewood does not become ashes and life does not become death, just as the winter does not become the spring. Every moment of time is “self-contained and quiescent.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To Po-chang is attributed the famous definition of Zen, “When hungry, eat; when tired, sleep.” For when asked about seeking for the Buddha nature he answered, “It’s much like riding an ox in search of the ox.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dogen is here trying to express the strange sense of timeless moments which arises when one is no longer trying to resist the flow of events, the peculiar stillness and self-sufficiency of the succeeding instants when the mind is, as it were, going along with them and not trying to arrest them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A Zen poem says:
The morning glory which blooms for an hour
Differs not at heart from the giant pine,
Which lives for a thousand years.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the contrary, the measuring of worth and success in terms of time, and the insistent demand for assurances of a promising future, make it impossible to live freely both in the present and in the “promising” future when it arrives. For there is never anything but the present, and if one cannot live there, one cannot live anywhere.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is not a philosophy of not looking where one is going; it is a philosophy of not making where one is going so much more important than where one is that there will be no point in going.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The story is told of a Zen monk who wept upon hearing of the death of a close relative. When one of his fellow students objected that it was most unseemly for a monk to show such personal attachment he replied, “Don’t be stupid! I’m weeping because I want to weep.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The silence which prevails is deepened rather than broken by occasional sounds that float up from a near-by village, by the intermittent ringing of soft-toned bells from other parts of the monastery, and by the chatter of birds in the trees.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zen masters are quite human. They get sick and die; they know joy and sorrow; they have bad tempers or other little “weaknesses” of character just like anyone else, and they are not above falling in love and entering into a fully human relationship with the opposite sex. The perfection of Zen is to be perfectly and simply human. The difference of the adept in Zen from the ordinary run of men is that the latter are, in one way or another, at odds with their own humanity, and are attempting to be angels or demons.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It hurries on and on, and misses everything. Not hurrying, the purposeless life misses nothing, for it is only when there is no goal and no rush that the human senses are fully open to receive the world.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Aware is not quite grief, and not quite nostalgia in the usual sense of longing for the return of a beloved past. Aware is the echo of what has passed and of what was loved, giving them a resonance such as a great cathedral gives to a choir, so that they would be the poorer without it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zen has no goal; it is a traveling without point, with nowhere to go. To travel is to be alive, but to get somewhere is to be dead, for as our own proverb says, “To travel well is better than to arrive.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A world which increasingly consists of destinations without journeys between them, a world which values only “getting somewhere” as fast as possible, becomes a world without substance. One can get anywhere and everywhere, and yet the more this is possible, the less is anywhere and everywhere worth getting to.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For if we open our eyes and see clearly, it becomes obvious that there is no other time than this instant, and that the past and the future are abstractions without any concrete reality. Until this has become clear, it seems that our life is all past and future, and that the present is nothing more than the in-nitesimal hairline which divides them. From this comes the sensation of “having no time,” of a world which hurries by so rapidly that it is gone before we can enjoy it. But through “awakening to the instant” one sees that this is the reverse of the truth: it is rather the past and future which are the ,eeting illusions, and the present which is eternally real.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Both Takuan and Bankei stressed the fact that the “original” or “unborn” mind is constantly working miracles even in the most ordinary person. Even though a tree has innumerable leaves, the mind takes them in all at once without being “stopped” by any one of them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He had surpassed all the other disciples and Bodhisattvas by answering a question as to the nature of the nondual reality with a “thunderous silence”–an example frequently followed by Zen masters.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="negation" >Negation
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#negation">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Even at the conventional level it is surely easy to see that knowing what is not so is often quite as important as knowing what is [&amp;hellip;] Furthermore, the function of negative knowledge is not unlike the uses of space–the empty page upon which words can be written, the empty jar into which liquid can be poured, the empty window through which light can be admitted, and the empty pipe through which water can flow.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indeed, when Hindu and Buddhist texts speak of the “empty” or “illusory” character of the visible world of nature–as distinct from the conventional world of things–they refer precisely to the impermanence of its forms.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Thus the greater part of Nagarjuna’s work was a carefully logical and systematic refutation of every philosophical position to be found in the India of his time.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It must therefore be repeated that the negations apply, not to reality itself, but to our ideas of reality.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Awakening is to know what reality is not. It is to cease identifying oneself with any object of knowledge whatsoever.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="liberation" >Liberation
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#liberation">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But Taoism must on no account be understood as a revolution
against convention, although it has sometimes been used as a
pretext for revolution. Taoism is a way of liberation, which never
comes by means of revolution, since it is notorious that most
revolutions establish worse tyrannies than they destroy.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Fourth Patriarch, following Seng-ts’an, is believed to have been Tao-hsin. When he came to Seng-ts’an he asked, “What is the method of liberation?” “Who binds you?” replied Seng-ts’an. “No one binds me.” “Why then,” asked Seng-ts’an, “should you seek liberation?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>True dhyana is to realize that one’s own nature is like space, and that thoughts and sensations come and go in this “original mind” like birds through the sky, leaving no trace. Awakening, in his school, is “sudden” because it is for quickwitted rather than slow-witted people. The latter must of necessity understand gradually, or more exactly, after a long time, since the Sixth Patriarch’s doctrine does not admit of stages or growth. To be awakened at all is to be awakened completely, for, having no parts or divisions, the Buddha nature is not realized bit by bit.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="za-zen" >Za-zen
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#za-zen">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The following story is told of Huai-jang, initiating into Zen his great successor Ma-tsu, who was at the time practicing sitting meditation at the monastery of Ch’uan-fa. “Your reverence,” asked Huai-jang, “what is the objective of sitting in meditation?” “The objective,” answered Ma-tsu, “is to become a Buddha.” Thereupon Huai-jang picked up a floor-tile and began to polish it on a rock. “What are you doing, master?” asked Ma-tsu. “I am polishing it for a mirror,” said Huai-jang. “How could polishing a tile make a mirror?” “How could sitting in meditation make a Buddha?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>it could be assumed that the type of za-zen under criticism is za-zen practiced for a purpose, to “get” Buddhahood, instead of “sitting just to sit.” There is, of course, a proper place for sitting–along with standing, walking, and lying–but to imagine that sitting contains some special virtue is “attachment to form.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yet however much za-zen may have been exaggerated in the Far East, a certain amount of “sitting just to sit” might well be the best thing in the world for the jittery minds and agitated bodies of Europeans and Americans–provided they do not use it as a method for turning themselves into Buddhas&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Although the West has its own contemplative tradition in the Catholic Church, the life of “sitting and looking” has lost its appeal, for no religion is valued which does not “improve the world,” and it is hard to see how the world can be improved by keeping still. Yet it should be obvious that action without wisdom, without clear awareness of the world as it really is, can never improve anything. Furthermore, as muddy water is best cleared by leaving it alone, it could be argued that those who sit quietly and do nothing are making one of the best possible contributions to a world in turmoil. There is, indeed, nothing unnatural in long periods of quiet sitting. Cats do it; even dogs and other more nervous animals do it. So-called primitive peoples do it–American Indians, and peasants of almost all nations. The art is most diffcult for those who have developed the sensitive intellect to such a point that they cannot help making predictions about the future, and so must be kept in a constant whirl of activity to forestall them. But it would seem that to be incapable of sitting and watching with the mind completely at rest is to be incapable of experiencing the world in which we live to the full&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But just as there is no need to try to be in accord with the Tao, to try to see, or to try to hear, so it must be remembered that the breath will always take care of itself. This is not a breathing “exercise” so much as a “watching and letting” of the breath, and it is always a serious mistake to undertake it in the spirit of a compulsive discipline to be “practiced” with a goal in mind.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>every human activity can become a form of za-zen&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The late Dr. Kunihiko Hashida, a lifelong student of Zen and editor of the works of Dogen, never used formal za-zen. But his “Zen practice” was precisely his study of physics, and to suggest his attitude he used to say that his lifework was “to science” rather than “to study science.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="widespread" >Widespread
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#widespread">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Confucianism, in other words, preoccupies itself with conventional
knowledge, and under its auspices children are brought up so that
their originally wayward and whimsical natures are made to fit the
Procrustean bed of the social order. The individual defines himself
and his place in society in terms of the Confucian formulae.
Taoism, on the other hand, is generally a pursuit of older men,
and especially of men who are retiring from active life in the
community. Their retirement from society is a kind of outward
symbol of an inward liberation from the bounds of conventional
patterns of thought and conduct. For Taoism concerns itself with
unconventional knowledge. with the understanding of life directly.
&amp;hellip;Confucianism presides, then, over the socially necessary task of
forcing the original spontaneity of life into the rigid rules of
convention-a task which involves not only conflict and pain, but
also the loss of that peculiar naturalness and un-self-consciousness
for which little children are so much loved, and which is sometimes
regained by saints and sages. The function of Taoism is to undo the
inevitable damage of this discipline, and not only to restore but also
to develop the original spontaneity, which is termed tzu-jan or
“self-so-ness.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Popularity almost invariably leads to a deterioration of quality, and as Zen became less of an informal spiritual movement and more of a settled institution, it underwent a curious change of character. It became necessary to “standardize” its methods and to find means for the masters to handle students in large numbers&amp;hellip;For the Zen community became less an association of mature men with spiritual interests, and more of an ecclesiastical boarding school for adolescent boys. Under such circumstances the problem of discipline became paramount. The Zen masters were forced to concern themselves not only with the way of liberation from convention, but also with the instilling of convention, of ordinary manners and morals, in raw youths. The mature Western student who discovers an interest in Zen as a philosophy or as a way of liberation must be careful to keep this in mind, for otherwise he may be unpleasantly startled by monastic Zen as it exists today in Japan. He will find that Zen is a discipline enforced with the big stick. He will find that, although it is still an effective way of liberation at its “upper end,” its main preoccupation is with a disciplinary regimen which “trains character” in the same way as the old-fashioned British public school or the Jesuit novitiate.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For one of the main objects of this work was to establish a proper “apostolic succession” for the Zen tradition, so that no one could claim authority unless his satori had been approved by someone who had been approved &amp;hellip; right back to the time of the Buddha himself&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nothing, however, is more difficult than establishing proper qualifications in the imponderable realm of spiritual insight. Where the candidates are few the problem is not so grave, but where one master is responsible for some hundreds of students the process of teaching and testing requires standardization. Zen solved this problem with remarkable ingenuity, employing a means which not only provided a test of competence but–what was much more–a means of transmitting the Zen experience itself with a minimum of falsification. This extraordinary invention was the system of the kung-an ee (Japanese, koan) or “Zen problem.” Literally, this term means a “public document” or “case” in the sense of a decision creating a legal precedent. Thus the koan system involves “passing” a series of tests based on the mondo or anecdotes of the old masters.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="art" >Art
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#art">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Even in painting, the work of art is considered not only as representing nature but as being itself a work of nature&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When you paint it is the brush, ink, and paper which determine the result as much as your own hand.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Since writing and poetry were among the chief preoccupations of Chinese scholars, and since the Chinese way of painting is closely akin to writing, the roles of scholar, artist, and poet were not widely separated&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Since the touch of the brush is so light and fluid, and since it must move continuously over the absorbent paper if the ink is to flow out regularly, its control requires a free movement of the hand and arm as if one were dancing rather than writing on paper. In short, it is a perfect instrument for the expression of unhesitating spontaneity, and a single stroke is enough to “give away” one’s character to an experienced observer.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One of the most striking features of the Sung landscape, as of sumi-e as a whole, is the relative emptiness of the picture–an emptiness which appears, however, to be part of the painting and not just unpainted background. By filling in just one corner, the artist makes the whole area of the picture alive. Ma-yüan, in particular, was a master of this technique, which amounts almost to “painting by not painting,” or what Zen sometimes calls “playing the string-less lute.” The secret lies in knowing how to balance form with emptiness and, above all, in knowing when one has “said” enough. For Zen spoils neither the aesthetic shock nor the satori shock by filling in, by explanation, second thoughts, and intellectual commentary.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Western eye is immediately struck by the absence of symmetry in these paintings, by the consistent avoidance of regular and geometrical shapes, whether straight or curved. For the characteristic brush line is jagged, gnarled, irregularly twisting, dashing, or sweeping–always spontaneous rather than predictable. Even when the Zen monk or artist draws a solitary circle-one of the most common themes of zenga–it is not only slightly eccentric and out of shape, but the very texture of the line is full of life and verve with the incidental splashes and gaps of the “rough brush.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But the non-Japanese listener must remember that a good haiku is a pebble thrown into the pool of the listener’s mind, evoking associations out of the richness of his own memory. It invites the listener to participate instead of leaving him dumb with admiration while the poet shows off&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Even when robbed he is still rich, for:
The thief
Left it behind
The moon at the window.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They were always sparing and reserved in their use of color, as were the Sung painters before them, since masses of flowers in sharply varying colors are seldom found in the state of nature.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Herrigel spent almost five years trying to find the right way of releasing the bowstring, for it had to be done “unintentionally,” in the same way as a ripe fruit bursts its skin&amp;hellip; After all those years of practice there came a day when it just happened–how, or why, Herrigel never understood.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The artificial haiku always feels like a piece of life which has been deliberately broken off or wrenched away from the universe, whereas the genuine haiku has dropped off all by itself, and has the whole universe inside it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The point, therefore, of these arts is the doing of them rather than the accomplishments. But, more than this, the real joy of them lies in what turns up unintentionally in the course of practice, just as the joy of travel is not nearly so much in getting where one wants to go as in the unsought surprises which occur on the journey.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Numerical Stability in Flash Attention</title><link>/blog/numerical-stability-in-flash-attention/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:21:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/numerical-stability-in-flash-attention/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2023-01-12-flashattention-long-sequences">Flash attention&lt;/a>, a recent implementation of attention which makes less calls
to high-bandwidth memory, uses a version of the softmax function which is numerically stable. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly showcase how this is done and an example of an unstable softmax.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The softmax function is used in machine learning to convert a vector of
real numbers to a vector of probabilities which sum to 1, and is defined as:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>softmax(x) = [exp(x[i]) / sum([exp(xj) for xj in x]) for xi in x]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>where x is a vector of real numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The python implementation below is numerically unstable because it involves
exponentiation of large numbers, which can lead to overflow. Crucially,
underflow is not an issue, because exp(x) approaches zero when x is a large
negative number.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#fff;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">import&lt;/span> numpy &lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">as&lt;/span> np
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">def&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#feacd0">unstable_softmax&lt;/span>(x):
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> fx_unstable &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>exp(x)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">return&lt;/span> fx_unstable &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">/&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>sum(fx_unstable)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The following implementation is stable however, because there is no
exponentiation of large numbers:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#fff;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">def&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#feacd0">stable_softmax&lt;/span>(x):
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> fx_stable &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span> x &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">-&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>max(x)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#b6a0ff">return&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>exp(fx_stable) &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">/&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>sum(np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>exp(fx_stable))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Instead, the max of the vector is subtracted from each element. This does not
change the result of the softmax after the division as this subtraction is also
performed in the denominator, thus cancelling out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s compare the two implementations:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#fff;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> a &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>array([&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">6.0&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">3&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">15&lt;/span>], dtype&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span>np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>float32)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> stable_softmax(a)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.2339458e-04&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.5228101e-08&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">9.9987662e-01&lt;/span>]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> unstable_softmax(a)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.2339458e-04&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.5228101e-08&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">9.9987656e-01&lt;/span>]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>As you can see, the results are mostly equal, save for a few digits.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at what happens with 16 bits of precision:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#fff;background-color:#000;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> a &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span> np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>array([&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">6.0&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#00bcff">3&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">15&lt;/span>], dtype&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">=&lt;/span>np&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">.&lt;/span>float16)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> unstable_softmax(a)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[ &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">0.&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">0.&lt;/span> nan]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#00d3d0">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> stable_softmax(a)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[ &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.234e-04&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">0.000e+00&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#00bcff">1.000e+00&lt;/span>]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>When working with 16 bits of precision, we observe that exp(15) produces a numerical overflow
which turns the third element into a NaN. This is because exp(15) produces a value that can
not be represented by a float16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To recap, we showed that softmax is numerically unstable, especially when working with small precision bits. Because softmax uses exponentials in the numerator and denominator, we can subtract all exponents by the maximum exponent, constraining all the values between 0 and 1 and preventing numerical overflow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Kittyplot</title><link>/blog/introducing-kittyplot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 21:09:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/introducing-kittyplot/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/jarbus/kittyplot">Kittyplot&lt;/a> is a program designed to plot experiment data in the kitty terminal using the &lt;a href="https://sw.kovidgoyal.net/kitty/graphics-protocol/">kitty graphics protocol&lt;/a>, primarily for use on HPC clusters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./kittyplot-ex.gif" alt="Kittyplot example GIF" loading="lazy">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plots are rendered using matplotlib, and users can zoom into different regions of the plots by setting x and y limits using their editor. I use &lt;a href="https://python-prompt-toolkit.readthedocs.io/en/master/index.html">prompt_toolkit&lt;/a> to accept regexp input and I override the tab-completion to instead display a list of all metrics that are matched by the current regexp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will not be a well-maintained repo for the forseeable future and not a simple library one can &lt;code>pip install&lt;/code>. It&amp;rsquo;s merely a public copy of the script I use for visualizing experiment data over SSH without port-forwarding or running a web browser on my local machine. Kittyplot is only a few hunderd lines and is designed to be directly modified for user needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was initially inspired to make kittyplot when I got fed up with tensorboard taking 20+ minutes to load all the experiment data I was working with. I loved tensorboard solely for the purpose of monitoring metrics specified by a regexp, so I modified my experiments to stream all the metrics to a csv and wrote kittyplot to monitor them. Now, I can create, view, and save plots directly from my ssh connection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Owen, Make Your Website Already</title><link>/blog/please-make-your-website-owen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 11:47:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/please-make-your-website-owen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Make a fucking website already, Owen. You&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with the idea of making a blog for like two years, but you&amp;rsquo;ve been dragging your feet. Maybe you can&amp;rsquo;t decide what framework to use, or where to host it, or blah blah blah. If you want excuses not to make a site, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll find them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it literally just takes a few hours, less if you don&amp;rsquo;t set up a domain name or theme to start. You can do all that later. The important thing is getting it online, the rest is easy (and satisfying!) once you have the core site made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">HUGO&lt;/a> to start and change frameworks later, since all your content will be in markdown. You can host on &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub pages&lt;/a> to start, and always change later, since again, it takes no time to set up and there&amp;rsquo;s no lock-in from what I can tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can understand not wanting to deal with all the technical stuff like domain names or self-hosting or choosing a VPS or making it look pretty. But come on man, at least get started. The rest is so much easier to do once you are up and running.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unexpected Benefits of Testing Code</title><link>/blog/unexpected-benefits-of-testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 18:38:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/unexpected-benefits-of-testing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Matthew Carlson&amp;rsquo;s blog post &lt;a href="https://matthewc.dev/musings/unit-tests/">&amp;ldquo;Fighting Distraction With Unit Tests&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> inspired me to share some extra benefits of writing test code I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered during my PhD program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a &lt;a href="https://github.com/jarbus/evotrade">weird project&lt;/a> that&amp;rsquo;s constantly changing as I try new things, and naturally, debugging and ensuring correctness was a nightmare. So I started writing tests, cursing myself for needing to write so much code I&amp;rsquo;ll likely throw away soon. But as it turns out, testing can be pretty helpful in a few other ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>When I encounter a bug I didn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate, I already have most of the code needed to reproduce it in a deterministic manner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When I want to add/change functionality, I already have most of the code needed ensure that my changes work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When writing new functionality, if I don&amp;rsquo;t already have the code needed to make ensure it&amp;rsquo;s working, I can write a small test that &lt;a href="https://timholy.github.io/Revise.jl/stable/user_reference/#Revise.entr">runs whenever my code changes&lt;/a>. Making this test case auto-run on a second screen dramatically reduces the amount of time spent switching windows and lets me stay in my editor until the test passes. I highly recommend setting up a run-on-change system, it makes writing tests or designing plots pretty fun.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can write tests for newer code by using tests for older code. This makes tests valuable as you develop, even if you plan to throw them out later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I feel more confident about what my code is actually doing. As someone who is working in AI, the value of this is immense, as AI code can run without crashing but still be subtly incorrect.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not writing an exhaustive test suite, or tests for edge-cases that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen (asserts can deal with those). I&amp;rsquo;m writing code before I get bugs to spare myself the extra effort when I need to debug or make changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Dont Know Anyone Who Blogs</title><link>/blog/i-dont-know-anyone-who-blogs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/i-dont-know-anyone-who-blogs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know anybody in real life who blogs regularly, and I think that
kills my motivation to write blog posts myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I actually started writing this post before realizing that a friend of mine &lt;a href="https://jonnesaleva.com/blog">has
a blog&lt;/a>, but in my defense he&amp;rsquo;s only posted twice in the past 2
years. I suppose that makes my title a lie, but I like the title, and the point
still stands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to build a writing habit, but it feels hard to get the motivation to do
it from within myself. I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot from
people online, the people who&amp;rsquo;ve made the biggest impact on me are
people I&amp;rsquo;ve met in the physical world. Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by other
programmers; maybe that makes me feel less crazy spending all my time coding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I mention
my blog to people, or send my friends my latest post, I always feel a sense of
shame. Like I&amp;rsquo;m trying too hard. Maybe I am. I&amp;rsquo;m talking to nobody
and have little-to-no audience, so in a sense, I&amp;rsquo;d have to be crazy
to make a habit out of this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m just not surrounded by people who make me feel less crazy. I imagine
that if I was making digital music but everyone around me was some mainstream profession
like an accountant or baker, I&amp;rsquo;d probably feel embarrassed too, even though
there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to be embarrassed about. But, if I was surrounded by people who also made music, I&amp;rsquo;d feel normal. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the feeling of
&amp;ldquo;trying hard to do something that nobody else cares enough to do&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot about the benefits of blogging; Writing helps
flesh out ideas, improves communication, puts down what you are thinking
about to reference later, helps connect you to other people, gets you into your dream job, cures you of cancer, prevents global warming, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nl0wIJU22dw">saves the bees&lt;/a>. But somehow, the bees aren&amp;rsquo;t enough motivation to write.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In all the blog posts talking about why you should blog, nobody mentions this feeling of being &amp;ldquo;the guy with the blog&amp;rdquo;. I imagine other people feel this way, which is why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, I suppose. Hopefully I make writing a habit in 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to write LaTeX without writing LaTeX</title><link>/blog/write-latex-without-latex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 14:28:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/write-latex-without-latex/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love the look of LaTeX but hate the experience of writing in LaTeX, at least compared to Markdown. Luckily, &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/MANUAL.html#pandocs-Markdown">Pandoc can convert Markdown files to PDFs using a LaTeX engine as the renderer&lt;/a>, and includes a custom Markdown specification that can fill almost all my LaTeX needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about where Pandoc Markdown falls short:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No custom LaTeX style guides (although citation style files are supported)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>No Section Numbering&lt;/del> There is, thanks to naruhodo on Hacker News for the correction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Referencing labels doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well (Supposedly the pandoc-crossref filter fixes this but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t even bother with complex page layouts or precise figure placements&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This might be a deal breaker for some, but for others who are writing lots of documents (such as students), this may not be. Now for the benefits:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Produce a document with Markdown that looks like it was written in LaTeX&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use LaTeX math notation in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy BibTeX citations in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Figures and Captions are supported&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Two Columns are supported&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use your favorite editor instead of some LaTeX IDE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write and preview offline&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build a document in one command&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are reading this, you probably know how both Markdown and Latex work, and you probably know how to read the &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/MANUAL.html#pandocs-Markdown">Pandoc Markdown Documentation&lt;/a>, so instead, below is a template document that I wish I had when first starting out. It covers most things you&amp;rsquo;d need to write simple papers in Markdown. Configuration for document settings is done in the YAML block at the top of the document.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>---
title: How to Succeed in LaTeX without even trying
subtitle: For the lazy writer
author:
- jarbus.net
numbersections: true
toc: true
geometry:
- margin=1in
linkcolor: black
urlcolor: blue
bibliography: example.bib
csl: nature.csl
header-includes: |
\usepackage{package_here}
classoption:
- twocolumn
abstract: |
This is the abstract
---
# Introduction
According to all known laws
of aviation, there is now way
that a bee should be able to fly. [@seinfeld2007]
| &amp;#34;This is a quote&amp;#34;
![Caption here](bee.png){width=50% }
$\forall b , y = mx+b$
$$
a^2 + b^2 = c^2
$$
# References
::: {#refs}
:::
# Appendix
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Then, to compile your document to a PDF, simply run:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>pandoc &amp;#34;file.md&amp;#34; -o &amp;#34;file.pdf&amp;#34; --citeproc
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>to generate a document that looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./final-document.png" alt="" loading="lazy">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>--citeproc&lt;/code> option is needed for compiling a bibliography. For cross-references inside a document, take a look at &lt;a href="https://github.com/lierdakil/pandoc-crossref">pandoc-crossref&lt;/a>, which will require the use of &lt;code>--filter pandoc-crossref&lt;/code> if it works for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mapped a modified version of the build command above to a key in Neovim, so now pressing &lt;code>Space+b&lt;/code> in my Markdown buffer compiles my document automatically, no matter what file name I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>autocmd BufRead,BufNewFile *.md nnoremap &amp;lt;Leader&amp;gt;b
\ :silent pandoc % -o &amp;#34;%:p:h/%:t:r.pdf&amp;#34;
\ --filter pandoc-crossref --citeproc &amp;amp;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s how I write LaTeX documents offline in Markdown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI Index</title><link>/blog/ai-index/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/ai-index/</guid><description>&lt;p>An ever-expanding list of concepts in the field of AI to give myself and others an easy reference.
Each item in the list contains a short, rudimentary definition I&amp;rsquo;ve written, as well as a link to a resource that can explain it better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/380040/what-is-an-ablation-study-and-is-there-a-systematic-way-to-perform-it">Ablation Study&lt;/a>:
Removing some parts of a machine learning model to measure impact on performance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mc.ai/advantage-function-in-deep-reinforcement-learning/">Advantage Function&lt;/a>: The difference between a Q-value for a state-action pair and a value for the state. Useful to determine how good an action is relative to its state.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/intuitive-understanding-of-attention-mechanism-in-deep-learning-6c9482aecf4f">Attention&lt;/a>: Neural networks are able to &amp;ldquo;pay attention&amp;rdquo; to specific parts of input or output, useful in translating languages or predicting sequences. For example, when trying to predict the next word in &amp;ldquo;the clouds in the&amp;rdquo;, you pay attention to the word &lt;em>cloud&lt;/em> to predict the word &lt;em>sky&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autoencoder">Autoencoder&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A type of neural network that attempts to take raw data, convert it into a simpler representation (usually by limiting the amount of nodes in a hidden layer for representation), and then decode the representation back into it&amp;rsquo;s data. They are primarly used to extract the useful properties from data automatically. They can do this in an unsupervised fashion, since their output targets are the given input, requiring no labeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automated_machine_learning">AutoML&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Systems where the entire machine learning process, from data preparation to network design, is automated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://machinelearningmastery.com/autoregression-models-time-series-forecasting-python/">Autoregression&lt;/a>: A time series model that uses observations from previous time steps to predict the value at the next time step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backpropagation">Backpropogation&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: The algorithm and calculus behind gradient descent traditionally used in feed-forward neural networks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_statistics">Bayesian&lt;/a>: An interpretation of probability where the phrase &amp;ldquo;probability&amp;rdquo; expresses a degree of belief between 0 or 1, 0 representing false and 1 representing true. Uses expected values and random variables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bootstrapping_(statistics)">Bootstrapping&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Sampling from a distribution to approximate a function. In cases of reinforcement learning, bootstrapping usually samples potential future values to approximate a current value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network">Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A neural network primarly used for image processing. These networks design filters for specific parts of an image to extract higher level information, filters such as detecting a certain type of edge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-Covariate-shift?share=1">Covariate Shift&lt;/a>: The training distribution changes but the testing distribution does not change&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_mining">Data Mining&lt;/a>: Discovering knowledge and patterns from massive amounts of data, usually in an unsupervised fashion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">Deep Learning&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A subset of machine learning with a multi-step learning process, usually referring to neural networks with two or more layers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/221402/understanding-the-role-of-the-discount-factor-in-reinforcement-learning">Discount Factors&lt;/a>: A variable (usually $\gamma$) that determines how much a model cares about rewards in the distant future compared to immediate rewards.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>$\gamma = 0$ cares only about immediate reward,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$\gamma = 1$ cares only about sum of all future rewards.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/eligibility-traces-in-reinforcement-learning-a6b458c019d6">Eligibility Trace&lt;/a>: For temporal learning, the eligibility trace is a vector of decaying values that represent when weights were last used. When we encounter an error, this vector allows us to update recent weights harder than weights used long ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feedforward_neural_network">Feed-forward Neural Network&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A simple neural network where information is passed strictly from one layer to the next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network">Generative Adversarial Network (GAN)&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A set of two or more neural networks that can generate new data based on existing training data.
A simple example is &lt;a href="https://thispersondoesnotexist.com/">https://thispersondoesnotexist.com/&lt;/a>, that can generate fake pictures of humans.
- GANs consist of one generator network with the goal to make realistic new data, and a distinction network with the goal to tell real data from fake. As the networks train, they each improve at their individual task, forcing their adversaries to improve in turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genetic_algorithm">Genetic Algorithms&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Algorithms that try to mimic the evolutionary process by randomly modifying the best-performing sets of parameters while discarding those with the worst performance, then repeating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/">GPT-2/3&lt;/a>: A language model from OpenAI that can generate text that mimics a writing style incredibly well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gradient_descent">Gradient Descent&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: An interative process that attempts to find a minimum of a function that works by moving in the direction that will decrease the gradient until a local minima is reached.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperparameter_(machine_learning)">Hyperparameters&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Manually defined parameters of the model, such as the size of a neural network, or manually defined parameters of the machine learning algorithm, such as learning rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_and_identically_distributed_random_variables">(IID) Independent and Identically Distributed&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Random variables are independent and identically distributed when the value of one variable doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the probability of another variable. For example, the outcome of one coin flip does not affect the outcome of another coin flip, so both flips are IID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dibyaghosh.com/blog/probability/kldivergence.html">KL Divergence&lt;/a>: Divergence between two distributions of data. Useful for determining how different fake data is from real data (GANs) or for determining how differemt two policies are for trust-based reinforcement learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-driving_car">Level 0-5&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: The different &amp;ldquo;levels&amp;rdquo; of autonomy related to self driving cars. 0 represents full human control while 5 represents full vehicle control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_short-term_memory">Long Short Term Memory (LSTM)&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A type of recurrent neural network that works exceptionally well with sequential input. A unique trait of these networks are their memory cells&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;forget gates&amp;rdquo;, which allow them to control how long they hold onto data for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://deepai.org/publication/the-lottery-ticket-hypothesis-training-pruned-neural-networks">The Lottery Ticket Hypothesis&lt;/a>: A randomly-initialized, dense neural network contains a subnetwork that is initialised such that — when trained in isolation — it can match the test accuracy of the original network after training for at most the same number of iterations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markov_decision_process">Markov Decision Process&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A system of states, actions, and probabilities of getting to other states given actions taken from previous states.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aiden.nibali.org/blog/2017-01-18-mode-collapse-gans/">Mode Collapse&lt;/a>: When the distribution of samples produced by a generative adversarial network represent a subset of the latent distribution, instead of the entire latent distribution. For example, you train a network to produce pictures of animals but it only learns to produce pictures of cats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-armed_bandit">Multi-armed Bandit&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A core component of reinforcement learning, the multi-armed bandit problem is the classic &amp;ldquo;exploration versus exploitation&amp;rdquo; tradeoff. In this problem, expected gain must be maximized in an environment with varying rewards, forcing an agent to decide between keeping an option they know to be safe versus exploring new options that might be better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/897/online-vs-offline-learning">Online/Offline Learning&lt;/a>: Online learning happens as data comes in. Offline learning happens after data is collected and made into a batch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://mlss.tuebingen.mpg.de/2015/slides/ghahramani/gp-neural-nets15.pdf">Parametric &amp;amp; Non-Parametric Models&lt;/a>: Parametric models use a finite number of parameters, like weights in linear regression, to represent a learned hypothesis. Non-Parametric models use variable/infinite/no parameters, like data points in nearest neighbors, to represent a learned hypothesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_and_recall">Precision&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: The fraction of relevant instances among the retrieved instances. Also known as positive predictive value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_and_recall">Recall&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: The fraction of relevant instances that were retrieved. Also known as sensitivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recurrent_neural_network">Recurrent Neural Network (RNN)&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A type of network that can store state, giving it a type of memory that can process a series of inputs. This can be accomplished by having a cycle within the network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis">Regression&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A set of models that determine relationships between data and a dependent value. For example, linear regression tries to approximate a dependent value while logistic regression tries to determine the probability of a dependent value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residual_neural_network">Residual Neural Network&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Networks with connections that skip some layers and connect to non-adjacent ones. This type of network helps counter the vanishing gradient problem&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Algorithms are given a world state they are able to interact with, and learn from the reward their interactions give them.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ai.stackexchange.com/questions/4456/whats-the-difference-between-model-free-and-model-based-reinforcement-learning">Model-Based&lt;/a>: You create a model of the world and can predict what the next state and reward will be for each action&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ai.stackexchange.com/questions/4456/whats-the-difference-between-model-free-and-model-based-reinforcement-learning">Model-Free&lt;/a>: You know what action to take without knowing what to expect, since you don&amp;rsquo;t have a model of the world&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/an-intro-to-advantage-actor-critic-methods-lets-play-sonic-the-hedgehog-86d6240171d/">Value&lt;/a>: Networks that determine the value of a state.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/an-intro-to-advantage-actor-critic-methods-lets-play-sonic-the-hedgehog-86d6240171d/">Policy&lt;/a>: Network to choose actions. Can directly optimize model instead of computing values, useful when you have a continuous action space. Only uses reward function. Requires a score function to evaluate performance of policy, usually total rewards accumulated given a period of time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/an-intro-to-advantage-actor-critic-methods-lets-play-sonic-the-hedgehog-86d6240171d/">Actor Critic&lt;/a>: Backbone of state of the art reinforcement learning algorithms.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uses a value-based Critic to measure how good the action taken is&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uses a policy-based Actor to to choose actions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stochastic">Stochastic&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Randomly determined process, usually refers to probabilistic outputs of machine learning systems&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">Supervised Learning&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A model learns to produce a desired output and knows what that output is. Example: Image Recognition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temporal_difference_learning">Temporal Difference&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Model-free reinforcement learning design which learns by bootstrapping value samples in order to approximate a value function. Once more information is revealed about the true value during later timesteps, you can update the low information bootstrapped guess by using the newly acquired outcome as a &amp;ldquo;ground truth&amp;rdquo; to train a network.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Temporal Difference error is the difference between consecutive temporal predictions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ai.stackexchange.com/questions/7359/what-is-a-trajectory-in-reinforcement-learning">Trajectories&lt;/a>: The history of states (and potentially actions) taken during a walk of a Markov Decision Process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">Transfer Learning&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: Taking parts of a network trained on one data set, and using it in a different network with a different dataset.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/transformers-141e32e69591">Transformer&lt;/a>: A type of recurrent neural network primarily used with sequential data, like language translation. These networks use an attention model to improve performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsupervised_learning">Unsupervised Learning&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: A model learns to produce a desired output without being told what it&amp;rsquo;s looking for. Example: Playing Chess&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vanishing_gradient_problem">Vanishing Gradient Problem&lt;/a>&lt;sup>W&lt;/sup>: In a network, a gradient can become vanishingly small which will stop the weight from changing it&amp;rsquo;s value, since weights are modified based on their contribution to the gradient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to contact me with any suggested additions/changes at &lt;a href="mailto:jarbus@tutanota.com">jarbus@tutanota.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating Slides in Vim</title><link>/blog/generating-slides-in-vim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/generating-slides-in-vim/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a great tool known as &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org/">pandoc&lt;/a> that can convert documents from one filetype to another. For example, you can convert a Microsoft Word document to a PDF, without even needing to own a copy of Microsoft Word! However, we care about Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s ability to convert a Markdown document to a slideshow presentation using LaTeX Beamer as a rendering engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a great writeup about this basic feature &lt;a href="https://ashwinschronicles.github.io/beamer-slides-using-markdown-and-pandoc">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>TL;DR: With Pandoc installed and markdown file &lt;code>Demo.md&lt;/code>, executing &lt;code>pandoc -t beamer Demo.md -o Demo.pdf&lt;/code> will generate a slideshow as a pdf, with each section heading as the title of a new slide.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Different themes can be specified with the &lt;code>-V&lt;/code> option; I&amp;rsquo;m currently using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/matze/mtheme">Metropolis&lt;/a> beamer theme and &lt;a href="https://github.com/rchurchley/beamercolortheme-owl">Owl&lt;/a> colorscheme. After installing these themes, I can run:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>pandoc -t beamer
-V fontsize=14pt
-V theme=metropolis
-V colortheme=owl
-s
Demo.md -o Demo.pdf
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>to produce my presentation. &lt;strong>Note: All code blocks are single-line commands/&lt;code>.vimrc&lt;/code> entries, and are displayed as multi-line for readability.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to recompile a document every time I want to view my changes. Luckily, as a (Neo)Vim user, I can automatically run commands everytime I write a file. To avoid generating presentations with non-presentation markdown files, I instead write presentations in plaintext files that end with &lt;code>.slides&lt;/code>. In the example above, I&amp;rsquo;d be using &lt;code>Demo.slides&lt;/code> instead of &lt;code>Demo.md&lt;/code>. When I add:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>autocmd! BufWritePost *.slides silent !pandoc
-t beamer
-V fontsize=14pt
-V theme=metropolis
-V colortheme=owl
-s
% -o &amp;#34;%:p:h/.%:t:r.pdf&amp;#34;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>to my &lt;code>.vimrc&lt;/code>, everytime I save changes in a &lt;code>FILENAME.slides&lt;/code> file, it will generate a presentation located in &lt;code>.FILENAME.pdf&lt;/code>. I choose to add a leading period in the output to hide the PDF from my file manager, feel free to remove it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable markdown syntax highlighting in our &lt;code>.slides&lt;/code> file, add:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>autocmd BufRead,BufNewFile *.slides :set filetype=markdown
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>to your &lt;code>.vimrc&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now Vim generates a PDF presentation for us everytime we save a &lt;code>.slides&lt;/code> file. For easy viewing, I added another keybind, &lt;code>Z&lt;/code>, to open the corresponding PDF in my PDF viewer of choice, &lt;a href="https://pwmt.org/projects/zathura/">Zathura&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>nnoremap Z :silent !zathura --fork %:p:h/.%:t:r.pdf&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Zathura automatically refreshes the view whenever changes to an open document is detected. This means that I can open a &lt;code>.slides&lt;/code> file in Vim, save changes, and press &lt;code>Z&lt;/code> to view my changes in Zathura. I can then immediately view any additional changes I make in the open Zathura window, just by saving the &lt;code>.slides&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uninformed Or Misinformed?</title><link>/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is it better to have no facts about a topic and thus no opinion, or have access to a few &amp;ldquo;out of context&amp;rdquo; facts and thus a misinformed opinion?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>TL;DR: Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You can&amp;rsquo;t be well-informed on every topic; It&amp;rsquo;s just not possible. That&amp;rsquo;s why world leaders have advisers. Yet somehow, if you look at anyone&amp;rsquo;s Facebook account, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to try too hard to figure out their view on any political issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to realize how much nuance there is to the headlines we see. When I read an article that ruins the image of a company or individual, I always wonder: What information could the author be omitting? What view could the other side have? What outside information is the author conveniently using to make a point?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I try to avoid getting emotional until these questions are answered. I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of having basic gut feelings on unfamiliar topics, but these feelings aren&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to start an argument. I talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m informed about, and listen (with a grain of salt) to others talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for lots of us. Instead of admitting we are uninformed, many of us form an opinion after we read the headline, and most likely don&amp;rsquo;t update it after skimming the article with said headline. We are even less likely to look for an opposing take, as that requires we scroll outside of whatever feed we are browsing through. Some people don&amp;rsquo;t even use the news to form opinions: They just accept the opinions of their friends or family as &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;. As someone who accepted the outcome of the 2020 presidential election without looking into the claims of fraud, I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of this too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We then take this opinion that a) isn&amp;rsquo;t ours and b) took less than 10 seconds to form, and carry it into the foreseeable future, not even considering the idea that there might be more we don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with admitting that we don&amp;rsquo;t know enough to judge a topic or event? Do we really think we have enough context and facts to make sound judgements on all our beliefs? Do we really need to hold an opinion after every scandal? Why can&amp;rsquo;t we just say &amp;ldquo;This is a side of a story&amp;rdquo; and move on?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/03/timnit-gebru-google-fired/">Google&amp;rsquo;s firing of Timnit Gebru&lt;/a> for example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>I read a headline about Google firing a researcher that criticized the company on a mailing list. I didn&amp;rsquo;t need about any more drama in my life, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t read further, tucking this away in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google responded with something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;she was using an email list in such a way that was improper for her position&amp;rdquo;. I still didn&amp;rsquo;t need the drama, so I kept it in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I still hold no strong positions on this specific topic and don&amp;rsquo;t plan on learning more about it. Like in most &amp;ldquo;scandals&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;he said, she said&amp;rdquo; going on, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time figuring out who is right.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If I wanted to hold an opinion on this event, I&amp;rsquo;d need the following details to start:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The code of conduct for Gebru&amp;rsquo;s position&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other alternative methods Gebru could have used not in violation of the Code of Conduct if her actions violated it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The contents of the email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verbose arguments from both sides refuting each other&amp;rsquo;s points if possible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evidence of Gebru&amp;rsquo;s claims&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As someone who does not work at nor plans to work at Google, this just isn&amp;rsquo;t worth my time, so I don&amp;rsquo;t form an opinion. There are other things to worry about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL;DR (again): Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soft Rules</title><link>/blog/soft-rules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/soft-rules/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not all rules are made equal. Some rules, like the speed limit, are broken by everyone and their mother, and are enforced (mostly) when people are breaking them to a dangerous point. Other rules, like &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t murder people&amp;rdquo;, are enforced far more. Why is that?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="different-rules-different-tools" >Different Rules, Different Tools
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#different-rules-different-tools">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Some rules are in place to assign blame to someone with bad judgement. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing morally wrong with jaywalking when there are no cars coming, but you are at fault if you walk into oncoming traffic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some rules are in place to discourage bad habits from forming, like the drinking age. This law is so commonly broken that it&amp;rsquo;s expected behavior at this point, and yet I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen someone get arrested for under-age drinking. Despite this, the law conveys the dangers of drinking, makes it harder for minors to acquire alcohol, and prevents students from openly sharing alcohol in schools.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some rules, like mandatory attendance, exist to get people to show up to an event or perform an activity. Even when attendance isn&amp;rsquo;t taken, many people will still show up to prevent unnecessary trouble. College orientation activities are a prime example.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some rules exist simply because they haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated. Before 2020, some companies &amp;ndash; especially older ones &amp;ndash; didn&amp;rsquo;t allow employees to work from home. Working from home was seen as an unnecessary risk by upper management with no tangible benefit to any of the executives. Along comes the coronavirus, and suddenly the jobs people have been doing in an office for decades are suddenly doable from home.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="rules-for-rules" >Rules for Rules
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#rules-for-rules">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Rules should be justified. If a sign on a fish tank says, &lt;em>PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS&lt;/em>, do you think most people, especially children, are likely to obey? Does your answer change if the sign were to say &lt;em>PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS, IT SCARES THE FISH&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too many rules, even if they are justified. The more rules in place, the less likely people will follow them. Just think about it: If Moses received 206 commandments, do you think his followers would view &lt;em>Thou shalt not eat meat and dairy&lt;/em> with the same level of respect as &lt;em>Thou shalt not kill&lt;/em>? More rules can imply that there are strict guidelines to be followed, but people will interpret them as: &lt;em>Whoever came up with this must be fun at parties.&lt;/em> Unnecessary rules draw attention away from the important ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wrapping-up-rules" >Wrapping Up Rules
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#wrapping-up-rules">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m no rule expert. Nevertheless, I recognize that creating and selectively enforcing rules is a valuable skill, for both policy-makers and policy-enforcers alike. If you want people to respect your rules, make sure they have a reason for being there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critical Thinking</title><link>/blog/critical-thinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/critical-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I learn about the world, the less certain I become about it. There are so many conflicting views and information taken out of context that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to discern fact from truth. Below are some notes I keep to help navigate the sea of information that is modern society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL;DR: Don&amp;rsquo;t get fooled by facts if they have no context, don&amp;rsquo;t discount an opinion because it&amp;rsquo;s biased, and hear out crazy ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="be-skeptical-fact--truth" >Be skeptical: Fact != Truth
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#be-skeptical-fact--truth">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>There are facts available for virtually anything you need. No matter what argument you try to make, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to find a statistic that can back up your claims thanks to the glory of Google.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3030983/The-ultra-competitive-exercise-fad-ruin-health-called-planking-suddenly-sweeping-gyms-Pilates-classes.html">&amp;ldquo;Did you know that planking can ruin your health and result in months of pain?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.lifehack.org/292578/7-things-that-will-happen-when-you-do-planking-exercise-every-day">&amp;ldquo;Not true, planking works out multiple muscles in your body and can greatly improve your health if done daily&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not exactly scientific sources, but I think this demonstrates my point. Furthermore, the level of mixed information increases exponentially as the topic gets more political.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Facts should never be enough to prove a point, and I tend to suspect people who rely too heavily on them. Facts should instead be used to tell a narrative; facts are not the truth, but they can light the way towards it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewarren/status/1090252713156403200">&amp;ldquo;The top 0.1% &amp;hellip; own about the same wealth as the bottom 90% of America.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While deemed &amp;ldquo;Mostly True&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href="https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2019/jan/31/elizabeth-warren/warren-top-01-own-about-much-bottom-90/">Politifact.com&lt;/a>, this statement in isolation is less than useless: it&amp;rsquo;s misleading. On it&amp;rsquo;s own, this fact paints a picture of a grim society, where the bottom 90% are left to struggle for survival, with all resources being held for a greedy few. If you are in the bottom 90%, this prompts you to believe that life is unfair, and that this should be changed. That&amp;rsquo;s why this statistic is so popular, it seems outrageous and gives Americans a sense of justified anger at the rich, an anger which many ex-presidential candidates used to garner support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s break this idea down a bit. The greedy elite factoid on its own implies nothing about quality of life, standard of living, financial responsibility, or determination to work. Society could be a paradise where everyone has access to more than they could ever need, and the top 0.1% just has an absurd amount of money. Or society could be a system of addiction, where the bottom 90% are constantly spending money on things they don&amp;rsquo;t need and the top 0.1% simply aren&amp;rsquo;t addicted and save/invest wisely. The truth is, these numbers don&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything about the truth, and aren&amp;rsquo;t being used to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consider a narrative discussing the implications of this statistic from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wealth_inequality_in_the_United_States#Effect_on_democracy">Wikipedia&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A 2014 study by researchers at Princeton and Northwestern concludes that government policies reflect the desires of the wealthy, and that the vast majority of American citizens have &amp;ldquo;minuscule, near-zero, statistically non-significant impact upon public policy … when a majority of citizens disagrees with economic elites and/or with organized interests, they generally lose.&amp;rdquo; When Fed chair Janet Yellen was questioned by Bernie Sanders about the study at a congressional hearing in May 2014, she responded &amp;ldquo;There’s no question that we’ve had a trend toward growing inequality&amp;rdquo; and that this trend &amp;ldquo;can shape [and] determine the ability of different groups to participate equally in a democracy and have grave effects on social stability over time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Most people know about inequality, but not what it means for them. The wealth statistic means nothing in a vaccuum, only in context does it hold any value. If facts are used to invoke emotion instead of prove a point, be skeptical.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased" >Worth Listening to those who are biased?
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>A girl in a class of mine had a laptop sticker that read &amp;ldquo;Why be racist, sexist, or transphobic when you can just be quiet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t stand this type of thinking. It&amp;rsquo;s elitist, tells people with controversial views to not let their voice be heard, and contributes to the echo chamber of modern society. Furthermore, it accomplishes nothing except a pat on the back for people with her mindset. No racist is actually going to read that and go &amp;ldquo;Oh, guess I just won&amp;rsquo;t speak my mind then.&amp;rdquo; In fact, they might be driven further into racism in spite. Nobody likes being talked down to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of insight to be gained on both sides from listening to people with views you don&amp;rsquo;t like. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think white supremacists are evil and don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to speak; its harder to realize they have a reason for their beliefs. If you want to make the world a better place, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from silence, but from understanding. When fighting racism, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it make sense to understand where racists are coming from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to discuss tax law, you should hear out the rich guy that wants lower taxes just as much as the working class American who wants the same. If you want to discuss diversity, don&amp;rsquo;t limit the white participants to those with an &amp;ldquo;anti-white&amp;rdquo; mindset. These perspectives are essential to promoting an open dialogue, and leaving out those with biased opinions leads to toxic echo chambers and a mentality of &amp;ldquo;us versus them&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hear-out-the-crazy" >Hear out the crazy
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#hear-out-the-crazy">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>When I experimented with fasting, a few people I knew were opposed. The concept of not eating for days on end? Ridiculous! Your body needs food, your metabolism will slow to a halt if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These arguments didn&amp;rsquo;t come from any sort of reading on the subject, but human intuition. The concept of not eating for a few days went against everything they knew; to them it was crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fasting isn&amp;rsquo;t actually bad for you if done right, and can have &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fasting#Health_effects">numerous health benefits&lt;/a>. A simple Google search into the subject could have cleared up these misconceptions. But that would imply that this ridiculous idea could have some merit worth looking for. It&amp;rsquo;s like looking up &amp;ldquo;Did the Holocaust happen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to most domains however, there is usually some fascinating logic behind crazy ideas. Bitcoin comes to mind; a currency without a government to back it seems completely absurd on the surface. The gut reaction is to call Bitcoin a fraud, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/01/09/jamie-dimon-says-he-regrets-calling-bitcoin-a-fraud.html">but when the best in the business take some time to think about it, they might have second thoughts&lt;/a>. The Bitcoin community is full of brilliant people that built the foundation of blockchain technology. It&amp;rsquo;s worth hearing them out, even if their ideas seem a bit crazy at first glance. They must have their reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts" >Final Thoughts
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#final-thoughts">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As the news cycle continues to speed up, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to determine fact from fiction, who&amp;rsquo;s crazy and who&amp;rsquo;s biased, what&amp;rsquo;s conspiracy and what&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to listen to everyone, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t only listen to those with a similar mindset. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get the full story for every topic of discussion, but don&amp;rsquo;t fall for out-of-context information. Question everything, but keep an open mind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tesla and False Advertising in AI</title><link>/blog/tesla-and-false-advertising-in-ai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/tesla-and-false-advertising-in-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem with advertising AI-based technology that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You cannot promise anything about your product.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen AI advertised to the masses that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as advertised, just look at any voice-to-text system. When I got my Apple Watch, I hoped to use it to respond to messages without getting distracted by my phone. I quickly realized that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a viable solution: I had to repeat my message multiple times per text in order to get the correct dictation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this was a software issue, I could file a bug report and Apple could send out a fix. Unfortunately with AI, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much Apple can do besides get more data and re-train the model, which still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee a better user experience for anyone. Mind you, this is with software that&amp;rsquo;s already shipped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at Tesla, or more specifically its CEO, Elon Musk. &lt;a href="https://futurism.com/elon-musk-tesla-close-level-5-autonomy">Musk claims that Level 5 driving (in which a human is not needed behind the wheel) will be coming to Tesla vehicles in the form of a software update by the end of 2020&lt;/a>. A month before he made said claim, &lt;a href="https://futurism.com/the-byte/tesla-autopilot-slam-overturned-truck">a Tesla on autopilot crashed into a flipped truck&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;a mistake most humans wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just like Apple can&amp;rsquo;t promise its speech-to-text system will work better than a human (or even better than a toddler), Musk can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee anything about Tesla&amp;rsquo;s Level 5 capability. Tesla can&amp;rsquo;t even &amp;ldquo;reasonably claim&amp;rdquo; your car won&amp;rsquo;t crash into flipped trucks or &lt;a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/autos/enthusiasts/another-tesla-crashes-into-a-cop-car-while-on-autopilot/ar-BB16Mvkk#!">stopped cop cars&lt;/a>. In fact, no one using deep learning can promise anything about their system. Deep learning, and by extension Tesla&amp;rsquo;s Autopilot system, is a black box. We don&amp;rsquo;t know why it works, we can&amp;rsquo;t promise that it&amp;rsquo;ll work, but it seems to work when we test it. Unless Tesla is testing on all roads in all conditions, they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be &amp;ldquo;confident&amp;rdquo; level 5 technology, in which &lt;strong>a human does not need to be in the vehicle&lt;/strong>, is &amp;ldquo;around the corner&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tesla-autopilot-germany/german-court-bans-tesla-ad-statements-related-to-autonomous-driving-idUSKCN24F1T5">a court in Germany banned Tesla from including “full potential for autonomous driving” and “Autopilot inclusive” in its German advertising materials&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Full Self-Driving (FSD) update wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first time Tesla over-promises and under-delivers. Consumer Reports described the company&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Smart Summon&amp;rdquo; feature as &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/automotive-technology/teslas-smart-summon-performance-doesnt-match-marketing-hype/">&amp;ldquo;glitchy and at times worked intermittently&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. The damage with Smart Summon has been low, but a full-autonomy update could result in a few consequences:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tesla sold cars with the promise of Level 5 driving in the future: Not only is Tesla now under immense pressure to rush out a Level 5 update as soon as possible, but must do so using the hardware it sold customers years ago. Hopefully Level 5 doesn&amp;rsquo;t require LIDAR sensors (or any additional hardware) like Elon claims; because Tesla is expected to ship some version of FSD to users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customers may end up in legal trouble if Tesla&amp;rsquo;s software fails them: Tesla avoids legal responsibility for buggy software by shifting responsibility of an accident to the driver. However, when Tesla sells millions of cars on the premise that users won&amp;rsquo;t have to manually drive them one day, should drivers be held responsible when that day comes and their car crashes?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Other companies have realized the high standards a Level 5 system should meet. Two years ago, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-11-13/waymo-ceo-says-self-driving-cars-won-t-be-ubiqitious-for-decades">Waymo CEO John Krafcik claimed that true self-driving cars, that function everywhere under all circumstances, won&amp;rsquo;t be ubiquitous for decades&lt;/a>. As a result, Waymo shifted gears and placed its focus on rolling out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/9/21000085/waymo-fully-driverless-car-self-driving-ride-hail-service-phoenix-arizona">autonomous taxis&lt;/a> on a city by city basis, starting in Pheonix, Arizona. This approach to Level 5 driving is much safer for the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Waymo is minimizing the number of people at risk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Waymo is operating its vehicles strictly where they have been tested.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Waymo is not selling consumers a technology that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Waymo is not relying on the average consumer to be attentive&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Level 5 technology can save thousands of lives and millions of dollars&amp;ndash;but it needs to be done to the same (if not higher) standards of automotive testing, and not the &amp;ldquo;move fast and break things&amp;rdquo; approach of Silicon Valley. Hopefully Tesla can safely deliver on its promise of full self driving soon, but if not, consumers may soon have a case to demand a refund.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Short: Aftermath</title><link>/blog/short-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/short-aftermath/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jeff stepped over a beer can, then over a water bottle and onto a mat, whose faded lettering vaguely resembled the phrase &amp;ldquo;Welcome!&amp;rdquo; He opened his front door and walked inside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking to his right, Jeff noticed his old hooded friend where he left him; on his living-room rocking chair. The cold metal scythe still in his lap, the skeleton hadn&amp;rsquo;t moved an inch from where he left him earlier that morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s cooking, big guy?&amp;rdquo; Jeff said as he walked to the kitchen to grab his last can of Budweiser. His boney companioned turned his head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Oh, you know&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;, Death emitted. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>still out of work.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Ah.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>I do not understand why you still haven&amp;rsquo;t given up yet.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I could say the same about you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>I exist for one purpose, Jeffrey. and as long as you are alive, I cannot rest.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, you seem pretty well rested to me, what with you never leaving my house and all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>I used to have what you call a &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo;. It was very fulfilling, Jeffery. Took up all of my time. Do you want to know what it was?&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jeffery took a sip of his beer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>I used to collect the souls of the dead, Jeffery. It was wonderful. I conversed with the rich, the poor, the young and the old, Jeffrey, as they contemplated life and where they were headed. I had, what you would call, a &amp;rsquo;nice thing going.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All good things gotta come to an end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Then you came along,&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death continued, ignoring him, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>and ruined everything.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It be like that sometimes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It does not &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo; like that sometimes, Jeffrey&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death glared, a purple glow forming in his eye sockets. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>A single human does not wipe out humanity &amp;rsquo;every now and then&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Fair.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>What is even more despicable,&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death proceeded, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>is that you don&amp;rsquo;t even regret pushing the button.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t really think about it too much.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>YOU HAD A CHOICE,&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death boomed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>BETWEEN SAVING HUMANKIND, AND SAVING YOURSELF&amp;ndash;&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Mhm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>AND WITHOUT A SECOND THOUGHT, DOOMED YOUR ENTIRE SPECIES&amp;ndash;&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yup.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>&amp;ndash;IN EXCHANGE FOR A LIFE OF THEFT AND SLUMBER.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Can&amp;rsquo;t steal from the dead,&amp;rdquo; Jeff rebutted, taking another sip.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>THAT IS NOT THE POINT, JEFFREY&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death bellowed. He paused, taking a few seconds to decompose himself. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>You fail to understand the magnitude of your actions.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh, I understand perfectly well, you&amp;rsquo;ve made sure of that. I&amp;rsquo;d have to be deaf to spend a day with you and not hear your whining.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe you even have a soul worth collecting.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Listen, it was self defense, alright? It&amp;rsquo;s not like I wanted to kill everyone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Adolf Hitler, Joseph Stalin, Osama Bin Laden; every single corrupt soul in your history books would not have stooped to your level; self-defense does not justify genocide.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;So humans can drive thousands of species to extinction for selfish gain, but only when it happens to them it&amp;rsquo;s unjustified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Death moved as if to rebutt, but said nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Do you know how close we came to nuclear war? There was never a guarantee of tomorrow for anyone. For all we know, the human race might last an extra few decades thanks to me.&amp;rdquo; Jeff said, smirking. &amp;ldquo;Why does humanity deserves the benefit of the doubt?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Why do you?&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily,&amp;rdquo; Jeff said, taking a seat on the opposite couch. &amp;ldquo;It just happened to be my choice. My parents were already dead&amp;ndash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t owe anybody anything. What moral rule says I &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to lay down my life for those I don&amp;rsquo;t know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>You are selfish, Jeffrey Johnson.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Death said, rising from his seat. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>You put yourself in front of millions of good, innocent people who would lay down their lives in your situation.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Is it selfish, or simply not being selfless? A starving man doesn&amp;rsquo;t owe another starving man his bread.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Death leaned forward, skull to face with Jeff, searching for any sign of remorse. He came back empty. Death turned around drifted towards the exit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;em>He owes the guilt of denying a meal,&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; he remarked as he left the room. The front door creaked open, then closed. Silence filled the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Should I instead spend humanity&amp;rsquo;s last years crying?&amp;rdquo; Jeff yelled to the door.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The door didn&amp;rsquo;t respond.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happiness</title><link>/blog/happiness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some thoughts on Happiness:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happiness doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from wealth. Otherwise, therapists and anti-depressants would have to be much cheaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If happiness came from consumption of goods and services, it would therefore follow that once those goods and services are reduced or cut off, one would no longer be as happy. If you can cut off happiness, it&amp;rsquo;s more akin to a drug than an emotion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2017/04/over-nearly-80-years-harvard-study-has-been-showing-how-to-live-a-healthy-and-happy-life/">&amp;ldquo;Close relationships, more than money or fame, are what keep people happy throughout their lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> While financial security is ideal for easing pain and suffering, significant amounts of money can strain relationships and cast doubt on who your friends really are. If solid relationships are a path to happiness, the drama and expectations caused from wealth differences in the relationships might very well block that path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a sense, happiness isn&amp;rsquo;t something you can obtain, but something you become. True happiness has to come from within to be strong and sustainable. Performing work you find meaningful, engaging in relationships of substance, and living a life of virtue are all ways to approach happiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happiness can&amp;rsquo;t come from believing you are the smartest, most attractive, or funniest person in your social circles. If it does, you either aren&amp;rsquo;t around people you can learn from or are living in a world of illusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If stressed about all those that are above you, happiness is possible if you enjoy the process of learning and take pride in trying your best.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s possible to be a masterpiece and a work in progress at the same time.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Pain and happiness are not mutually exclusive, but rather two sides of the same coin. The greatest pains can come from the greatest happiness, such as the loss of a loved one. Some of the greatest happiness comes from the greatest pain, such as starting new relationships after others have ended. The most painful moments can sometimes fuel transitions into the best ones. Don&amp;rsquo;t let pain go to waste.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/healthbeat/giving-thanks-can-make-you-happier">One of the best ways to increase happiness is to show gratitude.&lt;/a> When expressing thanks for what you have instead of longing for what you don&amp;rsquo;t, you learn to draw happiness from yourself instead of the high of getting something new. If you were to lose that for which you are thankful, the situation doesn&amp;rsquo;t change &amp;ndash; draw gratitude from what&amp;rsquo;s left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Whitepaper, Explained</title><link>/blog/bitcoin-whitepaper-explained/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/bitcoin-whitepaper-explained/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction" >Introduction
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#introduction">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In this essay we will give a brief history of crytocurrency leading up to
Bitcoin, give an overview of the Bitcoin protocol by summarizing
key sections of the whitepaper, and briefly discuss Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s use of cryptographical
proof and computational security instead of trusted third parties within
the protocol.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="history" >History
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#history">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Bitcoin is far from original. Digital currencies date back as far as
1982, where David Chaum released a paper called &amp;quot;Blind Signatures&amp;quot;,
which formed the basis of a digital currency known as eCash. In 1996,
Douglass Jackson created a currency known as e-gold in 1996, the first
currency to reach mass adoption at over 3.5 million accounts.
Many other subsequent currencies rose and fell before Bitcoin gained
stable footing, including projects such as BitGold and b-money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blockchain technology development began as early as 1991 when Stuart
Haber and W. Scott Stornetta began work on a cryptographically secured
chain of blocks. &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2F3-540-38424-3_32.pdf">Their inital goal was to implement a system where
document timestamps could not be tampered with.&lt;/a> Bitcoin builds upon
Haber and Stornetta&amp;rsquo;s subsequent work of reliable timestamping and
securing names for bit strings and cites three of their papers,
making up a third of the nine citations in the Bitcoin whitepaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bitcoin also builds upon technology such as Proof-of-Work, first
developed in 1997 by Adam Back under the name &lt;a href="http://hashcash.org/">Hashcash.&lt;/a>
Proof-of-Work is a counter-measure towards abuse of un-metered internet
resources which could enable a Denial of Service attack on email by
requiring an attacker to expend computational resources in order to
interact with the network. A reusable version of Proof-Of-Work was
further developed by Hal Finney in 2004, the receiver of the first
bitcoin transaction. Proof-Of-Work will be further discussed later on in
this paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Satoshi Nakamoto, the anonymous creator(s) of Bitcoin released the
Bitcoin whitepaper to a cryptography mailing list on October 31st, 2008,
four short years after Hal Finney&amp;rsquo;s paper. The first block was mined
January the following year, with a comment that reads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Times 03/Jan/2009 Chancellor on brink of second bailout for banks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Very fitting for the anti-authority ideals Bitcoin would spur in the coming years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="design" >Design
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#design">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="section-2-and-9-transactions-combining-and-splitting-value" >Section 2 and 9: Transactions, Combining and Splitting Value
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#section-2-and-9-transactions-combining-and-splitting-value">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Bitcoin is represented as a publicly visible global log of
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_signature">signed&lt;/a>$^W$
transactions. Each transaction denotes the participants in a transaction
as well as the amount of money transfered (analogous to the Venmo public
feed), and the signature ensures the account publishing the transaction
is the account who owns the Bitcoin. Since the amount of Bitcoin an
account has is directly represented by outputs of previous transactions,
sending money is represented by taking previous transactions addressed
to your account, sigining them, and specifying which addresses will
receive which portions of the funds. Since one or more transactions can
be used as input for this process, there can be one or more addresses
receiving the output, including the spender who recieves any left-over
Bitcoin as change, since it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to use a fraction of a
transaction as input.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Transactions must be verified, i.e. nodes must confirm that transaction
signatures come from their corresponding private keys. Transactions are
verified in large batches. Each transaction is added to a pool of
unverified transactions, which are then all verified and published to
the network in a block, approximately once every ten minutes. Each block
is published with a timestamp and a hash of a previous block, forming a
&amp;ldquo;chain&amp;rdquo; of all valid transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sections-3-and-4-timestamp-server-proof-of-work" >Sections 3 and 4: Timestamp server, Proof of Work
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#sections-3-and-4-timestamp-server-proof-of-work">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Bitcoin also implements a distributed timestamp server. Normal timestamp
servers take hashes of previous timestamps and the current block in
order to form a new timestamp hash, then widely publish this hash.
However, this requires a trusted party, and does not work in a
distributed setting with no trusted parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nakamoto takes inspiration from Adam Back&amp;rsquo;s Hashcash algorithm, which
implements a Proof-Of-Work scheme based off of finding a hash with a
specific number of zeros at the beginning. This is a very
computationally expensive task, as the only method of obtaining such a
hash is brute force. Since a new block is published every ten minutes
and each block requires the hash of a previous block, this requires
anyone attmempting to modify the blockchain history to not only find the
proper hash at the specific time, but also all hashes of subsequent
blocks in order to maintain the validity of the ledger. This type of
attack can be used to spend the same Bitcoin twice, as a user could make
a transaction, erase it from the blockchain, and then use it again.
However, thanks to the proof-of-work algorithm, this attack increases in
difficultly exponentially as new blocks are added, and is one of the
many forms of computational security the Bitcoin protocol implements.
Since the amount of computational power on the blockchain will naturally
vary overtime, the proof-of-work algorithm will also adjust to
compensate for increased/decreased mining power in order to keep blocks
published approximately every ten minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first block verified and published is added to the network, and the
longest chain of blocks is deemed to be the correct one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="section-5-network" >Section 5: Network
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#section-5-network">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The Bitcoin network runs on the following steps taken verbatim from the
original whitepaper, as there is not much summary for this section I
deem myself capable of doing better than Nakamoto.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>New transactions are broadcast to all nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each node collects new transactions into a block&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each node works on finding a difficult proof-of-work for its block&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When a node finds a proof-of-work, it broadcasts the block to all nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nodes accept the block only if all transactions in it are valid and
not already spent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nodes express their acceptance of the block by working on creating
the next block in the chain, using the hash of the accepted block as
the previous hash.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Nodes always consider the longest chain to be the correct one and will
keep working on extending it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sections-6-8-incentive-reclaiming-disk-space-simplified-payment-verification" >Sections 6-8: Incentive, Reclaiming Disk Space, Simplified Payment Verification
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#sections-6-8-incentive-reclaiming-disk-space-simplified-payment-verification">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Section six explains the financial benefits of mining, namely how miners get newly minted coins and transaction fees.
Nakamoto then explains how even when an adversary can claim control over a majority of the network&amp;rsquo;s mining power, it makes economic sense to act according to the protocol to gain profit instead of creating double-spend attacks, since people will stop using the system once it is compromised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In section seven, Nakamoto also discusses storage optimizations for
reducing the amount of disk space the entire blockchain uses. The
primary method discussed involved removing transactions that are buried
underneath many blocks but hashing the transactions in a Merkle tree as
to break the hashes of any blocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In section eight, Nakamoto describes a method of payment verification
without needing to run a full node, as well as potential attacks and
countermeasures on nodes attempting to verify transactions without
storing the entire blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="section-10-privacy" >Section 10: Privacy
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#section-10-privacy">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>It should be noted that Bitcoin has no privacy protections in place to
protect users besides basic anonymity of not tying real-world identities
to keys. The amount of Bitcoin sent in each transaction is public, as
well as the public keys used. New public-private keypairs are
recommended for each transaction, but the multi-input nature of
transactions reveals two inputs are attached to the same owner. As a
result, if the identity of a sender is compromised, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
trace transaction history and link previous transactions that user has
made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="section-11-cryptography-and-security" >Section 11: Cryptography and Security
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#section-11-cryptography-and-security">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Attackers are unable to steal the money of other users without their
private key. There is also no method to generate new Bitcoin in anyway
that an honest node could recognize as valid. Therefore, the only
feasible attack on Bitcoin is to generate an alternative chain of
blocks. Since the longest chain of blocks is considered valid, this
attack requires the generation of an alternative chain faster than the
honest chain. This can be thought of as a race between the attacker and
the rest of the network, with the attacker starting from behind since
they have to re-compute proof of work for existing blocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nakamoto demonstrates how an attacker with $51%$ of the networks hashing power
will be guaranteed to eventually catch up and sustain an alternative
chain, however given a sufficiently large network Nakamoto assumes this
infeasilbe, as the computation power required would be enormous.
Additionally, every time an adversary fails to beat an honest node in
creating the next block, the amount of blocks they need to catch up to
increases and thus unless an attacker gets incredibly lucky when they
first start generating an alternate chain, their chances of catching up
to the main chain decreases exponentially. Since the chance for an
attacker to catch up to the honest chain decreases exponentially as new
blocks are added, Nakamoto demonstrates how long an honest recipient
must wait before they can be 99.9% certain a double-spend attack will
not happen given attackers of various computational power. For example, if attackers
control 10% of the mining power, one would need to merely wait five
blocks, but if attackers have 45%, one would need to wait 340 blocks,
or just under two and a half days, to be sure their transaction is safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="resources-used" >Resources Used
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#resources-used">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Of course the &lt;a href="https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf">Bitcoin whitepaper&lt;/a> and it&amp;rsquo;s references have been used in the writing of this essay, but I also wanted to credit &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-came-before-bitcoin">this Quora post&lt;/a> for pointing author in the right direction for the second section.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anonymity</title><link>/blog/anonymity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/anonymity/</guid><description>&lt;p>What happened to &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t give out your name on the internet?&amp;rdquo; Within the past 15 years, the desire for online anonymity has vanished &amp;ndash; as &amp;ldquo;normal people&amp;rdquo; joined the digital world, the number of &amp;ldquo;creepy people&amp;rdquo; worth hiding your identity from seems to have dropped in comparison. Despite the perceived safety of the online world, remaining anonymous still has its merits.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anonymity-addresses-ideas" >Anonymity addresses ideas
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#anonymity-addresses-ideas">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In an ideal world, political debate occurs detached from the people debating the topic. When discussing the gender wage gap for example, fact-based discussions should be possible between any two individuals, regardless of gender, salary, or race. Productive discourse where different interpretations of the same statistics should occur, where arguents, not participants, are rebutted and questioned. This ideal world does not exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, when arguments are backed by identities, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to attack an argument by attacking the arguer. It&amp;rsquo;s too easy to claim someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what they are talking about, since they are too old or too young, too priveleged or too uneducated. Political elections are perhaps the best examples of this, especially when candidates attack past actions of their opponents to avoid attacking their values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An idea with no group or person attributed to it is the truest form of an idea, for it exists on its own and must be taken down for what it is, not who is behind it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anonymity-ensures-security" >Anonymity ensures security
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#anonymity-ensures-security">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Freedom of speech ensures individuals can not be legally punished for publicly expressing their opinion. However, when opinions are tied to identities, the government is not needed to punish those with different views. Citizens can take matters into their own hands if given the target&amp;rsquo;s place of work and the ability to write a dishonest complaint. A quote taken out of context and a social network to spread it can end a career. Given the rapid spread of data in society, the best way to ensure your security is to spread as little of your information as possible, and to separate whatever you share from each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anonymity-ensures-authenticity" >Anonymity ensures authenticity
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#anonymity-ensures-authenticity">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Give a man a mask and he&amp;rsquo;ll show his true face&amp;rdquo; is a favorite quote of mine. It can act as an attack against anonymity, claiming people will act badly if able to avoid social and legal backlash. This can be interpreted in a different way; &lt;strong>people have the freedom to be who they are when they don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about backlash&lt;/strong>. Is it just to not feel safe showing one&amp;rsquo;s true face in modern society?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surveillance acts partially as a way to collect information on a populus, and partially as a way to enforce good behavior; if you see a camera at a stoplight, you are more likely to act in good behavior whether or not the camera is actually on. In an ideal world, everyone acts in good behavior and gets along, but on their own terms and not because they are being watched. Remaining anonymous ensures good behavior is not done in hopes of receiving praise or gaining social acceptance, but rather for the sake of being good. An example could be comparing a person who drives safely in case there might be a cop versus a person who drives safely because they don&amp;rsquo;t wish to risk anyone&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tldr" >TL;DR
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#tldr">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>An anonymous idea is stronger than a non-anonymous idea, as it lacks the weaknesses associated with having a human (and thus flawed) orator.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A person is always safer when they aren&amp;rsquo;t publicly tied to any comments or statements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A person has the freedom to be who they are when their identity isn&amp;rsquo;t behind their actions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Forgiveness</title><link>/blog/forgiveness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/forgiveness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Forgiveness has a negative connotation these days. We see forgiving each other as weak — as not standing by one’s values, as giving up one’s pride. This view is incredibly counter-productive and, in my opinion, the cause of many problems in today’s society. Here is the actual definition of forgiveness:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>forgive (verb)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>to cease to feel resentment against (an offender)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Source: Merriam Webster&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This definition is all that forgiveness has to be — not pardoning or excusing someone for their actions, but instead letting go of anger towards them. Grudges may appear to make someone “tough” and “strong,” but all they do is keep someone’s mind tormented by the people they despise. It is very easy to hold a grudge—grudges make one feel powerful without requiring them to do anything. However, true power in one’s life stems from overcoming this negativity and taking control of one’s emotions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="forgiving-others" >Forgiving Others
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#forgiving-others">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Forgiving others is much easier than it sounds and is one of the quickest and simplest ways to &lt;em>improve your mental state&lt;/em>. This will be more challenging for deep, long-term grudges, but you can displace surface-level anger as easily as saying, “[Person], I forgive you” aloud—even when alone. Forgiveness helps get negative people out of your head who don’t deserve to be there. It also helps you understand others instead of hating them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Letting go of blame/resentment helps focus on finding solutions, instead of blaming others for problems—this results in &lt;em>better decision making&lt;/em>. Your thought process goes from, “If only this person didn’t do that, everything would be so much better” to “This happened, what can I do about it?” It’s not possible to control the actions of others, but we can control our own responses. This attitude &lt;em>sharpens social skills&lt;/em>, as you learn to respond maturely instead of reacting passionately when upset.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="forgiving-yourself" >Forgiving Yourself
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#forgiving-yourself">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>What does forgiving yourself mean? In line with our definition from above, it means to cease self-resentment. Many toxic behaviors stem from insecurities and regrets people have. If people were content with themselves and their accomplishments, the world would be a kinder place. Self forgiveness can be a much more difficult task than forgiving others (since you can’t exactly put yourself behind you), but can reap the greatest benefits. &lt;em>Self forgiveness helps guide one’s life towards inner peace and self-love and away from a dependency on external stimuli (such as degrading others) for happiness.&lt;/em> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the best ways to help forgive yourself for shortcomings is to work on improving them. Hate how you look? Exercise! Hate being socially incompetent? Practice talking to people! The amount of effort you put into change doesn’t have to be significant, as long as it’s consistent. You should be able to say, “I don’t like this aspect of myself but that’s ok, because I’m taking steps to improve.” This will &lt;em>increase self-esteem&lt;/em> and thus &lt;em>increase happiness&lt;/em> in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An alternative to changing who you are is accepting your flaws. No one is perfect! This skill is difficult to master, but promotes loving who you are instead of trying to change into who you want to be. Self-acceptance doesn’t require you to change everything you despise about yourself, but also can lead to a life of mediocrity where you always settle for “good enough”. I find a bit of each mindset to be ideal—I try to improve the qualities I can control and accept the ones I can’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you hold self-resentment for past actions, try talking to a professional counselor/therapist! They are skilled at helping patients work through complex and specific issues. They suggest solutions you might not have thought of and call you out when you need it, making your problems much easier to tackle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recap--final-thoughts" >Recap &amp;amp; Final Thoughts
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#recap--final-thoughts">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Forgiveness means letting go of resentment, not justifying an action or person.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is easier to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is not stronger to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness increases confidence.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness improves communication.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness clears the mind.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness allows you to learn from others.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness in some aspects of life help you forgive in others.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forgiveness makes the world kinder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“I don’t like myself because I am inferior,” can turn into “I love myself because I’m trying to grow.”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“If only this didn’t happen,” can turn into “This happened, how do we respond?”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note that this writing isn’t citing scientific studies or telling anecdotes—it is presenting a set of ideas for the reader to consider. These beliefs do not cover the entire subject nor do they universally hold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Balance</title><link>/blog/balance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/balance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Choosing sides is fun. Be it politics or pop culture, nothing validates an opinion better than classifying opposing opinions as wrong. Sometimes, as seen by Holocaust deniers or the anti-vaccine movement, it&amp;rsquo;s possible people can be completely and utterly wrong. However, in the general case, both sides have merits and both sides have pitfalls. When trying to gain a perspective of the bigger picture, it&amp;rsquo;s best to position oneself somewhere in the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="this-versus-that" >This versus that
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#this-versus-that">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We live in a world with seven billion perspectives. Seven billion lifetimes of thought and contemplation. Of course, one cannot listen to every lifestory nor hear every person&amp;rsquo;s opinion. So we form into groups, with each important group representing something between the loudest minority or general majority of people with a particular set of opinions. This is a system able to properly distinguish emerging schools of thought while categorizing people into said schools, enabling people to efficiently organize, communicate, and compare ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This does not imply that everyone in a group has well formed opinions. Quite the opposite in fact &amp;ndash; these groups require people to give considerably less thought into their beliefs. Immersing oneself in a group for a few ideas can easily lead to naturally picking up other beliefs of the group, as many people will adapt for acceptance. This lower barrier to entry for taking sides is a core part of the conflict between groups, as society seems to reinforce beliefs by ridiculing opponents who don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand theirs &amp;ndash; consider the plethora of &amp;ldquo;Person X DESTROYS believer of Y&amp;rdquo; videos online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given a large enough group however, there tend to be many people who have given careful time and consideration into why they believe what they believe. Thus, one cannot simply sweep a prominent idea under the rug because of a few bad apples. To do so is to throw away ideas which stood the test of time and the people behind them. If proposed a ridiculous sounding idea, merely dismissing it without consideration denies you of a potentially meaningful realization. Instead of &amp;ldquo;No, that&amp;rsquo;s wrong&amp;rdquo;, all parties benefit more from &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; The pursuit of knowledge would have ended a long time ago if we dismissed everything we didn&amp;rsquo;t believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="entertaining-thoughts" >Entertaining Thoughts
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#entertaining-thoughts">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>An invaluable skill that many successful people have is the ability to play with an idea without accepting it. This is essential for multiple reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>By entertaining an idea, you can learn key takeaways from views that may appear ridiculous at first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can reinforce your beliefs by attempting (and failing) to convince yourself of an opposing view&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Additionally, many people are absolutely rubbish at laying out a convincing argument. Requiring the persuasion of other people to change your mind will result in your mind rarely being changed. Sometimes, the best person to convince you of something is in fact, you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts" >Final Thoughts
&lt;span>
&lt;a href="#final-thoughts">
&lt;svg viewBox="0 0 28 23" height="100%" width="19" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">&lt;path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71" fill="none" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-miterlimit="10" stroke-width="2"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit an idea based on the people proposing it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit a person based on the group they belong to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Doing so inhibits learning for both parties&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If someone can&amp;rsquo;t convince you of something, try convincing yourself&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is not a fully fleshed out idea of mine, nor is this idea exclusively mine. There are both counter arguments and room for expansion, however I think this is best left up to the reader.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>