<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on </title>
    <link>/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description> (Philosophy)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:21:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen in the Art of Beatsaber</title>
      <link>/blog/zen-in-the-art-of-beatsaber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:21:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/zen-in-the-art-of-beatsaber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contents: &lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#step-away-come-back-later&#34;&gt;Step away, come back later&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#focus-but-not-too-much&#34;&gt;Focus, but not too much&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#generalization-comes-after-specialization&#34;&gt;Generalization comes after specialization&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t bother if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#let-go&#34;&gt;Let Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34; &gt;Introduction
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_in_the_Art_of_Archery&#34;&gt;Zen in the Art of Archery&lt;/a&gt;, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a book about archery as much as it is a book about zen. The book describes author&amp;rsquo;s journey learning archery from a zen master. I highly recommend it, the book is a short read&amp;ndash;I finished it in a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My core takeaway, which fails to properly describe book, is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To master archery, the archer must first let go of their body and mind so they can be one with the art. This can only be achieved with an open mind through extensive practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was mesmerized by the dedication, personal growth and the zen-like state the author achieved throughout his journey. I wanted to try something similar but have neither materials for archery or a zen master. I do, however, have a VR headset and a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beatsaber.com/&#34;&gt;Beat Saber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/beatsaber/s/TSEdiDeJzk&#34;&gt;which can apparently induce a feeling of zen&lt;/a&gt;. I gave it a shot, silly as it seems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat Saber a game where you need to slice blocks in a specific direction to the beat of a song. The harder the level, the more notes you have to hit per second. If you miss too many notes within a short time span, you fail the song. For reference, here is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vXfw-fhmPc&#34;&gt;video of gameplay on an easier difficulty&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N6Y7ZgxeTUs&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;video of gameplay on harder difficulty&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_songs_in_Beat_Saber&#34;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of the songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial goal was to beat all ten songs in the first volume of the free soundtrack on the hardest difficulty, &lt;em&gt;Expert+&lt;/em&gt; (I also started this to get myself to exercise, but that&amp;rsquo;s less exciting). As someone who couldn&amp;rsquo;t beat a single medium difficulty song on &lt;em&gt;Guitar Hero 3&lt;/em&gt; as a child, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to beat anything on the hardest setting, let alone one that required physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you the hero&amp;rsquo;s journey: I beat all ten songs on &lt;em&gt;Expert+&lt;/em&gt; in a few weeks. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe my progress; I figured beating a single level would take me at least a month or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to push myself and beat all the songs in all six original soundtracks on &lt;em&gt;Expert+&lt;/em&gt;. Again, I figured the levels would get harder, and I&amp;rsquo;d spend weeks mastering some of the harder songs. They did get significantly harder, but I chiped away at all but the six fastest songs over the course of another few weeks, one song at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still no zen-master, but I wanted to share some lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, which I think can apply to lots of aspects of life. Take these with a grain of salt, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-away-come-back-later&#34; &gt;Step away, come back later
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#step-away-come-back-later&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The body naturally improves once you let it rest and process. I&amp;rsquo;d struggle with a song one night only to beat it on the first try the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-but-not-too-much&#34; &gt;Focus, but not too much
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#focus-but-not-too-much&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of restarting a failed song from the beginning, I relied on practice mode, which lets you start the song from any time. I drilled the sections I struggled with at lower speeds, ramping up the speed as I improved, eventually going back and beating the full song. Said in reverse, I wasted little time on the easy parts and made good use of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got tired of a song, I switched to one that I previously beat, but found that I rusted. Switching it up and reviewing things I previously mastered improved my general ability and allowed me to perform better when encountering a new song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;generalization-comes-after-specialization&#34; &gt;Generalization comes after specialization
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#generalization-comes-after-specialization&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my time drilling specific sequences of notes in certain songs, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t think would generalize well to other songs. While true to some extent, this practice helped me master patterns which would took similar forms elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the same principle applies to learning in general, at least for me. I learn better when I start from examples and experience. Only after a while do I obtain the subconscious instincts required to shift my attention from the specifics to the higher level abstractions. My growth as a programmer followed a similar path, and the same is true for chess grandmasters from what I hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to&#34; &gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t bother if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#dont-bother-if-you-dont-need-to&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During faster, less-intuitive sequences, I&amp;rsquo;d often fail because I attempted to hit every single note. I noticed that I&amp;rsquo;d usually go down-hill after making a few consecutive mistakes which threw me off. Instead of drilling these sequences to mastery, I realized I could flat-out ignore the few pain points that disrupted my flow without failing the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-go&#34; &gt;Let Go
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#let-go&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the songs got so fast that my conscious mind couldn&amp;rsquo;t process rapid sequences in time. These parts weren&amp;rsquo;t counter-intuitive or confusing like prior sequences I drilled, they were simply &lt;em&gt;too fast&lt;/em&gt;. I felt drilling these sequences wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help, no matter the speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy that eventually worked was &amp;ldquo;not thinking&amp;rdquo;, true to zen philosophy. For most of the song, I&amp;rsquo;d consciously process the notes and patterns as they came, but for the fastest sequences, I would clear my mind, and operate purely on instinct for a few seconds. This was perhaps the most surpising part of this journey&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;d often be able to land a perfect or near-perfect combo once my mind no longer got in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I plan on beating the remaining songs, and will update this post if/when I do. I did not expect this experiment to go anywhere, but I learned a surprising amount about myself, my learning process, and breaking my limits. With the exception of brief moments, I don&amp;rsquo;t experience a zen-like state when playing, but I do notice that I need to &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing significantly less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way of Zen</title>
      <link>/blog/the-way-of-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 15:49:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-way-of-zen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpts I found interesting from Alan Watt&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Way of Zen&lt;/em&gt;, grouped by vibes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#convention&#34;&gt;Convention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#feel&#34;&gt;Feel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#growing&#34;&gt;Growing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#spontaneity&#34;&gt;Spontaneity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#pointing&#34;&gt;Pointing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#ego&#34;&gt;Ego&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#interference&#34;&gt;Interference&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#present&#34;&gt;Present&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#negation&#34;&gt;Negation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#liberation&#34;&gt;Liberation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#za-zen&#34;&gt;Za-zen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#widespread&#34;&gt;Widespread&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#art&#34;&gt;Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition&#34; &gt;Definition
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#definition&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zen Buddhism is a way and a view of life which does not belong to any of the formal categories of modern Western thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As will soon be obvious, a way of liberation can have no positive definition. It has to be suggested by saying what it is not, somewhat as a sculptor reveals an image by the act of removing pieces of stone from a block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious reason for the lack of materials would be that a principle of this kind, so easily open to misinterpretation, might have been kept as a “secret doctrine,” discussed openly only in later times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zen points out that our precious “self” is just an idea, useful and legitimate enough if seen for what it is, but disastrous if identified with our real nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the famous saying of Ch’ing-yüan: Before I had studied Zen for thirty years, I saw mountains as mountains, and waters as waters. When I arrived at a more intimate knowledge, I came to the point where I saw that mountains are not mountains, and waters are not waters. But now that I have got its very substance I am at rest. For it’s just that I see mountains once again as mountains, and waters once again as waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remain caught up in ideas and words about Zen is, as the old masters say, to “stink of Zen.” For this reason the masters talk about Zen as little as possible, and throw its concrete reality straight at us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another master was having tea with two of his students when he suddenly tossed his fan to one of them, saying, “What’s this?” The student opened it and fanned himself. “Not bad,” was his comment. “Now you,” he went on, passing it to the other student, who at once closed the fan and scratched his neck with it. This done, he opened it again, placed a piece of cake on it, and offered it to the master. This was considered even better, for when there are no names the world is no longer “classified in limits and bounds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;convention&#34; &gt;Convention
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#convention&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have difficulty in communicating with each other unless we can identify ourselves in terms of roles–father, teacher, worker, artist, &amp;ldquo;regular guy,&amp;rdquo; gentleman, sportsman, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to convention, I am not simply what I am doing now. I am also what I have done, and my conventionally edited version of my past is made to seem almost more the real &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; than what I am at this moment. For what I am seems so fleeting and intangible, but what I was is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A philosophy restricted to the alternatives of conventional language has no way of conceiving an intelligence which does not work according to plan, according to a (one-at-atime) order of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To serve their purpose, names and terms must of necessity be &amp;ldquo;fixed and definite like all other units of measurement. But their use is–up to a point–so satisfactory that man is always in danger of confusing his measures with the world so measured, of identifying money with wealth, fixed convention with fluid reality. But to the degree that he identifies himself and his life with these rigid and hollow frames of definition, he condemns himself to the perpetual frustration of one trying to catch water in a sieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transitoriness is depressing only to the mind which insists upon trying to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are so accustomed to this convention in speaking and thinking that we fail to recognize that it is simply a convention, and that it does not necessarily correspond to the actual experience of knowing. Thus when we say, “A light flashed,” it is somewhat easier to see through the grammatical convention and to realize that the flashing is the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anxiety-laden problem of what will happen to me when I die is, after all, like asking what happens to my fist when I open my hand, or where my lap goes when I stand up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diffculty of making equations and comparisons between Eastern and Western ideas is that the two worlds do not start with the same assumptions and premises. They do not have the same basic categorizations of experience. When, therefore, the world has never been divided into mind and matter, but rather into mind and form, the word “mind” cannot mean quite the same thing in both instances. The word “man,” for example, does not have quite the same meaning when contrasted with “woman” as when contrasted with “animal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feel&#34; &gt;Feel
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#feel&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general tendency of the Western mind is to feel that we do not really understand what we cannot represent, what we cannot communicate, by linear signs–by thinking. We are like the “wallflower” who cannot learn a dance unless someone draws him a diagram of the steps, who cannot &amp;ldquo;get it by the feel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn music, for example, by restricting the whole range of tone and rhythm to a notation of fixed tonal and rhythmic intervals-a notation which is incapable of representing Oriental music. But the Oriental musician has a rough notation which he uses only as a reminder of a melody. He learns music, not by reading notes, but by listening to the performance of a teacher, getting the “feel” of it, and copying him, and this enables him to acquire rhythmic and tonal sophistications matched only by those Western jazz artists who use the same approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the greater part of our important decisions depend upon “hunch”- in other words, upon the “peripheral vision” of the mind. Thus the reliability of our decisions rests ultimately upon our ability to “feel” the situation, upon the degree to which this “peripheral vision” has been developed. Every exponent of the I Ching knows this. He knows that the book itself does not contain an exact science, but rather a useful tool which will work for him if he has a good “intuition,” or if, as he would say, he is “in the Tao.” Thus one does not consult the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing&#34; &gt;Growing
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#growing&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas God produces the worldby maklng (wei), the Tao produces it by “not makmg” (wu wei) which is approximately what we mean by &amp;ldquo;growing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the universe were made, there would of course be someone who knows how it is made-who could explain how it was put together bit by bit as a technician can explain in one-at-a-time words how to assemble a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the genuine &amp;ldquo;Zen flavor&amp;rdquo; is when a man is almost miraculously natural without intending to be so. His Zen life is not to make himself but to grow that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of time it may grow, but one does not blame an egg for not being a chicken; still less does one criticize a pig for having a shorter neck than a giraffe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he watches as a gardener watches the growth of a tree, and wants his student to have the attitude of the tree–the attitude of purposeless growth in which there are no short cuts because every stage of the way is both beginning and end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rinzai School has always forbidden the publication of formally acceptable answers to the various koan because the whole point of the discipline is to discover them for oneself, by intuition. To know the answers without having so discovered them would be like studying the map without taking the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese proverb “What comes in through the gate is not family treasure” is understood in Zen to mean that what someone else tells you is not your own knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spontaneity&#34; &gt;Spontaneity
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#spontaneity&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw that the I Ching had given the Chinese mind some experience in arriving at decisions spontaneously, decisions which are effective to the degree that one knows how to let one’s mind alone, trusting it to work by itself. This is wu-wei, since wu means “not” or “non-” and wei means “action,” “making,” “doing,” “striving,” “straining,” or “busyness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No amount of working with the muscles of the mouth and tongue will enable us to taste our food more acutely. The eyes and the tongue must be trusted to do the work by themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become unaffected;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cherish sincerity;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belittle the personal;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Lao Tzu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is not to reduce the human mind to a moronic vacuity, but to bring into play its innate and spontaneous intelligence by using it without forcing it. It is fundamental to both Taoist and Confucian thought that the natural man is to be trusted, and from their standpoint it appears that the Western mistrust of human nature–whether theological or technological–is a kind of schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a man has learned to let his mind alone so that it functions in the integrated and spontaneous way that is natural to it, he begins to show the special kind of “virtue” or “power” called te. This is not virtue in the current sense of moral rectitude but in the older sense of effectiveness, as when one speaks of the healing virtues of a plant[&amp;hellip;] Te is the unthinkable ingenuity and creative power of man’s spontaneous and natural functioning–a power which is blocked when one tries to master it in terms of formal methods and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nirvana can only arise unintentionally, spontaneously, when the impossibility of selfgrasping has been thoroughly perceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctrine of the Dharmadhatu is, approximately, that the proper harmony of the universe is realized when each “thing-event” is allowed to be freely and spontaneously itself, without interference. Stated more subjectively, it is saying, “Let everything be free to be just as it is. Do not separate yourself from the world and try to order it around.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Six Precepts&amp;rdquo; of Tilopa: No thought, no reflection, no analysis, No cultivation, no intention; Let it settle itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–that truly to know is not to know, that the awakened mind responds immediately, without calculation, and that there is no incompatibility between Buddhahood and the everyday life of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was the first to answer questions about Buddhism by hitting the questioner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We feel that our actions are voluntary when they follow a decision, and involuntary when they happen without decision. But if decision itself were voluntary, every decision would have to be preceded by a decision to decide–an infinite regression which fortunately does not occur. Oddly enough, if we had to decide to decide, we would not be free to decide. We are free to decide because decision “happens.” We just decide without having the faintest understanding of how we do it. In fact, it is neither voluntary nor involuntary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The master may begin a conversation with the student by asking a series of very ordinary questions about trivial matters, to which the student responds with perfect spontaneity. But suddenly he will say, “When the bath-water flows down the drain, does it turn clockwise or counter-clockwise?” As the student stops at the unexpectedness of the question, and perhaps tries to remember which way it goes, the master shouts, “Don’t think! Act! This way–” and whirls his hand in the air. Or, perhaps less helpfully, he may say, “So far you’ve answered my questions quite naturally and easily, but where’s your difficulty now?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of mo chih ch’u is not to eliminate reflective thought but to eliminate “blocking” in both action and thought, so that the response of the mind is always like a ball in a mountain stream-“one thought after another without hesitation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet this is why the Western mind is dismayed when ordered conceptions of the universe break down, and when the basic behavior of the physical world is found to be a “principle of uncertainty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is true in learning to use the brush for writing or painting. The brush must draw by itself. This cannot happen if one does not practice constantly. But neither can it happen if one makes an effort. Similarly, in swordsmanship one must not first decide upon a certain thrust and then attempt to make it, since by that time it will be too late. Decision and action must be simultaneous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use the imagery of a Tibetan poem, every action, every event comes of itself from the Void “as from the surface of a clear lake there leaps suddenly a fish.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pointing&#34; &gt;Pointing
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#pointing&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus from the standpoint of Zen the Buddha “never said a word,” despite the volumes of scriptures attributed to him. For his real message remained always unspoken, and was such that, when words attempted to express it, they made it seem as if it were nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it is the essential tradition of Zen that what cannot be conveyed by speech can nevertheless be passed on by “direct pointing,” by some nonverbal means of communication without which the Buddhist experience could never have been handed down to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its own (probably rather late) tradition, Zen maintains that the Buddha transmitted awakening to his chief disciple, Mahakasyapa, by holding up a flower and remaining silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic position of Zen is that it has nothing to say, nothing to teach. The truth of Buddhism is so self-evident, so obvious that it is, if anything, concealed by explaining it. Therefore the master does not “help” the student in any way, since helping would actually be hindering. On the contrary, he goes out of his way to put obstacles and barriers in the student’s path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ego&#34; &gt;Ego
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ego&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fundamental to every school of Buddhism that there is no ego, no enduring entity which is the constant subject of our changing experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can, for example, imagine the path of a bird through the sky as a distinct line which it has taken. But this line is as abstract as a line of latitude. In concrete reality, the bird left no line, and, similarly, the past from which our ego is abstracted has entirely disappeared. Thus any attempt to cling to the ego or to make it an effective source of action is doomed to frustration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, too, lies the basis of the Buddhism of faith, of the Sukhavati or Pure Land school, in which it is held that all efforts to become a Buddha are merely the false pride of the ego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is often a deceptive resemblance between opposite extremes. Lunatics frequently resemble saints, and the unaffected modesty of the sage often lets him seem to be a very ordinary person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why the sage Fa-yung received no more offerings of flowers from the birds after he had had his interview with the Fourth Patriarch, for his holiness no longer “stood out like a sore thumb.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one notices him because he does not notice himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So often one thinks of the saint as a man whose sincerity provokes the enmity of the world, but Ryokan holds the distinction of being the saint whom everyone loved–perhaps because he was natural, again as a child, rather than good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interference&#34; &gt;Interference
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#interference&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, however, cannot quite be compressed into the sweeping assertion that “life is suffering.” The point is rather that life as we usually live it is suffering-or, more exactly, is bedeviled by the peculiar frustration which comes from attempting the impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man is involved in karma when he interferes with the world in such a way that he is compelled to go on interfering, when the solution of a problem creates still more problems to be solved, when the control of one thing creates the need to control several others. Karma is thus the fate of everyone who “tries to be God.” He lays a trap for the world in which he himself gets caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This nonduality of the mind, in which it is no longer divided against itself, is samadhi, and because of the disappearance of that fruitless threshing around of the mind to grasp itself, samadhi is a state of profound peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, not exterminating the passions does not mean letting them flourish untamed. It means letting go of them rather than fighting them, neither repressing passion nor indulging it. For the Taoist is never violent, since he achieves his ends by noninterference (wu-wei), which is a kind of psychological judo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To concentrate on the mind and to contemplate it until it is still is a disease and not dhyana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the principle that “the true mind is no-mind,” and that “our true nature is no (special) nature,” it is likewise stressed that the true practice of Zen is no practice, that is, the seeming paradox of being a Buddha without intending to be a Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no place in Buddhism for using effort. Just be ordinary and nothing special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas the koan advocates used this technique as a means for encouraging that overwhelming “feeling of doubt” which they felt to be essential as a prerequisite for satori, the Soto School argued that it lent itself too easily to that very seeking for satori which thrusts it away, or–what is worse–induces an artificial satori.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temptation is all the stronger because it upsets the fondest illusion of the human mind, which is that in the course of time everything may be made better and better. For it is the general opinion that were this not possible the life of man would lack all meaning and incentive. The only alternative to a life of constant progress is felt to be a mere existence, static and dead, so joyless and inane that one might as well commit suicide. The very notion of this “only alternative” shows how firmly the mind is bound in a dualistic pattern, how hard it is to think in any other terms than good or bad, or a muddy mixture of the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To succeed is always to fail–in the sense that the more one succeeds in anything, the greater is the need to go on succeeding. To eat is to survive to be hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently the whole notion of getting something “out” of life, of seeking something “from” experience, becomes absurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, Zen begins at the point where there is nothing further to seek, nothing to be gained. Zen is most emphatically not to be regarded as a system of self-improvement, or a way of becoming a Buddha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the effort to remain always “good” or “happy” is like trying to hold the thermostat to a constant 70 degrees by making the lower limit the same as the upper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the Taoist mentality, the aimless, empty life does not suggest anything depressing. On the contrary, it suggests the freedom of clouds and mountain streams, wandering nowhere, of flowers in impenetrable canyons, beautiful for no one to see, and of the ocean surf forever washing the sand, to no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the superficiality of this consciousness is seen in the fact that it cannot and does not regulate even the human organism. For if it had to control the heartbeat, the breath, the operation of the nerves, glands, muscles, and sense organs, it would be rushing wildly around the body taking care of one thing after another, with no time to do anything else. Happily, it is not in charge, and the organism is regulated by the timeless “original mind,” which deals with life in its totality and so can do ever so many “things” at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear sight has nothing to do with trying to see; it is just the realization that the eyes will take in every detail all by themselves, for so long as they are open one can hardly prevent the light from reaching them. In the same way, there is no di8culty in being fully aware of the eternal present as soon as it is seen that one cannot possibly be aware of anything else–that in concrete fact there is no past or future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;present&#34; &gt;Present
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#present&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it is one-pointed in the sense of being focused on the present, since to clear awareness there is neither past nor future, but just this one moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way Dogen pointed out that firewood does not become ashes and life does not become death, just as the winter does not become the spring. Every moment of time is “self-contained and quiescent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Po-chang is attributed the famous definition of Zen, “When hungry, eat; when tired, sleep.” For when asked about seeking for the Buddha nature he answered, “It’s much like riding an ox in search of the ox.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogen is here trying to express the strange sense of timeless moments which arises when one is no longer trying to resist the flow of events, the peculiar stillness and self-sufficiency of the succeeding instants when the mind is, as it were, going along with them and not trying to arrest them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Zen poem says:
The morning glory which blooms for an hour
Differs not at heart from the giant pine,
Which lives for a thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, the measuring of worth and success in terms of time, and the insistent demand for assurances of a promising future, make it impossible to live freely both in the present and in the “promising” future when it arrives. For there is never anything but the present, and if one cannot live there, one cannot live anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a philosophy of not looking where one is going; it is a philosophy of not making where one is going so much more important than where one is that there will be no point in going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is told of a Zen monk who wept upon hearing of the death of a close relative. When one of his fellow students objected that it was most unseemly for a monk to show such personal attachment he replied, “Don’t be stupid! I’m weeping because I want to weep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The silence which prevails is deepened rather than broken by occasional sounds that float up from a near-by village, by the intermittent ringing of soft-toned bells from other parts of the monastery, and by the chatter of birds in the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zen masters are quite human. They get sick and die; they know joy and sorrow; they have bad tempers or other little “weaknesses” of character just like anyone else, and they are not above falling in love and entering into a fully human relationship with the opposite sex. The perfection of Zen is to be perfectly and simply human. The difference of the adept in Zen from the ordinary run of men is that the latter are, in one way or another, at odds with their own humanity, and are attempting to be angels or demons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It hurries on and on, and misses everything. Not hurrying, the purposeless life misses nothing, for it is only when there is no goal and no rush that the human senses are fully open to receive the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aware is not quite grief, and not quite nostalgia in the usual sense of longing for the return of a beloved past. Aware is the echo of what has passed and of what was loved, giving them a resonance such as a great cathedral gives to a choir, so that they would be the poorer without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zen has no goal; it is a traveling without point, with nowhere to go. To travel is to be alive, but to get somewhere is to be dead, for as our own proverb says, “To travel well is better than to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A world which increasingly consists of destinations without journeys between them, a world which values only “getting somewhere” as fast as possible, becomes a world without substance. One can get anywhere and everywhere, and yet the more this is possible, the less is anywhere and everywhere worth getting to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if we open our eyes and see clearly, it becomes obvious that there is no other time than this instant, and that the past and the future are abstractions without any concrete reality. Until this has become clear, it seems that our life is all past and future, and that the present is nothing more than the in-nitesimal hairline which divides them. From this comes the sensation of “having no time,” of a world which hurries by so rapidly that it is gone before we can enjoy it. But through “awakening to the instant” one sees that this is the reverse of the truth: it is rather the past and future which are the ,eeting illusions, and the present which is eternally real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Takuan and Bankei stressed the fact that the “original” or “unborn” mind is constantly working miracles even in the most ordinary person. Even though a tree has innumerable leaves, the mind takes them in all at once without being “stopped” by any one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had surpassed all the other disciples and Bodhisattvas by answering a question as to the nature of the nondual reality with a “thunderous silence”–an example frequently followed by Zen masters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;negation&#34; &gt;Negation
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#negation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at the conventional level it is surely easy to see that knowing what is not so is often quite as important as knowing what is [&amp;hellip;] Furthermore, the function of negative knowledge is not unlike the uses of space–the empty page upon which words can be written, the empty jar into which liquid can be poured, the empty window through which light can be admitted, and the empty pipe through which water can flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, when Hindu and Buddhist texts speak of the “empty” or “illusory” character of the visible world of nature–as distinct from the conventional world of things–they refer precisely to the impermanence of its forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the greater part of Nagarjuna’s work was a carefully logical and systematic refutation of every philosophical position to be found in the India of his time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must therefore be repeated that the negations apply, not to reality itself, but to our ideas of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awakening is to know what reality is not. It is to cease identifying oneself with any object of knowledge whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;liberation&#34; &gt;Liberation
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#liberation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Taoism must on no account be understood as a revolution
against convention, although it has sometimes been used as a
pretext for revolution. Taoism is a way of liberation, which never
comes by means of revolution, since it is notorious that most
revolutions establish worse tyrannies than they destroy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Patriarch, following Seng-ts’an, is believed to have been Tao-hsin. When he came to Seng-ts’an he asked, “What is the method of liberation?” “Who binds you?” replied Seng-ts’an. “No one binds me.” “Why then,” asked Seng-ts’an, “should you seek liberation?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True dhyana is to realize that one’s own nature is like space, and that thoughts and sensations come and go in this “original mind” like birds through the sky, leaving no trace. Awakening, in his school, is “sudden” because it is for quickwitted rather than slow-witted people. The latter must of necessity understand gradually, or more exactly, after a long time, since the Sixth Patriarch’s doctrine does not admit of stages or growth. To be awakened at all is to be awakened completely, for, having no parts or divisions, the Buddha nature is not realized bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;za-zen&#34; &gt;Za-zen
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#za-zen&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following story is told of Huai-jang, initiating into Zen his great successor Ma-tsu, who was at the time practicing sitting meditation at the monastery of Ch’uan-fa. “Your reverence,” asked Huai-jang, “what is the objective of sitting in meditation?” “The objective,” answered Ma-tsu, “is to become a Buddha.” Thereupon Huai-jang picked up a floor-tile and began to polish it on a rock. “What are you doing, master?” asked Ma-tsu. “I am polishing it for a mirror,” said Huai-jang. “How could polishing a tile make a mirror?” “How could sitting in meditation make a Buddha?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it could be assumed that the type of za-zen under criticism is za-zen practiced for a purpose, to “get” Buddhahood, instead of “sitting just to sit.” There is, of course, a proper place for sitting–along with standing, walking, and lying–but to imagine that sitting contains some special virtue is “attachment to form.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet however much za-zen may have been exaggerated in the Far East, a certain amount of “sitting just to sit” might well be the best thing in the world for the jittery minds and agitated bodies of Europeans and Americans–provided they do not use it as a method for turning themselves into Buddhas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the West has its own contemplative tradition in the Catholic Church, the life of “sitting and looking” has lost its appeal, for no religion is valued which does not “improve the world,” and it is hard to see how the world can be improved by keeping still. Yet it should be obvious that action without wisdom, without clear awareness of the world as it really is, can never improve anything. Furthermore, as muddy water is best cleared by leaving it alone, it could be argued that those who sit quietly and do nothing are making one of the best possible contributions to a world in turmoil. There is, indeed, nothing unnatural in long periods of quiet sitting. Cats do it; even dogs and other more nervous animals do it. So-called primitive peoples do it–American Indians, and peasants of almost all nations. The art is most diffcult for those who have developed the sensitive intellect to such a point that they cannot help making predictions about the future, and so must be kept in a constant whirl of activity to forestall them. But it would seem that to be incapable of sitting and watching with the mind completely at rest is to be incapable of experiencing the world in which we live to the full&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just as there is no need to try to be in accord with the Tao, to try to see, or to try to hear, so it must be remembered that the breath will always take care of itself. This is not a breathing “exercise” so much as a “watching and letting” of the breath, and it is always a serious mistake to undertake it in the spirit of a compulsive discipline to be “practiced” with a goal in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;every human activity can become a form of za-zen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late Dr. Kunihiko Hashida, a lifelong student of Zen and editor of the works of Dogen, never used formal za-zen. But his “Zen practice” was precisely his study of physics, and to suggest his attitude he used to say that his lifework was “to science” rather than “to study science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;widespread&#34; &gt;Widespread
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#widespread&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confucianism, in other words, preoccupies itself with conventional
knowledge, and under its auspices children are brought up so that
their originally wayward and whimsical natures are made to fit the
Procrustean bed of the social order. The individual defines himself
and his place in society in terms of the Confucian formulae.
Taoism, on the other hand, is generally a pursuit of older men,
and especially of men who are retiring from active life in the
community. Their retirement from society is a kind of outward
symbol of an inward liberation from the bounds of conventional
patterns of thought and conduct. For Taoism concerns itself with
unconventional knowledge. with the understanding of life directly.
&amp;hellip;Confucianism presides, then, over the socially necessary task of
forcing the original spontaneity of life into the rigid rules of
convention-a task which involves not only conflict and pain, but
also the loss of that peculiar naturalness and un-self-consciousness
for which little children are so much loved, and which is sometimes
regained by saints and sages. The function of Taoism is to undo the
inevitable damage of this discipline, and not only to restore but also
to develop the original spontaneity, which is termed tzu-jan or
“self-so-ness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popularity almost invariably leads to a deterioration of quality, and as Zen became less of an informal spiritual movement and more of a settled institution, it underwent a curious change of character. It became necessary to “standardize” its methods and to find means for the masters to handle students in large numbers&amp;hellip;For the Zen community became less an association of mature men with spiritual interests, and more of an ecclesiastical boarding school for adolescent boys. Under such circumstances the problem of discipline became paramount. The Zen masters were forced to concern themselves not only with the way of liberation from convention, but also with the instilling of convention, of ordinary manners and morals, in raw youths. The mature Western student who discovers an interest in Zen as a philosophy or as a way of liberation must be careful to keep this in mind, for otherwise he may be unpleasantly startled by monastic Zen as it exists today in Japan. He will find that Zen is a discipline enforced with the big stick. He will find that, although it is still an effective way of liberation at its “upper end,” its main preoccupation is with a disciplinary regimen which “trains character” in the same way as the old-fashioned British public school or the Jesuit novitiate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one of the main objects of this work was to establish a proper “apostolic succession” for the Zen tradition, so that no one could claim authority unless his satori had been approved by someone who had been approved &amp;hellip; right back to the time of the Buddha himself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing, however, is more difficult than establishing proper qualifications in the imponderable realm of spiritual insight. Where the candidates are few the problem is not so grave, but where one master is responsible for some hundreds of students the process of teaching and testing requires standardization. Zen solved this problem with remarkable ingenuity, employing a means which not only provided a test of competence but–what was much more–a means of transmitting the Zen experience itself with a minimum of falsification. This extraordinary invention was the system of the kung-an ee (Japanese, koan) or “Zen problem.” Literally, this term means a “public document” or “case” in the sense of a decision creating a legal precedent. Thus the koan system involves “passing” a series of tests based on the mondo or anecdotes of the old masters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;art&#34; &gt;Art
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#art&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in painting, the work of art is considered not only as representing nature but as being itself a work of nature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you paint it is the brush, ink, and paper which determine the result as much as your own hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since writing and poetry were among the chief preoccupations of Chinese scholars, and since the Chinese way of painting is closely akin to writing, the roles of scholar, artist, and poet were not widely separated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the touch of the brush is so light and fluid, and since it must move continuously over the absorbent paper if the ink is to flow out regularly, its control requires a free movement of the hand and arm as if one were dancing rather than writing on paper. In short, it is a perfect instrument for the expression of unhesitating spontaneity, and a single stroke is enough to “give away” one’s character to an experienced observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most striking features of the Sung landscape, as of sumi-e as a whole, is the relative emptiness of the picture–an emptiness which appears, however, to be part of the painting and not just unpainted background. By filling in just one corner, the artist makes the whole area of the picture alive. Ma-yüan, in particular, was a master of this technique, which amounts almost to “painting by not painting,” or what Zen sometimes calls “playing the string-less lute.” The secret lies in knowing how to balance form with emptiness and, above all, in knowing when one has “said” enough. For Zen spoils neither the aesthetic shock nor the satori shock by filling in, by explanation, second thoughts, and intellectual commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Western eye is immediately struck by the absence of symmetry in these paintings, by the consistent avoidance of regular and geometrical shapes, whether straight or curved. For the characteristic brush line is jagged, gnarled, irregularly twisting, dashing, or sweeping–always spontaneous rather than predictable. Even when the Zen monk or artist draws a solitary circle-one of the most common themes of zenga–it is not only slightly eccentric and out of shape, but the very texture of the line is full of life and verve with the incidental splashes and gaps of the “rough brush.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the non-Japanese listener must remember that a good haiku is a pebble thrown into the pool of the listener’s mind, evoking associations out of the richness of his own memory. It invites the listener to participate instead of leaving him dumb with admiration while the poet shows off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when robbed he is still rich, for:
The thief
Left it behind
The moon at the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were always sparing and reserved in their use of color, as were the Sung painters before them, since masses of flowers in sharply varying colors are seldom found in the state of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herrigel spent almost five years trying to find the right way of releasing the bowstring, for it had to be done “unintentionally,” in the same way as a ripe fruit bursts its skin&amp;hellip; After all those years of practice there came a day when it just happened–how, or why, Herrigel never understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artificial haiku always feels like a piece of life which has been deliberately broken off or wrenched away from the universe, whereas the genuine haiku has dropped off all by itself, and has the whole universe inside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point, therefore, of these arts is the doing of them rather than the accomplishments. But, more than this, the real joy of them lies in what turns up unintentionally in the course of practice, just as the joy of travel is not nearly so much in getting where one wants to go as in the unsought surprises which occur on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uninformed Or Misinformed?</title>
      <link>/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/would-you-rather-be-uninformed-or-misinformed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it better to have no facts about a topic and thus no opinion, or have access to a few &amp;ldquo;out of context&amp;rdquo; facts and thus a misinformed opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t be well-informed on every topic; It&amp;rsquo;s just not possible. That&amp;rsquo;s why world leaders have advisers. Yet somehow, if you look at anyone&amp;rsquo;s Facebook account, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to try too hard to figure out their view on any political issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to realize how much nuance there is to the headlines we see. When I read an article that ruins the image of a company or individual, I always wonder: What information could the author be omitting? What view could the other side have? What outside information is the author conveniently using to make a point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to avoid getting emotional until these questions are answered. I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of having basic gut feelings on unfamiliar topics, but these feelings aren&amp;rsquo;t strong enough to start an argument. I talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m informed about, and listen (with a grain of salt) to others talk about issues I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for lots of us. Instead of admitting we are uninformed, many of us form an opinion after we read the headline, and most likely don&amp;rsquo;t update it after skimming the article with said headline. We are even less likely to look for an opposing take, as that requires we scroll outside of whatever feed we are browsing through. Some people don&amp;rsquo;t even use the news to form opinions: They just accept the opinions of their friends or family as &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;. As someone who accepted the outcome of the 2020 presidential election without looking into the claims of fraud, I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of this too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then take this opinion that a) isn&amp;rsquo;t ours and b) took less than 10 seconds to form, and carry it into the foreseeable future, not even considering the idea that there might be more we don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with admitting that we don&amp;rsquo;t know enough to judge a topic or event? Do we really think we have enough context and facts to make sound judgements on all our beliefs? Do we really need to hold an opinion after every scandal? Why can&amp;rsquo;t we just say &amp;ldquo;This is a side of a story&amp;rdquo; and move on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/03/timnit-gebru-google-fired/&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s firing of Timnit Gebru&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a headline about Google firing a researcher that criticized the company on a mailing list. I didn&amp;rsquo;t need about any more drama in my life, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t read further, tucking this away in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google responded with something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;she was using an email list in such a way that was improper for her position&amp;rdquo;. I still didn&amp;rsquo;t need the drama, so I kept it in my mind as &amp;ldquo;researcher fired from Google&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still hold no strong positions on this specific topic and don&amp;rsquo;t plan on learning more about it. Like in most &amp;ldquo;scandals&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;he said, she said&amp;rdquo; going on, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time figuring out who is right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to hold an opinion on this event, I&amp;rsquo;d need the following details to start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code of conduct for Gebru&amp;rsquo;s position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other alternative methods Gebru could have used not in violation of the Code of Conduct if her actions violated it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The contents of the email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbose arguments from both sides refuting each other&amp;rsquo;s points if possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence of Gebru&amp;rsquo;s claims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who does not work at nor plans to work at Google, this just isn&amp;rsquo;t worth my time, so I don&amp;rsquo;t form an opinion. There are other things to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR (again): Either start learning about issues you care about, or stop caring about them so much. It&amp;rsquo;s more honest, less mental effort, and is less likely to ruin Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Rules</title>
      <link>/blog/soft-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/soft-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not all rules are made equal. Some rules, like the speed limit, are broken by everyone and their mother, and are enforced (mostly) when people are breaking them to a dangerous point. Other rules, like &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t murder people&amp;rdquo;, are enforced far more. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-rules-different-tools&#34; &gt;Different Rules, Different Tools
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#different-rules-different-tools&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules are in place to assign blame to someone with bad judgement. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing morally wrong with jaywalking when there are no cars coming, but you are at fault if you walk into oncoming traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules are in place to discourage bad habits from forming, like the drinking age. This law is so commonly broken that it&amp;rsquo;s expected behavior at this point, and yet I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen someone get arrested for under-age drinking. Despite this, the law conveys the dangers of drinking, makes it harder for minors to acquire alcohol, and prevents students from openly sharing alcohol in schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules, like mandatory attendance, exist to get people to show up to an event or perform an activity. Even when attendance isn&amp;rsquo;t taken, many people will still show up to prevent unnecessary trouble. College orientation activities are a prime example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some rules exist simply because they haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated. Before 2020, some companies &amp;ndash; especially older ones &amp;ndash; didn&amp;rsquo;t allow employees to work from home. Working from home was seen as an unnecessary risk by upper management with no tangible benefit to any of the executives. Along comes the coronavirus, and suddenly the jobs people have been doing in an office for decades are suddenly doable from home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-for-rules&#34; &gt;Rules for Rules
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rules-for-rules&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rules should be justified. If a sign on a fish tank says, &lt;em&gt;PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS&lt;/em&gt;, do you think most people, especially children, are likely to obey? Does your answer change if the sign were to say &lt;em&gt;PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH GLASS, IT SCARES THE FISH&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too many rules, even if they are justified. The more rules in place, the less likely people will follow them. Just think about it: If Moses received 206 commandments, do you think his followers would view &lt;em&gt;Thou shalt not eat meat and dairy&lt;/em&gt; with the same level of respect as &lt;em&gt;Thou shalt not kill&lt;/em&gt;? More rules can imply that there are strict guidelines to be followed, but people will interpret them as: &lt;em&gt;Whoever came up with this must be fun at parties.&lt;/em&gt; Unnecessary rules draw attention away from the important ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrapping-up-rules&#34; &gt;Wrapping Up Rules
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#wrapping-up-rules&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no rule expert. Nevertheless, I recognize that creating and selectively enforcing rules is a valuable skill, for both policy-makers and policy-enforcers alike. If you want people to respect your rules, make sure they have a reason for being there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Thinking</title>
      <link>/blog/critical-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/critical-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more I learn about the world, the less certain I become about it. There are so many conflicting views and information taken out of context that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to discern fact from truth. Below are some notes I keep to help navigate the sea of information that is modern society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Don&amp;rsquo;t get fooled by facts if they have no context, don&amp;rsquo;t discount an opinion because it&amp;rsquo;s biased, and hear out crazy ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-skeptical-fact--truth&#34; &gt;Be skeptical: Fact != Truth
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#be-skeptical-fact--truth&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are facts available for virtually anything you need. No matter what argument you try to make, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to find a statistic that can back up your claims thanks to the glory of Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3030983/The-ultra-competitive-exercise-fad-ruin-health-called-planking-suddenly-sweeping-gyms-Pilates-classes.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did you know that planking can ruin your health and result in months of pain?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifehack.org/292578/7-things-that-will-happen-when-you-do-planking-exercise-every-day&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not true, planking works out multiple muscles in your body and can greatly improve your health if done daily&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not exactly scientific sources, but I think this demonstrates my point. Furthermore, the level of mixed information increases exponentially as the topic gets more political.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facts should never be enough to prove a point, and I tend to suspect people who rely too heavily on them. Facts should instead be used to tell a narrative; facts are not the truth, but they can light the way towards it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ewarren/status/1090252713156403200&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The top 0.1% &amp;hellip; own about the same wealth as the bottom 90% of America.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While deemed &amp;ldquo;Mostly True&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2019/jan/31/elizabeth-warren/warren-top-01-own-about-much-bottom-90/&#34;&gt;Politifact.com&lt;/a&gt;, this statement in isolation is less than useless: it&amp;rsquo;s misleading. On it&amp;rsquo;s own, this fact paints a picture of a grim society, where the bottom 90% are left to struggle for survival, with all resources being held for a greedy few. If you are in the bottom 90%, this prompts you to believe that life is unfair, and that this should be changed. That&amp;rsquo;s why this statistic is so popular, it seems outrageous and gives Americans a sense of justified anger at the rich, an anger which many ex-presidential candidates used to garner support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break this idea down a bit. The greedy elite factoid on its own implies nothing about quality of life, standard of living, financial responsibility, or determination to work. Society could be a paradise where everyone has access to more than they could ever need, and the top 0.1% just has an absurd amount of money. Or society could be a system of addiction, where the bottom 90% are constantly spending money on things they don&amp;rsquo;t need and the top 0.1% simply aren&amp;rsquo;t addicted and save/invest wisely. The truth is, these numbers don&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything about the truth, and aren&amp;rsquo;t being used to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a narrative discussing the implications of this statistic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wealth_inequality_in_the_United_States#Effect_on_democracy&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2014 study by researchers at Princeton and Northwestern concludes that government policies reflect the desires of the wealthy, and that the vast majority of American citizens have &amp;ldquo;minuscule, near-zero, statistically non-significant impact upon public policy … when a majority of citizens disagrees with economic elites and/or with organized interests, they generally lose.&amp;rdquo; When Fed chair Janet Yellen was questioned by Bernie Sanders about the study at a congressional hearing in May 2014, she responded &amp;ldquo;There’s no question that we’ve had a trend toward growing inequality&amp;rdquo; and that this trend &amp;ldquo;can shape [and] determine the ability of different groups to participate equally in a democracy and have grave effects on social stability over time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people know about inequality, but not what it means for them. The wealth statistic means nothing in a vaccuum, only in context does it hold any value. If facts are used to invoke emotion instead of prove a point, be skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased&#34; &gt;Worth Listening to those who are biased?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#worth-listening-to-those-who-are-biased&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A girl in a class of mine had a laptop sticker that read &amp;ldquo;Why be racist, sexist, or transphobic when you can just be quiet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t stand this type of thinking. It&amp;rsquo;s elitist, tells people with controversial views to not let their voice be heard, and contributes to the echo chamber of modern society. Furthermore, it accomplishes nothing except a pat on the back for people with her mindset. No racist is actually going to read that and go &amp;ldquo;Oh, guess I just won&amp;rsquo;t speak my mind then.&amp;rdquo; In fact, they might be driven further into racism in spite. Nobody likes being talked down to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of insight to be gained on both sides from listening to people with views you don&amp;rsquo;t like. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think white supremacists are evil and don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to speak; its harder to realize they have a reason for their beliefs. If you want to make the world a better place, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from silence, but from understanding. When fighting racism, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it make sense to understand where racists are coming from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss tax law, you should hear out the rich guy that wants lower taxes just as much as the working class American who wants the same. If you want to discuss diversity, don&amp;rsquo;t limit the white participants to those with an &amp;ldquo;anti-white&amp;rdquo; mindset. These perspectives are essential to promoting an open dialogue, and leaving out those with biased opinions leads to toxic echo chambers and a mentality of &amp;ldquo;us versus them&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hear-out-the-crazy&#34; &gt;Hear out the crazy
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#hear-out-the-crazy&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I experimented with fasting, a few people I knew were opposed. The concept of not eating for days on end? Ridiculous! Your body needs food, your metabolism will slow to a halt if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These arguments didn&amp;rsquo;t come from any sort of reading on the subject, but human intuition. The concept of not eating for a few days went against everything they knew; to them it was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fasting isn&amp;rsquo;t actually bad for you if done right, and can have &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fasting#Health_effects&#34;&gt;numerous health benefits&lt;/a&gt;. A simple Google search into the subject could have cleared up these misconceptions. But that would imply that this ridiculous idea could have some merit worth looking for. It&amp;rsquo;s like looking up &amp;ldquo;Did the Holocaust happen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to most domains however, there is usually some fascinating logic behind crazy ideas. Bitcoin comes to mind; a currency without a government to back it seems completely absurd on the surface. The gut reaction is to call Bitcoin a fraud, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/01/09/jamie-dimon-says-he-regrets-calling-bitcoin-a-fraud.html&#34;&gt;but when the best in the business take some time to think about it, they might have second thoughts&lt;/a&gt;. The Bitcoin community is full of brilliant people that built the foundation of blockchain technology. It&amp;rsquo;s worth hearing them out, even if their ideas seem a bit crazy at first glance. They must have their reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the news cycle continues to speed up, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to determine fact from fiction, who&amp;rsquo;s crazy and who&amp;rsquo;s biased, what&amp;rsquo;s conspiracy and what&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to listen to everyone, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t only listen to those with a similar mindset. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get the full story for every topic of discussion, but don&amp;rsquo;t fall for out-of-context information. Question everything, but keep an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness</title>
      <link>/blog/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some thoughts on Happiness:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from wealth. Otherwise, therapists and anti-depressants would have to be much cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If happiness came from consumption of goods and services, it would therefore follow that once those goods and services are reduced or cut off, one would no longer be as happy. If you can cut off happiness, it&amp;rsquo;s more akin to a drug than an emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2017/04/over-nearly-80-years-harvard-study-has-been-showing-how-to-live-a-healthy-and-happy-life/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Close relationships, more than money or fame, are what keep people happy throughout their lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; While financial security is ideal for easing pain and suffering, significant amounts of money can strain relationships and cast doubt on who your friends really are. If solid relationships are a path to happiness, the drama and expectations caused from wealth differences in the relationships might very well block that path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, happiness isn&amp;rsquo;t something you can obtain, but something you become. True happiness has to come from within to be strong and sustainable. Performing work you find meaningful, engaging in relationships of substance, and living a life of virtue are all ways to approach happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness can&amp;rsquo;t come from believing you are the smartest, most attractive, or funniest person in your social circles. If it does, you either aren&amp;rsquo;t around people you can learn from or are living in a world of illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If stressed about all those that are above you, happiness is possible if you enjoy the process of learning and take pride in trying your best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s possible to be a masterpiece and a work in progress at the same time.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain and happiness are not mutually exclusive, but rather two sides of the same coin. The greatest pains can come from the greatest happiness, such as the loss of a loved one. Some of the greatest happiness comes from the greatest pain, such as starting new relationships after others have ended. The most painful moments can sometimes fuel transitions into the best ones. Don&amp;rsquo;t let pain go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.health.harvard.edu/healthbeat/giving-thanks-can-make-you-happier&#34;&gt;One of the best ways to increase happiness is to show gratitude.&lt;/a&gt; When expressing thanks for what you have instead of longing for what you don&amp;rsquo;t, you learn to draw happiness from yourself instead of the high of getting something new. If you were to lose that for which you are thankful, the situation doesn&amp;rsquo;t change &amp;ndash; draw gratitude from what&amp;rsquo;s left.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness</title>
      <link>/blog/forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness has a negative connotation these days. We see forgiving each other as weak — as not standing by one’s values, as giving up one’s pride. This view is incredibly counter-productive and, in my opinion, the cause of many problems in today’s society. Here is the actual definition of forgiveness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;forgive (verb)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to cease to feel resentment against (an offender)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: Merriam Webster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definition is all that forgiveness has to be — not pardoning or excusing someone for their actions, but instead letting go of anger towards them. Grudges may appear to make someone “tough” and “strong,” but all they do is keep someone’s mind tormented by the people they despise. It is very easy to hold a grudge—grudges make one feel powerful without requiring them to do anything. However, true power in one’s life stems from overcoming this negativity and taking control of one’s emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgiving-others&#34; &gt;Forgiving Others
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#forgiving-others&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forgiving others is much easier than it sounds and is one of the quickest and simplest ways to &lt;em&gt;improve your mental state&lt;/em&gt;. This will be more challenging for deep, long-term grudges, but you can displace surface-level anger as easily as saying, “[Person], I forgive you” aloud—even when alone. Forgiveness helps get negative people out of your head who don’t deserve to be there. It also helps you understand others instead of hating them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting go of blame/resentment helps focus on finding solutions, instead of blaming others for problems—this results in &lt;em&gt;better decision making&lt;/em&gt;. Your thought process goes from, “If only this person didn’t do that, everything would be so much better” to “This happened, what can I do about it?” It’s not possible to control the actions of others, but we can control our own responses. This attitude &lt;em&gt;sharpens social skills&lt;/em&gt;, as you learn to respond maturely instead of reacting passionately when upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgiving-yourself&#34; &gt;Forgiving Yourself
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#forgiving-yourself&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does forgiving yourself mean? In line with our definition from above, it means to cease self-resentment. Many toxic behaviors stem from insecurities and regrets people have. If people were content with themselves and their accomplishments, the world would be a kinder place. Self forgiveness can be a much more difficult task than forgiving others (since you can’t exactly put yourself behind you), but can reap the greatest benefits. &lt;em&gt;Self forgiveness helps guide one’s life towards inner peace and self-love and away from a dependency on external stimuli (such as degrading others) for happiness.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to help forgive yourself for shortcomings is to work on improving them. Hate how you look? Exercise! Hate being socially incompetent? Practice talking to people! The amount of effort you put into change doesn’t have to be significant, as long as it’s consistent. You should be able to say, “I don’t like this aspect of myself but that’s ok, because I’m taking steps to improve.” This will &lt;em&gt;increase self-esteem&lt;/em&gt; and thus &lt;em&gt;increase happiness&lt;/em&gt; in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to changing who you are is accepting your flaws. No one is perfect! This skill is difficult to master, but promotes loving who you are instead of trying to change into who you want to be. Self-acceptance doesn’t require you to change everything you despise about yourself, but also can lead to a life of mediocrity where you always settle for “good enough”. I find a bit of each mindset to be ideal—I try to improve the qualities I can control and accept the ones I can’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hold self-resentment for past actions, try talking to a professional counselor/therapist! They are skilled at helping patients work through complex and specific issues. They suggest solutions you might not have thought of and call you out when you need it, making your problems much easier to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap--final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Recap &amp;amp; Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#recap--final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness means letting go of resentment, not justifying an action or person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is easier to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not stronger to stay angry than to forgive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness increases confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness improves communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness clears the mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness allows you to learn from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness in some aspects of life help you forgive in others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness makes the world kinder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I don’t like myself because I am inferior,” can turn into “I love myself because I’m trying to grow.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“If only this didn’t happen,” can turn into “This happened, how do we respond?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this writing isn’t citing scientific studies or telling anecdotes—it is presenting a set of ideas for the reader to consider. These beliefs do not cover the entire subject nor do they universally hold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance</title>
      <link>/blog/balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 11:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing sides is fun. Be it politics or pop culture, nothing validates an opinion better than classifying opposing opinions as wrong. Sometimes, as seen by Holocaust deniers or the anti-vaccine movement, it&amp;rsquo;s possible people can be completely and utterly wrong. However, in the general case, both sides have merits and both sides have pitfalls. When trying to gain a perspective of the bigger picture, it&amp;rsquo;s best to position oneself somewhere in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-versus-that&#34; &gt;This versus that
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#this-versus-that&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in a world with seven billion perspectives. Seven billion lifetimes of thought and contemplation. Of course, one cannot listen to every lifestory nor hear every person&amp;rsquo;s opinion. So we form into groups, with each important group representing something between the loudest minority or general majority of people with a particular set of opinions. This is a system able to properly distinguish emerging schools of thought while categorizing people into said schools, enabling people to efficiently organize, communicate, and compare ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not imply that everyone in a group has well formed opinions. Quite the opposite in fact &amp;ndash; these groups require people to give considerably less thought into their beliefs. Immersing oneself in a group for a few ideas can easily lead to naturally picking up other beliefs of the group, as many people will adapt for acceptance. This lower barrier to entry for taking sides is a core part of the conflict between groups, as society seems to reinforce beliefs by ridiculing opponents who don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand theirs &amp;ndash; consider the plethora of &amp;ldquo;Person X DESTROYS believer of Y&amp;rdquo; videos online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a large enough group however, there tend to be many people who have given careful time and consideration into why they believe what they believe. Thus, one cannot simply sweep a prominent idea under the rug because of a few bad apples. To do so is to throw away ideas which stood the test of time and the people behind them. If proposed a ridiculous sounding idea, merely dismissing it without consideration denies you of a potentially meaningful realization. Instead of &amp;ldquo;No, that&amp;rsquo;s wrong&amp;rdquo;, all parties benefit more from &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; The pursuit of knowledge would have ended a long time ago if we dismissed everything we didn&amp;rsquo;t believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;entertaining-thoughts&#34; &gt;Entertaining Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#entertaining-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An invaluable skill that many successful people have is the ability to play with an idea without accepting it. This is essential for multiple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By entertaining an idea, you can learn key takeaways from views that may appear ridiculous at first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can reinforce your beliefs by attempting (and failing) to convince yourself of an opposing view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, many people are absolutely rubbish at laying out a convincing argument. Requiring the persuasion of other people to change your mind will result in your mind rarely being changed. Sometimes, the best person to convince you of something is in fact, you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34; &gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit an idea based on the people proposing it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t discredit a person based on the group they belong to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing so inhibits learning for both parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone can&amp;rsquo;t convince you of something, try convincing yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a fully fleshed out idea of mine, nor is this idea exclusively mine. There are both counter arguments and room for expansion, however I think this is best left up to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
